<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="telephoneInterviewTopics">
        <item>
            What is a telephone Interview?
        </item>
        <item>
            Before the Telephone Interview
        </item>
        <item>
            Creating the Right Environment
        </item>
        <item>
            During the Telephone Interview
        </item>
        <item>
            What questions to ask?
        </item>
        <item>
            After the Telephone Interview
        </item>

        <item>
            The Do\'s and Don\'t\'s
        </item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="telephoneInterviewTopicTips">
        <!--what is tel interview-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
           Telephone interviews often take place during the early stages of the job interview process.<br />Some recruiters will use them as a method of shortlisting; others as an opportunity to learn<br />more about the candidates who are applying to work for them.<br /><br />A telephone interview is often an effective way for a company to screen many candidates quickly and cost-effectively,<br />without having to invest the same level of time and resources needed for face-to-face interviews.<br /><br />Telephone interviews (and increasingly, Skype interviews) are usually straightforward, since the aim is to eliminate<br />weaker candidates, rather than to test stronger ones. Often, all recruiters are looking for is a calm,<br />confident telephone manner and an intelligent set of responses to common interview questions.<br /><br />In some occupations, phone communication is an important responsibility.<br />In this situation, the recruiter will be evaluating how well you can present yourself, convey messages and get your point<br />across clearly and concisely.<br /><br /><strong>Graduate-level telephone interviews</strong> are usually short - most last fewer than 30 minutes - and typically comprise a mix of<br />competency-based questions and questions about your CV, work experience and education.<br /><br />The questions that you will be asked at this initial stage are likely to include your motivations for applying,<br />your career aspirations and to see if you would be a good fit for the company. They are also an opportunity for you<br />to ask any initial questions about the job or the organisation.<br /><br />Your aim is to convey enthusiasm and commitment in a short conversation.<br />Sometimes the recruiter will inform you before the interview what you will be discussing - use this to your advantage.<br />If, for example, they say that they will be discussing your motivations for applying, draw up a list of your skills and<br />explain how they fit in with the company and the position that you have applied for,<br />including positives about the company such as their track record, successes and opportunities for development.
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--Before the tel interview-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            Even highly capable candidates can be rejected at this early stage if they are inadequately prepared or not used to speaking<br />in a professional manner over the phone. For many candidates, the whole situation can feel unnatural -<br />without eye contact it can be difficult to build rapport and display a strong personality with your interviewer.<br /><br />- <strong>Practice</strong><br />Practice is useful, especially if you haven\'t worked in an office or used a telephone to speak with clients in previous jobs.<br />If you can, try getting friends or family members to call you and ask interview questions. Candidates who don\'t think they\'ll<br />have any trouble with this style of assessment are often the ones that experience the most difficulty.<br /><br />- <strong>Research</strong><br />It\'s important to find out as much as you possibly can about a company, and a job role, before any type of interview;<br />a telephone interview is no exception. You may receive some information from your prospective employer,<br />but make sure you also visit their website, competitor websites, read relevant trade press, and keep up<br />to date with current industry-specific commercial awareness issues. Research the size of a company, its structure,<br />its products and services, its markets, competitors and future plans.
             </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--creating the right environment-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            Many candidates find it hard to adapt to telephone interviews and struggle to get into interview \'mode\'<br />when talking to interviewers over the telephone. This is not good enough; you need to be as<br />professional and presentable as you would in a face-to-face situation from the moment your interviewer calls.<br /><br />- <strong>What to Wear</strong><br />Although it may sound strange, putting on smart, interview-style clothes before your scheduled telephone interview can<br />help you to focus and get into a professional mindset. You don\'t have to wear a tie if that makes you feel uncomfortable.<br /><br />- <strong>Have everything in hand</strong><br />If you\'re being interviewed, then you have probably already sent them your CV;<br />make sure you have it to hand because it\'s fairly likely they will be drawing on it. Similarly,<br />if there is information about the employer or the job that you worry you might forget then make a note of it.<br /><br />- <strong>Location, location</strong><br />Telephone interviews are usually scheduled in advance. As such, there is no excuse for being in a room with bad<br />telephone signal or with lots of background noise. Make sure you are somewhere quiet and where you can speak<br />uninterruptedly without any risk of poor telephone reception. Coffee shops might seem like a good idea, but<br />espresso machines, babies and teenagers are one of the noisiest combinations. Getting these things wrong won\'t<br />set the best first impression with your interviewer and risks damaging your impact over the phone.<br /><br />- <strong>Posture and Behaviour</strong><br />Standing up, rather than sitting down, can be a good way to keep your confidence and enthusiasm levels high.<br />Professional salespeople use this trick to keep them focused and alert when making high-pressure sales calls.<br /><br />The best salespeople often recommend using a headset when making, or taking, important calls.<br />Doing so helps you concentrate on talking and thinking, rather than holding your phone, and allows you<br />to use your hands to complement your responses.<br /><br />-<strong> Get into a positive mind-set</strong><br />Do some breathing exercises before the interview to calm your nerves, and give yourself a pep talk,<br />reminding yourself of all of your achievements to date. I would also recommend visualising positive outcomes,<br />such as being offered the job. This will remind you of your end goal, motivating you to give your best performance<br />during the phone call.<br /><br />- <strong>Get organised</strong><br />Check that you have phone signal, full battery, have the hiring manager and recruiters name and number saved on your phone.<br />Make sure that you are clear on who is calling who, and at what time. Be ready for the call 15 minutes before,<br />ensuring you are in a quiet space and can talk. If you are at work, step outside of the office, and if you are at home,<br />switch off the TV and radio, and let anyone else in the house know that you can\'t be interrupted for the next hour or so.<br />Remember to also turn off your personal phone to avoid the chances of this ringing.
             </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--during the tel interview-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            -<strong> Answer the phone in a professional manner</strong><br />Pick up within two to three rings, and answer in a professional manner, for instance, "Hello Alex speaking".<br />Maintain this professional tone throughout the call.<br /><br />- <strong>Adjust your body language</strong><br />Even though your interviewer can\'t see you, getting your body language right during your telephone interview<br />can make all the difference to how you sound and come across. Sitting up straight or standing when answering questions<br />will improve how well you project your voice, and smiling and gesticulating will inflect a positive intonation as you speak.<br /><br />- <strong>Speak at an even pace</strong><br />It is harder to appreciate just how fast we are speaking over the phone, especially when we are nervous.<br />If you notice this happening, pause and take a deep breath. I would also recommend getting up and walking around,<br />this can help you to regulate your speaking patterns and feel more at ease.<br /><br />- <strong>Remember your manners</strong><br />Just because the interviewer can\'t see you, that doesn\'t mean you can get away with bad manners.<br />Avoid eating and chewing gum, this can be very off putting for the interviewer, and certainly don\'t start doing<br />anything else which could be perceived as rude during a face-to-face interview, such as scrolling through social<br />media on your phone or messaging your friends. It will be obvious to the interviewer that you are distracted.<br /><br />Interrupting people too much is also deemed as bad manners, and unfortunately is more likely to happen during a<br />telephone interview, mainly because you can\'t read the interviewer\'s visual cues in order to judge whether they have<br />finished talking. Avoid interrupting the interviewer by pausing for a second once you think they have finished speaking,<br />before you start responding.<br /><br />- <strong>Conclude as you would a face-to-face interview</strong><br />On the subject of manners, remember to thank the interviewer for their time, and state that you enjoyed learning more<br />about this opportunity. Reiterate your interest in the role, and clarify the next steps if the hiring manager hasn\'t<br />already done so.<br /><br />Again, just because this isn\'t a face-to-face interview, doesn\'t mean you can\'t leave a strong last impression with the<br />interviewer.
             </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--what questions to ask-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            Asking questions during a telephone interview is a good idea,<br />and shows your aptitude to the job in question.<br />This is not the time to ask about holiday entitlement, or company bonuses; you should use this as an opportunity to find<br />out about what the day to day entails, how big your potential team will be, and what opportunities for career progression are.<br /><br /><strong>Example Questions;</strong><br /><br />- How would you describe the responsibilities of this position?<br />- What qualities are you looking for in the person you hire to join this company?<br />- If I was hired, how would I be interacting with you and your department? What would be your expectations and your measures for success?<br />- How would I get feedback on how well my work meets these expectations?<br />- What do you view as the most challenging part of this job?<br />- Why is the last person who held this position leaving?<br />- Who does this position report to?<br />- How would you describe the company culture?
             </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--after the tel interview-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            After the interview, if you are still interested in taking this opportunity further,<br />I would advise that you follow up just as you would a face-to-face interview. Phone your recruiter straight after<br />the interview to give your feedback, and send a thank you note to the interviewer via your recruiter, affirming again,<br />just how interested you are in this opportunity. Remember to keep your phone close by in the coming days.
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--the dos and donts-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <strong>Do\'s:</strong><br /><br />- <strong>Your research.</strong><br />Just like a face-to-face interview, start by finding out as much as you can about the company.<br />Find out about the size and structure of the company, its products and services and the markets<br />it works in (including looking at competitor\'s websites).<br />The best place to start is the employer\'s website,<br />but also keep an eye out for news articles, which may mention plans for growth and expansion.<br /><br />- <strong>Write down any questions you want to ask.</strong><br />A phone interview is a really good opportunity to find out more about the role you\'ve applied for,<br />the company culture and opportunities for growth. And always make sure you have a pen and paper handy<br />for note taking (here\'s our list of interview questions for employers, just in case you\'re struggling for inspiration).<br /><br />- <strong>Have your CV to hand.</strong><br />In all probability, the recruiter will have a copy of it too,<br />so you may not be asked about it in detail. However, they may open the interview by asking questions<br />about your experience. It\'s also a good way to ease into the call while allowing them to find out how communicative you are.<br /><br />- <strong>Relax.</strong><br />Telephone interviewers are more concerned with finding out about your personality than your answers to questions.<br />If you prepare sufficiently for your interview, you will naturally be more relaxed, and more confident that you will<br />be able to answer the questions that you have been asked in sufficient detail.<br /><br />- <strong>Don\'t use slang or colloquialisms</strong><br />Make sure that you are polite throughout the conversation.<br />Keep slang words for your friends or informal conversations. Also try not to talk too quickly,<br />so that the interviewer can understand what you are saying.<br /><br />- <strong>Try to sound confident and capable.</strong><br />It is really important that you focus on what the interviewer is saying, so you can answer the questions properly and correctly.<br />Listen to the question, ask for clarification if you need it and speak slowly, confidently and clearly.<br /><br />- <strong>Smile.</strong><br />OK, so we know it sounds strange &ndash; but it actually works. Although your interviewer can\'t see you<br />(because that would be weird), always try and remain smiling throughout the conversation.<br />It helps ensure you sound upbeat and, according to research, people can actually hear you smile. You have been warned.<br /><br />- <strong>Listen.</strong><br />Undoubtedly the most important element to consider. Take on board all elements of their questions,<br />and make note of anything that seems of particular importance, just in case they refer back to it later.<br />Even if they don\'t, you can use it as a cheat sheet when answering the inevitable \'any other questions\'<br />invitation at the end of the interview.<br /><br /><strong>Don\'t\'s</strong><br /><br />- <strong>Treat it differently from a face-to-face interview.</strong><br />Strange as it sounds, it\'s a good idea to dress like a professional.<br />Obviously the interviewer can\'t see you, but it\'s harder to feel &ndash; and therefore sound &ndash; professional if you\'re<br />still sitting in your dressing gown.<br /><br />- <strong>Get distracted.</strong><br />You need to remain focused on the task at hand, something that can prove difficult,<br />if you still have one eye on the TV. The same goes for your partner/family members.<br />They might be being supportive, but your interview should be a two way conversation.<br />Having their frantic arm flapping and mouthed words of encouragement in the background will only put you off.<br /><br />- <strong>Eat.</strong><br />There is a time and a place for snacking. Five minutes before your phone interview isn\'t it.<br />You might think you\'re being quiet &ndash; but chances are that you aren\'t.<br />A mumbled answer because you have your mouthful is memorable,<br />but for all the wrong reasons. Especially important if you\'re a nervous eater.<br /><br />- <strong>Interrupt.</strong><br />The easiest way to avoid irritating the interviewer is to let them finish their sentence,<br />so always allow for a gap before you begin answering. Not only will it give you time to<br />think of a coherent response, it will also mean you don\'t speak over the person you\'re<br />trying to impress. Just make sure you approach gaps with a degree of caution.<br />There\'s a difference between a courteous pause and an awkward silence&hellip;<br /><br />- <strong>Sound bored.</strong><br />Remember when we said about remaining attentive a few paragraphs ago?<br />Well it\'s kind of a big deal&hellip; Again, it may seem obvious, but when you haven\'t done a telephone interview before,<br />it\'s easy to overlook. Try to sound positive, and avoid yawning or mumbling your responses.<br />Even if you haven\'t understood every single sentence, just go with it.<br />Make the right noises, and you\'re a shoe in for the next stage.
             </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
    </string-array>

</resources>