<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="cvTopics">
        <item>
            CV(Curriculum Vitae) or Resume?
        </item>
        <item>
            Tailor and Format CV
        </item>
        <item>
            Action Verbs/Power Words
        </item>
        <item>
            Key Points to Include
        </item>
        <item>
            The Header
        </item>
        <item>
            Summary
        </item>
        <item>
            Educational History
        </item>
        <item>
            Work Experience
        </item>
        <item>
            Work Experience with no Experience
        </item>
        <item>
            Any Hard/Soft and Transferable skills
        </item>
        <item>
            Some Examples of Transferable Skills
        </item>
        <item>
            Awards and honours
        </item>
        <item>
            Any published work
        </item>
        <item>
            Interests/Hobbies
        </item>
        <item>
            References
        </item>
        <item>
            The Do\'s and Don\'t\'s
        </item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="cvTopicsTips">
        <!--Cv or Resume-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            There are three major differences between CVs and resumes are the length, the purpose and the layout.<br />A resume is a brief summary of your skills and experience over one or two pages, a CV is more detailed<br />and can stretch well beyond two pages. The resume will be tailored to each position whereas the CV<br />will stay put and any changes will be in the cover letter.<br /><br />A CV has a clear chronological order listing the whole career of the individual whereas a resume\'s<br />information can be shuffled around to best suit the applicant. I would say the main difference between a resume and<br />a CV is that a CV is intended to be a full record of your career history and a resume is a brief, targeted list<br />of skills and achievements.<br /><br />A resume is the preferred application document in the US and Canada. Americans and Canadians would only use a<br />CV when applying for a job abroad or if searching for an academic or research oriented position.<br /><br />In the UK, Ireland and New Zealand, a CV is used in all contexts and resumes aren\'t used at all.<br />The CV prevails in mainland Europe and there is even a European Union CV format available for download.<br /><br />In Germany, the CV is more commonly known as a Lebenslauf (true to the latin origins) and is only one of many application<br />document the poor German job seekers must produce to get an interview.<br /><br />In Australia, India and South Africa, the terms resume and CV are used interchangeably.<br />The term resume is used more for jobs in the private sector and CV is more commonplace when applying for public service positions.
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--Tailor and format CV-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            It takes a recruiter less than one minute to scan a programmer resume and to start a short list of eligible candidates<br />for an interview. A resume format with dark colors for the heading with a column of content to the right of the article<br />is more appealing to the eye than a general resume.<br /><br />The art of writing a resume is to format the resume using a chronological, functional, or combination format.<br />I recommend you think about what to write before you begin because it will need a combination of technical skills<br />with qualitative data, interpersonal skills, achievements, volunteer work, or freelance experience to stand out<br />from the pile of resumes recruiters often receive. As a recruiter scans your resume,<br />it has to tell a story of your past, present, and where you plan to be in the future. So, it\'s a good idea to format your CV<br />in a reverse-chronological format.<br /><br />- It front-loads your strengths and shows the peak of your career at the top of the resume.<br />- It makes the whole thing searchable.<br />- It saves recruiter\'s time.<br /><br />-<strong> The Layout</strong><br />Making your CV fit on one side of a page of A4 is a good approach if you have not had work experience before or<br />have perhaps just had one job since leaving school. For most other people fitting their educational background and<br />various work experiences and achievements into such a small space is not likely to be realistic.<br /><br />If possible, keep your CV layout to two sides of A4 and three at the most.<br />This may mean you are tempted to squash a lot of information in by reducing typeface sizes and using small sub-headings.<br />Generally speaking, this is a mistake and you are better off cutting things and shortening sentences to make your content<br />fit the size of CV you are looking for.<br /><br />- <strong>TypeFace</strong><br />Conventional typefaces are the best ones to go for when writing a CV. It is hard to imagine the circumstances in which a<br />simple choice of Times New Roman would be frowned upon. However, to make your CV stand out from the pack,<br />other ones like Mistral, Calibri or Arial are quite acceptable.<br /><br />Avoid informal-looking fonts such as Comic Sans or AR Carter. If you have any doubts about your choice,<br />then change the typeface for something more conventional. Only if you are going for a graphic design job or<br />similar should you even consider the funkier typefaces.<br /><br />- <strong>Font Size</strong><br />Your name at the top of the CV can be in a larger font size than the rest of the CV.<br />Use a similar font size for headings that break up sections of your CV along the way.<br />If you are pushed for room, then simply make sub headings bold rather than employing a larger font size.<br /><br />For the main body of the text try not to go too small. A font size of about 11 is as small as you should go<br />otherwise what you are saying is likely to be hard to read. On the other hand you should not go so large that your<br />CV appears to have been padded out.<br /><br />Also, it\'s important to tailor your CV:<br /><br />- <strong>Tailoring your Skills</strong><br />Skills are the most important thing to change when you tailor your CV.<br />A straightforward way to do this is by looking at the skills desired by the employer in question and listing<br />any of the skills you have, how you acquired them and where you\'ve put them into practice.<br /><br />- <strong>Tailoring your Experience</strong><br />You can\'t change your employment history, but you can select what employment and experience is included on your CV.<br />Although everyone says that you should list your most recent employment on your CV, a better tip would be to list all<br />recent and relevant work experience. What is relevant, of course, relies upon the job you\'re applying for.<br />As mentioned before, relevant experience will be completely different for a bar job compared with an engineering vacancy.<br /><br />- <strong>Tailoring your Hobbies</strong><br />It\'s really not a good idea to stick with "Going to the gym, seeing friends and popular culture"<br />as your hobbies on every CV you send. In fact, it\'s not a good idea to have those boring, "generic" hobbies on any CV.<br /><br />Make sure your hobbies reflect you as a person and your ability to do the role you are applying for,<br />as well as your passion for that industry.<br /><br />For example, if you\'re applying for a creative position, emphasise your love of drawing,<br />visiting art galleries or your passion for a particular artist. Going for a role that requires<br />a lot of writing? Try focusing on a particular genre of literature that you enjoy, or if you\'re<br />going for a role that holds a lot of responsibility, focus on your love for hobbies that include team work (e.g. sports).

            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--Action Verbs/Power words-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            Using action verbs in resume writing is as easy as any other form of writing, so long as you know what to include and<br />what to look for. Here are two tests to determine if you are using passive voice in your resume writing:<br /><br />1 - <strong>Verb Test</strong>: Look for helping verbs, especially forms of the verb "to be."<br /><br />2 - <strong>"By You" Test</strong>: Can you insert the phrase "by you" after the verb? Does the sentence still make grammatical sense?<br />If yes, this signifies passive voice.<br /><br />Scan the resume for these warning signs and replace passive resume writing with more active verbs and sentences.<br />Here are a few examples of <strong>passive resume sentences</strong>:<br /><br />1 - A 20 percent revenue growth was realized in our department over two years.<br /><br />2 - A promotion to supervisor was awarded to me after only one year of service.<br /><br />3 - Responsibility was recognized as one of my strengths.<br /><br />Here are the same examples <strong>rewritten using active voice</strong>:<br /><br />1 - My team realized 20 percent revenue growth over two years.<br /><br />2 - After only one year, I earned a promotion to supervisor.<br /><br />3 - Recognized for responsibility and proactive decisions.<br /><br />The only time when passive voice is appropriate is when you want to draw more attention to results instead of yourself.<br />This is very rare, and you should focus on your achievements rather than your company\'s results.<br /><br />Make your resume shine with achievements<br />Another action-word strategy is to use "achieving" language rather than "doing" language.<br />How do you determine if the sentence is doing or achieving? Ask yourself three simple questions:<br /><br />1 - Can anyone perform this function?<br /><br />2 - Is this the standard, run-of-the-mill description?<br /><br />3 - Did any results come from this action?<br /><br />If your answers are yes, yes, and no, you are listing descriptions that only show what you can do.<br />What you want instead is to show what you have achieved.<br /><br />Here are a few examples of "doing" sentences and how to convert them into "achieving" sentences:<br /><br />- <strong>Doing</strong>: Responsible for inventory control and ordering products.<br /><br />- <strong>Achieving</strong>: Optimize inventory by monitoring for product shortages and ensuring efficient service usage.<br /><br />- <strong>Doing</strong>: Help company sell more products and gain revenue.<br /><br />- <strong>Achieving</strong>: Increase profit margins by creating effective sales plans and implementing strategies to solidify<br />client retention.<br /><br />Using action verbs and active voice makes all the difference in your resume, so it\'s worth the extra effort.<br />Show the employer what you can bring to the table by listing past achievements and notable contributions and you\'ll<br />increase your chance of getting an interview.
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--key points to include-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            Whether a potential employer asks to see your curriculum vitae, CV or resume, they\'re looking for one thing &ndash;<br />a document that proves why you\'re the ideal candidate to invest their time and money in. Essentially it\'s<br />a sales brochure, pinpointing the interesting USPs (unique selling points) that make you stand out from the crowd.<br /><br />There\'s no universally accepted format, but your CV should cover these elements:<br /><br />- Your Details in the Header Section.<br />- A Brief Bio<br />- Work Experience<br />- Educational History<br />- Skills<br />- Interests<br />- References
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--the header-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            Make it easy for employers to get in touch. Include your name, address, main phone number and email address.<br />Don\'t use email addresses that look unprofessional.<br /><br />Also, help a recruiter understand the value an organization will gain by hiring you.<br />One way to accomplish an effective use of links is to show off your work by adding<br />hyperlinks to an online portfolio, work samples, or blog posts to a programmer resume.<br />Here are a few examples of links on a CV:<br /><br />- LinkedIn profile<br />- Personal Website/Blog<br />- GitHub link<br />- StackOverflow link<br />- Upwork Profile (Freelance work)
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--summary-->
        <item>
             <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            A summary of a career is a four to five sentence description that highlights a career which includes soft skills and<br />technical skills with a few references to your ability to work effectively in a team. Here are a few ways to<br />outline an opening summary:<br /><br />- Reference the number of years in an industry<br />- Present skills in training employees<br />- Enhance tech programs completed in your position<br /><br />The ultimate goal is to craft the resume with no fluff;<br />only include quantitative content that shows a human resource recruiter you are fit for the position.<br /><br /><strong>Examples:</strong><br /><br />- Results-oriented C programmer with 8+ years experience developing, testing, and maintaining enterprise software applications.<br />Designed and developed over 30 advanced applications from use cases and functional requirements.<br />Investigated new technologies to make sure that XYZ Corp remained the leader in setting industry standards in past years.<br /><br />- Designed a customer Customer Relationship Management (CRM) software that reduced administrative work by 35% in the first 90 days".<br /><br />- Hard-working listing programmer with a flair for creating elegant solutions in the least amount of time.<br />As a freelance programmer, created SAS datasets of clinical data and developed macro programs to improve efficiency<br />and quality of data management for Takeda Pharmaceuticals. Looking to use my programming skills to help boost<br />Piper Companies\' data management efficiency.
             </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--educational history-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            What qualifications you choose to include on your CV is largely dependent<br />on what stage of your career you\'re in, and where your most impressive accomplishments lie.<br /><br />- <strong>If you\'ve just left school&hellip;</strong><br />If you\'re a recent school leaver, place emphasis on your GCSEs, A levels, or any other accomplishments you\'ve<br />achieved whilst you were in education.<br /><br />As most roles you apply for won\'t be looking for much direct work experience,<br />this is a great way to help sell yourself for a role. At the very least, a pass in Maths and English is essential for<br />many jobs, so be sure to include these.<br /><br />List the subjects you studied and your grades, but feel free to condense them down into less detailed descriptions<br />if you\'re not sure they\'re your strongest selling point. This will also allow more space for other experience<br />e.g. part time/summer jobs that directly relate to the role you\'re applying for.<br /><br />- <strong>If you\'ve just left University&hellip;</strong><br />As a recent graduate you should always focus on your degree, and include college and school level information with less detail.<br /><br />If you have a large number of GCSEs, list the amount and the grades you got rather than each individual subject<br />(e.g. 11 GCSEs A-C). This saves space and makes your CV clearer and easier to read.<br /><br />Work experience should also come secondary to education at this stage. Structure your CV by including your<br />degree information first, and then go on to include any jobs you may have held in the following section.<br /><br />Including individual modules isn\'t absolutely necessary, but could increase your chances if the modules relate<br />closely to the role you\'re applying for. If you don\'t have a lot of work experience, this is a good way to<br />demonstrate your skills and ability to do the job.<br /><br />- <strong>If you\'re still studying&hellip;</strong><br />If you\'re still in education, or you\'re developing your knowledge by taking an additional qualification,<br />information on your current area of study is likely to be the most relevant.<br /><br />Include any predicted grades, if you have them, and dates for when you\'re likely to complete your studies.<br />You may also choose to add in more information about the modules you\'ve covered so far, especially if they\'re<br />directly related to the role.<br /><br />This way, employers can identify any specific knowledge you\'ve<br />already gained in the industry, and won\'t be in the dark about completion dates when it comes to offering you the role.<br /><br />- <strong>If you have a professional qualification&hellip;</strong><br />Perhaps you haven\'t been in education for a while, and have decided to brush up on your knowledge in an industry<br />or learn something. In this case, you would benefit most from detailing your most recent educational qualification,<br />and keeping the others brief.<br /><br />If you aren\'t that far removed from education, and it relates equally to the role, then place an equal amount of<br />emphasis on each qualification.<br /><br />If you took a course for the purpose of developing current skills and gaining a higher-level role in a career you<br />already have experience in, then make sure previous work experience or related education is also adequately included.<br />This enables the employer to see how you\'ve grown and developed, and they will admire your dedication to the field.<br /><br />- <strong>If you\'ve been in employment for a while&hellip;</strong><br />If you\'ve taken a break from your career, it\'s likely that you\'ve developed an extensive portfolio of<br />work experience on your CV.<br /><br />Don\'t add unnecessary clutter by including a great deal of education on top of that &ndash; especially if it happened 10 years ago.<br />Detailing jobs you\'ve had that represent your talents and skills, not to mention, dedication and passion for the industry you\'re in,<br />will be what attracts most prospective employers.<br /><br />Include your education, but detailed descriptions aren\'t necessary in this situation; condense information into short<br />lists, with grades and courses &ndash; but there\'s no need for module choices or individual subjects to be addressed in detail.<br /><br /><strong>Remember</strong>: what you include is heavily dependent on what kind of role you\'re applying for and its requirements.<br />Take the time to read the job specification and skills needed and cater your CV to that.<br /><br />Bear in mind that your most successful achievements (educational or otherwise) are the ones worth showcasing,<br />so draw attention to your most impressive accomplishments and focus on what paints you in the best light from an employer\'s<br />perspective.
             </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--Work experience-->
        <item>
             <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
              The work experience section of your CV is where you show your professional track record.<br />It needs to be accurate, highlight your achievements and include relevant points that prove you\'re the right person for the job.<br /><br />1. <strong>Draw parallels</strong><br />List your previous jobs in chronological order with the most recent employment first.<br />If there are some parallels between your old company and the new one you are applying to, then it\'s worth providing<br />information about their similarities. This can show the hiring manager that you have the skills for the job and it<br />is important if your current company isn\'t well known.<br /><br />As an example, this might include stating that your previous employer worked with many clients in the media sector,<br />if you know this is a key customer base for the company you\'re applying to.<br /><br />2. <strong>Be factual</strong><br />All aspects of your CV, including your dates of employment, must be factually correct.<br />If you have a gap in employment and are worried about how this may come across, you can always enter dates as month-to-month<br />or even year-to-year, rather than specific dates.<br /><br />For jobs that were many years ago, or if you&rsquo;ve had a number of jobs in a relatively short period, you can group these jobs,<br />for example, \'2001-2003 worked in temporary roles within the retail sector\'.<br /><br />3. <strong>Prove you have what they want</strong><br />Research the job details and personal specifications for the type of job you want. Then,<br />under each of the jobs in your experience section, use bullet points to illustrate that you have exactly the skills and expertise they\'re after.<br /><br />Remember to be specific. If they want sales experience, then specify how many customers you dealt with,<br />the types of responsibilities you had and give an example to show off your skills.<br /><br /><strong>For Example</strong>: \'I have experience in a demanding sales role where I was required to meet monthly customer targets.<br />I dealt with X customers on a daily basis making X amount of sales in a period of X months, exceeding my target by X%.<br />This role taught me how to handle a busy and dynamic environment. I learnt to adapt to different customer needs to meet<br />my monthly goals.\'<br /><br />4. <strong>Voluntary work counts</strong><br />Where you have limited work experience, or are looking to change career entirely, other experience outside of paid employment<br />could show your capabilities. This might include unpaid work placements, community activities, such as working with a<br />charity or being a student representative for your course.<br /><br />Employers will respond positively to reading about any extracurricular activities you\'re involved in,<br />especially if they demonstrate energy and community spirit, because these are exactly the kind of behaviours<br />they want in their employees.<br /><br />5. <strong>Highlight your achievements</strong><br />Many job hunters write their CVs like a job description. They faithfully list the duties they performed and their<br />responsibilities. However, they fail to show the positive impact of their teamwork or contribution to the organisation as a whole.<br /><br />Ensure you don\'t make this mistake by using achievement statements instead.<br />For instance:<br /><br />- Since taking over the credit control function, over 95% of long-standing debts have been recovered,<br />some of which had been owing for more than two years<br />- Trained 50 staff in Excel, which increased the capabilities of employees and their time efficiency in producing reports<br />- Developed a new policy that significantly reduced risks to public health by making it mandatory for<br />organisations to train and induct staff properly.<br /><br />The examples show how you can expand upon your skills and show how you have delivered meaningful results to the organisation,<br />its customers and wider society.<br /><br />6. <strong>Use positive language</strong><br />Choose your words carefully to reflect that you are a high performing, \'can-do\' type of employee.<br />Use positive action words, such as &lsquo;excellent&rsquo;, &lsquo;initiated&rsquo; and &lsquo;accelerated&rsquo; to show the calibre and pace at<br />which you have been working.<br /><br />Never include any implicit criticisms about previous jobs. If you refer to difficult challenges,<br />explain how you helped overcome them or omit them completely.<br /><br />7. <strong>Focus on your strengths</strong><br />If you are looking for a job that is different from your previous work experience, then instead of using the heading<br />\'career history\' and listing your jobs chronologically, try using \'key skills and experience\'.<br />This will give you the flexibility to draw attention to the most relevant career experiences you have had.<br /><br />You will still need to include a short employment history with dates, but this can be relegated to the second page.<br />The aim is to convince the recruiter that you are a great candidate on the first page.<br />This approach also works well for people who have noticeable gaps in their employment history.
             </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--work experience with no experience-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            - <strong>Use structure to your advantage</strong><br />If you have no work experience, your degree is likely to be your biggest selling point.<br />But no two degrees are the same, nor are the specialised skills or results.<br /><br />Our template has \'placements &amp; projects\' section ahead of \'Education &amp; qualifications\'.<br />However, if you think your grades and qualifications are more impressive than your projects,<br />feel free to switch the sections around.<br /><br />Remember, the more impressive your achievement, the further up your CV it should sit.<br /><br />- <strong>Focus on transferable skills</strong><br />Despite your limited experience in employment, remember that you have plenty of transferable skills to offer<br />thanks to your degree.<br /><br />That\'s right; your three years of swotting got you more than just a shiny certificate.<br /><br />Transferable skills, otherwise known as soft skills, are utilised in every role and every industry.<br />And the best part is that you\'ve developed a mountain of them through your degree.<br /><br />Gave a group presentation? That\'s teamwork, communication, leadership and presenting skills right there.<br />Submitted your assignments on time? Well you developed time management and organisation skills, too.<br /><br />Focus on your transferable skills in your CV and you\'ll show any employer you\'ve got more to offer than a brand new<br />qualification.<br /><br />- <strong>Saving space</strong><br />If you\'re struggling to keep your CV to two pages, here are a few quick ways to make room.<br /><br />Firstly, try narrowing the margins or removing the footer.<br /><br />Secondly, try reducing the font size. However, make sure you don\'t reduce your font size below 10 or recruiters will<br />have to invest in a magnifying glass.<br /><br />Lastly, try neatening up your grades into one line. For example, you might write your GCSE results like this:<br /><br />10 GCSEs grades A* &ndash; C, including B in English and C in Maths.
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--Any hard/Soft and Transferable Skills-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            Transferable skills are a core set of skills and abilities, which can be applied to a wide range of different jobs and industries.<br /><br />They\'re usually picked up over time, and can be gained from previous positions, charity or voluntary work, your hobbies,<br />or even just at home.<br /><br />Although slightly softer skills than those directly related to a position, transferable skills are incredibly valuable to employers.<br /><br />Not only do they show that you\'d be a good fit for the team, they can also demonstrate what a candidate can bring to a role,<br />and how much they\'ve learnt from previous positions or experiences.<br /><br />So if you\'re currently lacking experience in the field you\'re looking for work in, transferable skills can be a<br />great way to highlight why you\'re right for the role. Examples of when this can be helpful include entry-level positions,<br />and those looking to change careers.<br /><br />Hard skills are specific abilities which help people carry out different jobs.<br />They\'re teachable, meaning that you can develop them through dedicated training.<br />And, for some careers, certain hard skills will be considered prerequisites.<br /><br /><strong>Hard Skills Examples</strong>:<br />- A degree (or other academic qualification)<br />- An industry specific certification<br />- Coding ability<br />- Foreign language skills<br />- Typing speed<br />- SEO marketing<br />- Bookkeeping<br />- Computer skills<br />- Proofreading<br /><br />The great thing about hard skills is that they\'re easy to back up.<br /><br />In many cases, these are exactly the attributes recruiters scan your CV for and, depending on the role you\'re applying for,<br />they can be considered absolute necessities.<br /><br />To demonstrate them effectively, always place an emphasis on the ones that have been picked out in the job description,<br />and structure your CV around your strongest skills.<br /><br />Soft skills are self-developed attributes, that aren\'t specific to a particular role.<br /><br />They\'re usually picked up through your life and work experiences, meaning no training is needed to build them.<br />And because they can be applied to a number of roles, soft skills are in demand in a wide range of different industries.<br /><br /><strong>Soft Skills Examples:</strong><br />- Interpersonal skills<br />- Leadership<br />- Project management<br />- Problem solving<br />- A good work ethic<br />- Team working<br />- Adaptability<br />- Perseverance<br />- Communication skills<br /><br />Unlike hard skills, soft skills are difficult to prove &ndash; especially when it comes to your CV.<br /><br />However, the most effective applications will always use practical examples to show times soft skills have<br />actually been put into use.<br /><br />In other words, saying you have good leadership skills is not enough to prove them to an employer.<br />But saying you have good leadership skills, and demonstrated them when you completed a particular task, will be much more effective.<br /><br />The job description will provide you with a good list of the skills your prospective is after.<br />So always tailor your application to include some of the headline characteristics.
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--Examples of transferable skills-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            Although this is by no means a comprehensive list, here are some great examples of transferable skills you can use in your CV:

            \n\n&#8226; Leadership
            \nThis skill is extremely versatile, and whilst it\'s typically linked to management positions, being a good leader is essential
            in almost every job – even if only in some situations.

            \nTo reference it in your CV, refer to times where you\'ve demonstrated great leadership – whether it\'s through motivating
            others in order to achieve a shared goal, leading a project, heading up training and development for a team, or
            even through your hobbies and interests (e.g. coaching a sports team).

            \n\n&#8226; Time management
            \nTime management is a vital skill for any role, that not only proves you can work to deadlines – but also that you\'re
            able to complete tasks in the most time-effective way, create to-do-lists, delegate, ask for help,
            and break up projects accordingly.

            \nWhether it\'s that you’ve had experience stacking shelves within a set time in a retail store,
            you\'ve completed projects within a deadline, or you’ve carried out construction work that met the time-sensitive needs
            of a client, you\'ll have at least one example of time management to reference in your CV.

            \n\n&#8226; Prioritisation
            \nPrioritising tasks effectively is essential if you want to get anything done, on time,
            and to a high standard. That\'s why it\'s a key skill that the vast majority of employers value.

            \nProve you\'re able to assess your workload, adjust your schedule, and organise tasks in order of importance by
            giving tangible examples in your CV. For example, it could be that your ability to be ruthless and say no to
            certain tasks enabled you to complete others which had a higher level of importance, or you implemented time
            saving techniques to get small tasks done faster (e.g. spreadsheets, templates).

            \n\n&#8226; Delegation
            \nWhilst delegation is primarily important for managers, supervisors, or anyone in a senior position, that doesn\'t
            mean those without a background in management aren\'t able to demonstrate this skill.

            \nFor example, if you\'ve ever mentored or tutored someone (whether it was at work or school), or trained another colleague
            in a particular system, procedure, or task, you’ll be able to prove you could be a good delegator.
            It\'s all about how you frame your skills, the examples you give, and how you link back to the criteria specified in the
            job description.

            \n\n&#8226; Listening
            \nLet\'s face it, everyone is likely to have good listening skills, no matter where your experience lies.
            This means demonstrating them in your CV should be easy.

            \nThink about times where your ability to listen well resulted in a positive outcome – whether it\'s that you’re great at
            following instructions (which meant your work was done specifically to a client\'s requirements),
            you\'re able to absorb knowledge quickly when taught (whether it was in a meeting, at university,
            or anywhere else), or you delivered excellent customer service by listening carefully to a customer\'s needs.

            \n\n&#8226; Communication
            \nAlthough it\'s particularly important in customer facing industries, good communication is an extremely versatile
            skill that\'s an important part of every role – which contributes to the smooth running of any workplace.

            \nLuckily, that means everyone has it. Examples of communication skills could range from instances where you communicated
            with a customer or client to fulfil their needs or resolve a problem, to times where you worked together with your
            colleagues to achieve a joint goal.

            \n\n&#8226; Research &amp; analysis
            \nMany roles require some level of research and analysis ability – making it an important skill to make known to employers.

            \nThe examples you include may differ depending on the role and what\'s required (particularly if the vacancy calls for harder
            skills, e.g. knowledge of Google Analytics), but a basic level of research and analysis skills can be shown
            in anything from university essays, to any form of gathering, organising, and evaluating information – whether it\'s
            sales figures, website visits, or technical reports.
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--Awards and Honours-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            In a competitive academic and job market, many students or recent grads find themselves lost in the shuffle,
            especially when other applicants have similar academic or work histories. Academic and work accomplishments are
            what set you apart from the hundreds, perhaps thousands, of other candidates vying for the same seat in college
            or that job you really want. Admissions directors and hiring managers know that past achievement usually predicts
            future performance. They also know that achievers are self-starters, motivated, and an asset to their school or company.

            \n\nRemember, admissions directors and hiring managers have dozens of resumes to review on a daily basis.
            In that sea of paper, accomplishments are what capture and retain their interest, so to make certain that
            you get noticed, highlight your academic or work-related honors, awards, and accomplishments.

            \n\nWhen describing honors, awards, or accomplishments on your resume, it is important to maximize the use of language and wording in order to get your point across in the strongest way. Keep the following tips in mind:

            \n\n1. Avoid writing vague self-serving statements on your student resume by using quantifying data.
            \nWeak: High School Senior with good grades

            \n\nStrong: High School Senior consistently named to the Honor Roll, 2000-2004 Member of the National Honor Society

            \n\n2. Avoid accomplishments that have nothing to do with your future career goal, your current job search, or
            those that do not enhance your candidacy.
            \nDon’t use: Beauty contest "Miss Congeniality" winner

            \n\nUse: Won Award at High School Science Fair, 2002

            \n\n3. Be specific with details to capture and retain interest.
            \nWeak: Won Award for Best Art.

            \n\nStrong: Earned Excellence Award for Art Work (pen &amp; ink drawings), 2008-2010

            \n\nWeak: Helped customers in showroom.

            \n\nStrong: Increased sales by $5,000 during summer by helping clients in showroom. This resulted in sales to 8 out of 10
            customers.

            \n\nAccomplishments, no matter how stellar, will do little to enhance your chances of getting into school or getting a job,
            unless they are properly showcased in your student resume or entry-level resume. If you bury them within your daily duties
            or general academic information, they may not be seen. Remember, admissions directors and hiring managers have many resumes
            to review. If it’s hard for them to find important information on your resume, they may pass on your candidacy.

            \n\nYou should emphasize your academic, work, or volunteer recognitions by creating a specific honors, awards,
            and accomplishments section of your resume. Make sure to provide the following details when including your accomplishments:

            \n\n - Date of recognition or award
            \n - Purpose of award and accomplishment it recognizes (i.e., Academic, athletic, job related)
            \n - Significance of award (i.e., What did you have to accomplish? Only one who received the award? )
            \n - Scope of the award (i.e.: National, regional, or local)
            \n - As you can see, there are a variety of ways to market and display your academic and career accomplishments.
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--Any published work-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            If you have only a few publications to list and your publication history isn’t a requirement for the job,
            the best approach is to summarize your work in the accomplishments section of your resume.
            Add a bullet point that says something like, "Published in ABC magazine and XYZ Journal."
            If the interviewer is interested in learning more, he will ask. Bring copies of your published work to the interview to
            share when asked.
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--Interests/Hobbies-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            While your CV tells the story of your qualifications and your career, the hobbies and interest section reveals a
            little more of your personality.

            \n\nBenefits of including hobbies on your CV include:

            \n\n - Demonstrating your relevant skills for the role
            \n - Helps your CV stand out from the crowd
            \n - Makes your CV more individual
            \n - Allows you to show voluntary and community-focused projects
            \n - Gives you something to talk about during your interview

            \n\nSome recruiters are absolute advocates, believing them to be an integral part of well-rounded application. Conversely,
            some may only consider them important if it\'s a close decision, or if company fit/culture becomes a factor.

            \n\nAs a general rule, most recruiters will only be interested in your hobbies if they\'re relevant to the role and,
            crucially – if you\'ve ticked all the other boxes.

            \n\nSo not everyone\'s a fan of Morris Dancing. But surely it\'s better to include something to help sell yourself
            than leave more blank space, right? Wrong.

            \n\nUnfortunately, not everyone\'s a fan of traditional English folk dancing. And unless you\'ve applied for a job
            where these skills will be particularly useful, they\'ll probably not help you get the job.

            \n\nWherever possible, your hobbies and interests should reinforce your application and the idea that you\'ll be the right
            fit for the role – even if it\'s just through transferable skills.

            \n\nIf you do decide to include some hobbies, style can be just as importance as substance.

            \n\nBullet points are fine, but should not be used as a way to list all of your activities individually with zero context.
            The most effective CVs have their hobbies backing up everything the recruiter has read so far.

            \n\nFor example, a \'weekly five-a-side game with friends\' becomes a lot more attractive when written as
            \'successfully organised a range of regional five-a-side football tournaments, including managing all bookings,
            venues and participants and helping coach my own team\'.

            \n\nAnother Example:
            \n\nAvid blogger and social media user, and an owner of my own blog.
            Not only do I use it to write and edit articles about all topics related to sports (specifically football),
            I also use it as a platform to sell advertising space on a CPC basis. Whilst studying, I also successfully organised a
            range of regional five-a-side football tournaments, including managing all bookings, venues and participants and helping
            coach my own team, and contributed to the sports section in the student newspaper and social sites.

            \n\nIf you can\'t think of any particular passions or interests you pursue, don\'t be tempted to just stick to clichés.

            \n\nSocialising with friends, eating out and going to the cinema may be accurate, but are all unlikely to add value to your
            application. And it\'s far better to lose the section completely than to offer up a token gesture.

            \n\nIf you really want something to set yourself apart, you could also take up volunteering.
            Not only is it a great hobby to have, it can also help get your foot in the door in your chosen industry.

            \n\nWho should include them:
            \n - School leavers
            \n - Graduates
            \n - Those lacking experience
            \n - Those applying for roles which are directly related to their hobbies

            \n\nWho should delete them:
            \n - Those who want to cut down their CV
            \n - Those who don\'t know what to say
            \n - Those who have no real hobbies
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--References-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            Almost 60&#37; of employers claim that they have had to withdraw an offer of employment after receiving poor references about
            successful applicants. So, just because you have managed to wow your future employer at interview stage and convinced them
            that you are the best person for the job, it does not mean that you can get away with poorly prepared references.

            \n\nReferences act as a third party endorsement – they are used by hiring managers as reassurance that you are who you
            say you are and will do for them what you claim you have done for your previous employers.

            \n\nTherefore, given the high number of rejections, it is important to prepare your references properly.

            \n\nDon\'t include the details
            \nDon\'t give the names and contact details of your referees on your CV. You should simply state that
            \'References are available on request\'. Employers will ask you for details if and when they are ready
            to offer you a position. After all, you wouldn\'t want your current employer being asked if they would
            re-hire you when you haven\'t even told them you\'re leaving!

            \n\nProviding the right kind of information
            \nNowadays, hiring managers can only request details from former employers that cover:

            \n\n&#8226; Length of employment
            \n&#8226; Previous job title
            \n&#8226; Brief details of responsibility
            \n&#8226; Overall performance
            \n&#8226; Time-keeping and attendance
            \n&#8226; Reason for leaving
            \n&#8226; Employers can also ask your previous company if they would re-hire you should you apply for a position there
            in the future.

            \n\nChoose your referees carefully
            \n85% of employers will check at least one of your references when offering you a position – typically your most recent
            employer - so it is important that you choose the right and responsive people to can testify for your working practices.

            \n\nPersonal references are not advisable because they are more likely to be complimentary and positive,
            so it is best to avoid them – having Grandma Doris saying what \'a lovely lad\' you are isn\'t going to hold much weight.

            \n\nThat said, it is not written in stone that you have to use a former employer as a reference.
            Business acquaintances, customers and organisation leaders can all make good references, too.
            If you don\'t have much in terms of work experience, you\'re advised to use one of your tutors.
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--The do's and don't's-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
           Do\'s

            \n\n&#8226; Tailor your CV to every job.
            \n&#8226; Use spell check and proofread before you send.
            \n&#8226; Keep it concise with no more than two sides.
            \n&#8226; Choose a professional font.
            \n&#8226; Present things in a logical order.
            \n&#8226; Create a professional email address.
            \n&#8226; Include contact details.
            \n&#8226; Maintain consistent formatting.
            \n&#8226; Begin sentences with verbs, rather than writing in the first person.
            \n&#8226; Bullet point your achievements and responsibilities, providing more information for your more recent roles.

            \n\nDon\'t\'s

            \n\n&#8226; Include irrelevant work experience.
            \n&#8226; Try to include too much.
            \n&#8226; include unnecessary references.
            \n&#8226; Make the same application for every role.
            \n&#8226; However tempting, don\'t make your CV too long – your CV needs to reflect all of your selling points, nothing else.
            \n&#8226; Include a photograph of yourself on your CV unless necessary – the vast majority of professional jobs go to the person with the best looking CV, not the photograph.
            \n&#8226; Use clichés. Everyone likes to say they’re a team player with great communication skills who can work under pressure. Instead, use your experience to demonstrate how you can do those things.
            \n&#8226; Lie or embellish the truth on your CV – things are easily checked and a small untruth could blow your chance of success.
            \n&#8226; List every process or package you’ve ever worked with, trained on, heard of or read on the job specification.
            \n&#8226; Use tables and graphics such as ClipArt – they can look untidy and unsightly.
            \n&#8226; Be tempted to shrink the font or reduce the margins to get more information in.
            \n&#8226; Include pages of obscure testimonials, references, newspaper cuttings and brochures.
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
    </string-array>

</resources>