<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Interview Revision</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="nav_header_title">Interview Revision</string>
    <string name="nav_header_desc">Navigation header</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="what_is_behavioural_questions">Behavioural questions are asked to get to know your personality, to understand your resume more deeply,
        and just to ease you into an interview. They are important questions and can be prepared for. </string>

    <!--Interview Prep Grid Texts-->
    <string name="topText">Go through each of the projects or components of your resume and ensure that you can talk about them in
        detail. Filling out a grid like this may help:</string>
    <string name="belowTable">Along the top, as columns, you should list all the major aspects of your resume, including each project, job,
        or activity. Along the side, as rows, you should list the common behavioural questions.
        Study this grid before your interview. Reducing each story to just a couple of keywords may make the grid
        easier to study and recall. You can also more easily have this grid in front of you during an interview without
        it being a distraction.
    </string>

    <!--Behavioural Questions-->
    <string-array name="behaviouralQuestions">
        <item>So, tell me about yourself.</item>
        <item>How would a friend or colleague describe you?</item>
        <item>What are your strengths?</item>
        <item>What are your weaknesses?</item>
        <item>How do you handle a challenge?</item>
        <item>Tell me about a challenging client-facing situation and how you handled it.</item>
        <item>Describe a time when you anticipated potential problems and developed preventative measures.</item>
        <item>Tell me about a time when you had to manage multiple responsibilities. How did you handle that?</item>
        <item>Tell me about the toughest decision you have had to make in the past x months.</item>
        <item>Have you ever made a mistake? How did you handle it?</item>
        <item>Tell me about how you worked effectively under pressure.</item>
        <item>Describe a time when you led by example.</item>
        <item>Give an example of how you worked on a team.</item>
        <item>What do you do if you disagree with someone at work?</item>
        <item>Tell me about a time you had to work closely with someone whose personality or work style clashed with yours.</item>
        <item>Sometimes we have an all-hands-on-deck situation that may require everyone to work extra hours. How would you handle that?</item>
        <item>What is your biggest professional mistake? How did you handle it?</item>
        <item>Give me an example of a time when you failed to hit a deadline.</item>
        <item>Tell me about a time you learned a new skill. How did you approach it and how to did you apply your new learning?</item>
        <item>What are you most proud of? Why?</item>
        <item>Give an example of how you set goals.</item>
        <item>Give an example of a goal you reached and how you achieved it.</item>
        <item>Tell me about a goal you failed to achieve.</item>
    </string-array>

    <!--Behavioural Answers -->
    <string-array name="behaviouralAnswers">
        <!--So, tell me about yourself.-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center"><strong>A typical structure</strong> that works well for many people is essentially chronological,
            with the opening sentence<br />describing their current job and the conclusion discussing their relevant and interesting
             hobbies outside<br />of work (if any).
             <br /><br />1. <strong>Current Role [Headline Only]</strong>:
             I\'m a software engineer at Microworks, where I\'ve been leading the<br />Android team for the last five years:
             <br />2.<strong>College</strong>: My background is in computer science. I did my undergrad at Berkeley and spent a
             few<br />summers working at startups, including one where I attempted to launch my own business.
             <br />3. <strong>Post College &amp; Onwards</strong>: After college, I wanted to get some exposure to larger corporations so
             I joined<br />Amazon as a developer. It was a great experience. I learned a ton about large system design and
             I got to<br />really drive the launch of a key part of AWS. That actually showed me that I really wanted to be in a more
             <br />entrepreneurial environment.<br />4. <strong>Current Role [Details]</strong>: One of my managers from Amazon
              recruited me out to join her startup,<br />which was what brought me to Microworks. Here, I did the initial system architecture,
               which has scaled<br />pretty well with our rapid growth. I then took an opportunity to lead the Android team.
                I do manage a<br />team of three, but my role is primarily with technical leadership: architecture, coding, etc.
                <br />5. <strong>Outside of Work</strong>: Outside of work, I\'ve been participating in some hackathons-mostly doing
                iOS<br />development there as a way to learn it more deeply. I\'m also active as a moderator on online
                forums<br />around Android development.
                <br />6. <strong>Wrap Up</strong>: I\'m looking now for something new,
                 and your company caught my eye. I\'ve always loved the<br />connection with the user, and I really want to get back to
                 a smaller environment too.</pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--How would a friend or colleague describe you?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            1. Highlight one personality trait at a time, sharing an example of a time when
            you demonstrated this quality.<br />    Storytelling is an opportunity to display confidence, charisma, and
            strong interpersonal skills.
            <br />    <br />2. Focus on the personality traits that are applicable to the job for which you are applying.
            Of course, be positive,<br />
             but make sure you are honest and humble also, as these virtues are highly valued in the workforce.
             <br />    Moreover, embellishing your assets or flat-out lying could land you in a company culture that is<br />
               incompatible with your true nature.<br />    <br /><strong>Examples;</strong><br />
                   - My colleagues have told me that I am extremely organized and excellent at time management.<br />
                      During one project, my team members praised me for developing and sticking to a timeline for all the phases of the
                       project.<br />
                        (Give a brief summary of what the project was.) We ended up successfully completing it ahead of time,
                         and it was a hit!<br /><br />     - My colleagues would say that I am very optimistic,
                         as I see setbacks as opportunities to learn and grow.<br />
                          There is always a creative solution to a problem, and I love searching for it.<br />
                            One instance that comes to mind was when colleagues from my last job were upset about budget
                            cuts to our department,<br />
                             and I devised a few clever ways to maintain some of our resources on a shoestring budget.
                              They ended up being implemented.<br /><br />
                              - I\'ve been told that I am both a strong leader and a team player.<br />
                                 In fact, one colleague offered to write me a personal letter of reference at one point because of my
                                  strong team leadership.<br />    He was impressed by my ability to effectively lead a group of
                                   colleagues while also listening to and considering everyone\'s<br />
                                     input as we determined the best plan of action for this new company initiative.
                                      ​<br />    <strong>(Give a brief summary of the initiative and the outcome.)</strong>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What are your strengths?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            1. <strong>Be accurate</strong>. Choose strengths that you actually possess. Don\'t pick a strength just because it\'s in the job description or<br />worked for your buddy. You want to be yourself in an interview, just the best and most professional version of yourself.<br />You will be much more convincing and likable if you talk about authentic strengths.<br /><br />2. <strong>Be relevant</strong>. You should take the time to analyze the job description and identify the most important strengths for each opportunity.<br />You likely have many strengths, but which will be most relevant for this interviewer?<br /><br />3. <strong>Be specific</strong>. Choose specific strengths. Instead of "people skills" (too broad and boring), go with "relationship building" or<br />"persuasive communication." Don\'t be generic. Could 90% of your friends claim your strength? Pick another one.<br /><br />4. <strong>Don\'t be too humble</strong>. See common mistakes above. Avoid "weak praise" and lame strengths. Pick something impressive.<br />Don\'t go with "pleasant to work with" as your main selling point. Just about everybody can and should be pleasant to work with.<br />To get the job, you have to show you would bring more to the position.<br /><br />5. <strong>Be prepared to demonstrate</strong>. As discussed, have a concise example ready to back each strength up.<br />Be careful about rambling on too long here. Your answer should still be 1-2 minutes long.<br />If you want to share three strengths and back each up with an example, you will want to practice in advance<br />so that you can do it in a concise way.<br /><br /><strong>Examples:</strong><br /> - I think one of my greatest strengths is as a problem solver. I have the ability to see a situation from different perspectives<br />and I can get my work done even in the face of difficult obstacles. I also feel that my communication skills are top notch.<br />I feel just as comfortable presenting to senior executives as I do mediating a conflict between junior team members.<br />I worked as a programmer in the past so I have that perspective of a developer and I think that they respect me for that.<br /> <br /> - One of my strengths is my strong work ethic. When I commit to a deadline, I do whatever it takes to deliver.<br />For example, last week we had a report due and got some numbers back late from our team in Singapore.<br />I pulled an all-nighter to finish the spreadsheet because I knew that the client HAD to receive the report on time.
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What are your weaknesses?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <ul>
<li><strong>Be authentic</strong>.<br />Don\'t select a weakness just because it sounds good. You will make a better impression with sincerity.<br />That doesn\'t mean you have to share a weakness that makes you look bad. If you\'re like most of us, you have several weaknesses and<br />at least one of them will be interview-friendly as defined by the additional guidelines below.</li>
<li><strong>Pick a weakness that is acceptable for the job at hand.</strong><br />Be aware of the job requirements and don\'t cite a weakness related to any of the required skills or desired qualities.<br />If you\'re an accountant, don\'t talk about hating math or lack of attention to detail. If you\'re in sales,<br />don\'t confess to being too reserved or lacking persistence.</li>
<li><strong>Select a weakness that is relatively minor and fixable.</strong><br />By fixable, I mean it\'s something you can improve through work and motivation.</li>
</ul>
<pre><strong>Examples:</strong><br /> - I think one area I could work on is my delegation skills. I am always so concerned about everything being done right and<br />on time that I can get stuck in that mentality of "If you want it done right, do it yourself." Unfortunately,<br />that\'s not always possible and I\'ve realized that I can slow things down if I am too controlling.<br />I learned this recently when given the opportunity to manage the department\'s summer interns.<br />I had never managed direct reports before, so this was a hugely educational experience in many different ways.<br />It definitely taught me how to delegate and my manager noticed the difference in my management style at the end of the summer.<br />I know that I can benefit from additional development in this area, so I signed up for a management skills training course and<br />am always looking for opportunities to manage projects for our group.<br /><br /> - Honestly, I would say that public speaking is an area that I could work on.<br />I tend to get nervous when asked to present to a large group of people. In small team meetings, I\'m the first one to stand up and<br />present. But put me in front of a big group and I can get flustered.<br />I actually spoke to my manager about this and we set it as one of my development goals for this year.<br />I took an internal presentation skills class and attended some meetings of Toastmasters,<br />a networking group for people who want to practice public speaking. With some practice, I started to feel more comfortable.<br />Last month, I even volunteered to represent our team at a division-wide town hall.<br />I only had to present for 10 minutes, but I did it and got great feedback! It was actually kind of fun,<br />so I plan on continuing to seek out opportunities to improve in this area.<br /><br /> - Sometimes I can be a bit too honest when I provide feedback to coworkers. My personality is naturally very straightforward<br />and to the point, and most of my colleagues really value that, but I have learned that there are times on the job<br />when more diplomacy is required.<br />I took a training class on conflict management and it really opened my eyes to the need to communicate differently with<br />different people. So now I am much better at providing constructive feedback, even if it doesn\'t always come naturally.
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--How do you handle a challenge?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
           1. Recall a challenge that was significant, but one that you consider a success. Most importantly, you want to be able to discuss a<br />real professional challenge, not an arbitrary or annoying occurrence. You also want to be able to define how you met the challenge<br />successfully. If possible, mention a challenge most relevant to the role you\'re applying to. In your answer, <br />you\'ll want to set up the challenge clearly and succinctly.<br /><br />2. Don\'t just say what you did - explain how you did it. The employer is interested in learning your approach to a challenge,<br />including the actions you took and your thought process. Don\'t skip ahead to the end result. Use specifics to describe what you<br />did to contribute to the solution.<br /><br />3. Emphasize the outcome and what you learned from it. Employers want to hire individuals who can turn challenges into<br />opportunities. When brainstorming an answer, think about ways to emphasize how you made the most of a difficult time. Of course,<br />in the real world, it\'s not possible to wave a magic wand and transform every difficulty into a grand success.<br />It is possible to learn from your hardships, and then apply what you learned to future challenges.<br />Make sure you express your takeaways and how you\'ve grown from your challenges.<br /><br /><strong>Examples:</strong><br /><br /> - One time, my supervisor needed to leave town unexpectedly, and we were in the middle of a touchy negotiation with a new sponsor.<br />I was tasked with putting together a PowerPoint presentation just from the notes he had left, and some briefing from his manager.<br />My presentation turned out successfully - we got the sponsorship, and the management team recommended me for an award.
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--Tell me about a challenging client-facing situation and how you handled it.-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
           The employer wants to see that you can keep a calm head when difficult situations arise, so share a narrative that shows your<br />ability to resolve conflicts.<br /><br /><strong>Example:</strong><br /> - We had a customer who complained frequently and was becoming hostile toward customer service reps.<br />I did some investigating and discovered that our CS agents were repeating the same templated scripts to him and<br />he felt as though his complaints weren\'t being heard. I helped devise an escalation system so that this endless<br />CS loop wouldn\'t happen again. Then I contacted the customer personally to apologize and thank him for helping us<br />find and fix a glitch in our process.

            </pre></html>
             ]]>
        </item>
        <!--Describe a time when you anticipated potential problems and developed preventative measures.-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre>You will probably want to provide an answer that highlights your ability to solve problems in the role you are interviewing for.<br />you will want to avoid giving a vague or general answer. If you are interviewing for the computer engineer role -<br />you would want to discuss the software involved- the other engineers on the team- and the technological process you used to<br />solve the software issue. Just be as detailed as possible- and describe the situation using multiple perspectives.<br /><br />As always, use the STAR format as a framework for your story. The STAR format will help you focus your thoughts and turn<br />your example into an interesting (non-rambling) and convincing (impressive) story.<br />    <br /><strong>- S/T (Situation/Task)</strong>

Give a brief overview of the project or situation. Provide only enough background to give context and help your interviewer understand the difficulty and importance.</pre>
<ul>
<li>In my role as Business Development Manager at XYZ Inc., I was responsible for a team of five tasked with organizing all of our client events.</li>
<li>As you may know, XYZ Inc. is a top provider of enterprise security software.</li>
<li>Our client events are key to driving revenue. We host conferences and other events that feature expert speakers on key issues in the industry.</li>
</ul>
<p>- <strong>A(Approach)</strong><br />Once you\'ve set up the problem, it\'s time to walk through the key actions that you took to address it. What exactly did you do and why?</p>
<ul>
<li>When I sat down to start planning the 2013 event schedule, I knew that it would be critical to get attendance back to at least 2011 levels.</li>
<li>I sat down with my team members and I also interviewed our top sales representatives. I had some ideas about why attendance had dropped,<br />but I wanted to look at it from all angles. Our sales reps felt like we could do a better job marketing the events through social media.</li>
<li>We also sent out a questionnaire to past attendees and partners and asked for their input on how we could improve our<br />events. In the feedback, we saw some key themes emerging &mdash; our clients had great ideas for new topics and speakers and we also<br />saw a clear desire for more structured networking as part of the events.</li>
</ul>
<pre> - <strong>R(Results)</strong><br />Remember that a good STAR interview story always features a happy ending. The last part of your answer should describe the<br />positive result(s) of the actions that you took. Hard numbers are always especially impressive<br />(increased revenue by 41%, came in 20% under budget or 2 weeks ahead of schedule), but anecdotal results can also be powerful<br />(My client said I was a hero, my VP gave me a raise based on my stellar performance).</pre>
<ul>
<li>We saw the impact of our changes right away. We saw a lot of buzz on LinkedIn and Twitter and had a record number<br />    of advance registrations for our first big event of 2013.</li>
<li>For that event, we saw increased attendance of more than 25% over the previous year.<br />    We also saw a huge improvement in our event evaluation scores.</li>
<li>Particular, attendees really enjoyed the new networking component and<br />    over 75% said they would be very likely to recommend the event to a colleague.</li>
</ul>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--Tell me about a time when you had to manage multiple responsibilities. How did you handle that?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
           <pre>If you\'re a great multitasker, you may be tempted to brag. Resist the urge. Instead of trying to make yourself sound like a superhero, try showing your capacity to learn.<br /><strong><br />Example:</strong><br /><br />My partner left for a new job right in the middle of a major project and her responsibilities fell to me.<br />It was a huge challenge! I spent a day prioritizing the project steps and created a timeline for keeping everything on track.<br />I ended up putting in some extra hours, but the project was completed by deadline.</pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
            </item>
        <!--Tell me about the toughest decision you have had to make in the past x months.-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            1. <strong>Pick the Right Challenge</strong><br />Whatever example you use, make sure it highlights a strength you would bring to the role.<br />For example, your flexibility and ability to navigate change, negotiating skills, or perseverance.<br />Your first move is to lay out exactly what the challenge was, and why it was important for the department.<br /><br /><strong>Example:</strong><br /> - In my previous position, I was in charge of selecting vendors to print our promotional materials.<br />We have a long-time vendor we\'ve been working with for over a decade. However, for one of our biggest print jobs of the year,<br />another vendor came in with a lower bid.<br /><br />2. <strong>Discuss how you weighed the options</strong><br />The interviewer is interested in learning how you think. Put yourself in their shoes. Any job comes with problems, and<br />they want to know you\'ll be purposeful and careful in weighing the options.<br />The second part of the answer should give a glimpse into the thought process you went through.<br /><br /><strong>Example:</strong><br /> - I didn\'t want to take the work away from a vendor with whom we did so much business with,<br />but I couldn\'t justify picking them out of loyalty if someone else was doing the same job for less money.<br />So, I told the old vendor frankly about the other bid to hear what they had to say, and I also solicited references<br />from the new vendor to see if their work matched that of what we had been getting.<br /><br />3. <strong>Tell the interviewer what choice you made</strong><br />Make like Houdini and dazzle your audience with the reveal. Tell the interviewer what choice you came to.<br /><br /><strong>Example:</strong><br /> - Our long-time vendor was able to bring down their bid.<br />They actually did the job for less than the new vendor would have, so we ended up saving some money.
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--Have you ever made a mistake? How did you handle it?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            The best way to answer this question is to talk about a specific example of a time you made a mistake.<br />Briefly explain what the mistake was, but don&rsquo;t dwell on it. Quickly switch over to what you learned, or how you improved,<br />after making that mistake. You might also explain the steps you took to make sure that mistake never happened again.<br /><br />When talking about what you learned, try to emphasize skills or qualities you gained that are important for the job you&rsquo;re interviewing<br />for now. You might also explain that something you struggled with a long time ago has actually become one of your strengths.<br /><br />You want your example of a mistake to be honest. However, it\'s a good idea not to mention a mistake that would be critical for success<br />in the new position. For instance, give an example from your last position that isn\'t specifically related to the job requirements<br />for the new position.<br /><br /><strong>Examples:</strong><br /> <br /> - One thing I have learned from past mistakes is when to ask for help. I have learned that it is far better to ask for<br />clarification and solve an issue right away than to be unsure. I know that your company emphasizes teamwork and the need to be in constant<br />communication with one another, and I think my ability to ask (and answer) questions of my peers would help me fit in very well with your<br />company culture.<br /><br /> - I\'m the kind of person who tries to learn and grow from every mistake. Years ago, a team I was working on failed to land a sale,<br />and we were told it had to do in part with our ineffective visuals. Over the next six months, I spent much of my free time learning<br />how to use various software programs to create enticing visual presentations. Since then, I\'ve been continuously praised for my visuals<br />in meetings and sales pitches.
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--Tell me about how you worked effectively under pressure.-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            The best way to answer this question is to give an example of how you have handled stress in a previous job.<br />That way, the interviewer can get a clear picture of how well you work in stressful situations.<br />Avoid mentioning a time when you put yourself in a needlessly stressful situation.<br />For example, do not share a story about a time when you were stressed because you procrastinated and had to finish a project quickly.<br />Rather, describe a time when you were given a difficult task or multiple assignments, and you rose to the occasion.<br /><br />You also should not focus too much on how stressed out you felt. While you should certainly admit that stress happens, emphasize how you<br />dealt with the stress, rather than how it bothered you. If possible, avoid saying you are stressed by a situation that will be<br />common in the job for which you are applying.<br /><br /><strong>Examples:</strong><br /><br /> - I had been working on a key project that was scheduled for delivery to the client in 60 days. My supervisor came to me and<br />said that we needed to speed it up and be ready in 45 days, while keeping our other projects on time.<br />I made it into a challenge for my staff, and we effectively added just a few hours to each of our schedules and<br />got the job done in 42 days by sharing the workload.<br />Of course, I had a great group of people to work with, but I think that my effective allocation of tasks was a major component of the<br />success of the project.<br /><br /> - Pressure is very important to me. Good pressure, such as having a lot of assignments to work on, or an upcoming deadline,<br />helps me to stay motivated and productive. Of course, there are times when too much pressure can lead to stress;<br />however, I am very skilled at balancing multiple projects and meeting deadlines, which prevents me from feeling stressed often.<br />For example, I once had three large projects due in the same week, which was a lot of pressure. However, because I created a schedule<br />that detailed how I would break down each project into small assignments, I completed all three projects ahead of time and avoided<br />unnecessary stress.<br /><br /> - I am very sensitive to the nuances of group dynamics. If there\'s an unhealthy amount of competition or criticism between<br />team members, this negativity can start to affect my own work performance. And so what I do is to try to proactively listen to<br />the concerns of the people around me, checking in frequently to see if they themselves are under stress. If they are, I think<br />about how I can help them with their workload so the collective stress of the team doesn\'t escalate. When the team\'s happy,<br />I\'m happy.
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--Describe a time when you led by example.-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">

            For more senior-level roles (any position with direct reports), it\'s important to communicate your ability to jump in and assume a<br />leadership role immediately. The best way to do this is to demonstrate that you\'ve done it successfully in the past.<br />For other roles, the leadership challenge may be to lead and motivate people who DON\'T report to you. For example, any project management<br />role or position that requires gaining cooperation and/or buy-in from other departments.<br />For other positions (even entry-level jobs), companies ask about leadership because they want to hire people with leadership potential -<br />individuals who can grow with the company and have superstar potential.<br /><br />Here\'s an overview of how to use the STAR format specifically to present a leadership experience:<br /><br /><strong>S/T (Situation/Task)</strong><br />Briefly describe the project or situation. Give just enough history and/or background to provide context.<br /><br /><strong>Examples:</strong></pre>
<ul>
<li>When I was at ABC Company, we went through some company-wide lay-offs.</li>
<li>The team of five that remained in the department had to absorb the duties of the two that left.</li>
<li>At the same time, more mistakes were being made because attention was so scattered.</li>
</ul>
<pre><strong>A (Approach)</strong><br />Talk about the key actions that you took. When telling a leadership story, make sure that you convey specifically how you stepped up as a leader.<br />What actions did you take and why? How did your actions demonstrate leadership?<br /><br /><strong>Examples:</strong></pre>
<ul>
<li>I scheduled a meeting of the full team to discuss strategies.</li>
<li>I made it clear that this was a brainstorming meeting to come up with options - that no idea was stupid and that it was a safe environment<br />for making suggestions.</li>
<li>I asked for their assistance in identifying ways for us all to be more efficient - including me!</li>
</ul>
<pre>
<strong>R (Results)</strong><br />A strong STAR interview story always includes a happy ending. Wrap up your example by describing the positive outcome(s)<br />of your action. Quantifiable results are particularly impressive (boosted sales by 32%, saved the organization $19K),<br />but anecdotal results also can work well (My client was delighted and sang my praises to my manager, my VP loved our creative<br />approach and promoted me).<br /><br /><strong>Examples:</strong>
<li>First of all, the team responded very positively to this approach. They loved the idea of being empowered to help find a solution.<br />Instead of complaining, they channeled their energy in a more productive way once they knew that they would be heard.</li>
<li>Right off the bat, we came up with two ideas that could be implemented quickly and save us a lot of time.</li>
<li>We are now more efficient and morale is way up.</li>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--Give an example of how you worked on a team.-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
                Before an interview, think of at least two team situations when you displayed some of the teamwork skills listed above.<br />At least one of these examples should include a moment when you helped solve a problem or challenge that struck the group.<br /><br /><strong>Examples:</strong><br /> - During my last semester in college, I worked as part of a research team in the History department. The professor leading the<br />project was writing a book on the development of language in Europe in the Middle Ages. We were each assigned different sectors<br />to focus on, and I suggested that we meet independently before our weekly meeting with the professor to discuss our progress,<br />and help each other out if we were having any difficulties. The professor really appreciated the way we worked together, and<br />it helped to streamline his research as well. He was ready to start on his final copy months ahead of schedule because of the<br />work we helped him with.<br /><br /> - When I was a junior, I worked on a case project for a marketing class where six of us were asked to analyze the<br />marketing practices of Amazon.com and make recommendations for alternative approaches.<br />Early on we floundered in an effort to find a focus. I suggested that we look at Amazon\'s advertising strategy<br />within the social media.<br />I led a discussion about the pros and cons of that topic and encouraged a couple of the more reticent members to chime in.<br />Two of the group members didn\'t initially embrace my original proposal. However, I was able to draw consensus after<br />incorporating their suggestion that we focus on targeted advertising within Facebook based on users\' expressed interests.<br />We ended up working hard as a group, receiving very positive feedback from our professor, and getting an A grade on the project.<br /><br /> - I have years of experience on team projects at my previous marketing job and that has helped me develop into a strong<br />listener who can resolve conflict and ensure timely completion of projects.<br />About a year ago, I was working on a team project with a tight deadline. One team member felt that his voice was not being heard,<br />and as a result, he wasn\'t working quickly enough on his element of the project. I sat down with him and listened to his concerns,<br />and together we came up with a way for him to feel he had more input in the project. By making him feel listened to,<br />I helped our team complete the project successfully and on time.
             </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What do you do if you disagree with someone at work?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            Be prepared. This type of answer always has two parts, and sometimes three. You need to describe a problem, obviously.<br />And you need to show how you actively, not passively, resolved the situation. You don\'t necessarily have to be the one who solved<br />the entire problem, though if you did, good job for you for showing initiative. Many times, however, calling in the right people<br />is the best and most appropriate form of action. Either way, don\'t be shy about telling this to your interviewer.<br /><br />A third part of answering this type of question involves sharing your personal philosophy.<br />Your philosophy can be about your work ethic in general or certain industry-specific issues.<br />Don\'t stress about coming up with a major problem. Not everyone can rescue a company from financial ruin.<br />A problem can be as simple as helping two colleagues who disagree about how to address a task resolve their differences.<br />What you perceive as a problem and how you choose to resolve it tells a whole lot about who you are as a person.<br /><br /><strong>Examples:</strong><br /><br /> - A few years ago, I had a supervisor who wanted me to find ways to outsource most of the work we were doing in my department.<br />I felt that my department was one where having the staff on premises had a huge impact on our effectiveness and ability to relate to<br />our clients. I presented a strong case to her, and she came up with<br />a compromise plan.<br /> - Once I found a major flaw in the work of one of the most senior members of the department, which could have been very costly to<br />the company if it had been overlooked. I went directly to him and called it to his attention so he could fix it before it affected the<br />final outcome.<br /> - I feel that the best way to deal with any challenges is to meet them head-on. When I found that one of my colleagues was saying<br />things that weren\'t true behind my back, I went to him and talked it through. It turned out that he had misunderstood what I had said,<br />and I was able to set the record straight with him, and my supervisor.
             </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--Tell me about a time you had to work closely with someone whose personality or work style clashed with yours.-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            It\'s okay to be honest here, but don\'t bash your former colleague. It\'s important to show that you can be flexible<br />and overcome challenges.<br /><strong><br />Examples:</strong><br /><br /> - I had a supervisor who was ultra-creative, and so he had a creative person\'s impulse-driven approach to projects.<br />I need more structure, so we worked together to develop an Asana project where he could add creative input when inspiration struck,<br />and I had a central place for project notes to keep me on task.
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--Sometimes we have an all-hands-on-deck situation that may require everyone to work extra hours. How would you handle that?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            Like it or not, we\'re working more hours these days. Although you don\'t want to become a slave to the office,<br />if your prospective employer has asked you this question, you can be sure she\'s going to need you to be a team player.<br /><br /><strong>Example:</strong><br /> <br /> - I try to keep a good work/life balance, so I\'d do my best to help my team meet project goals during working hours.<br />That said, crunch times happen. I\'m dedicated to putting in the extra hours when they become necessary.
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What is your biggest professional mistake? How did you handle it?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            You need to show you have come out on the other side of this error ultimately a better employee.<br />Did you learn to become better organized? Do you hold yourself to a higher standard than you did previously?<br />After discussing the story behind your mistake- talk about how you are a better worker because of it.<br />At the end of the day- this is what prospective employers want to see in a candidate- one they know has the capability to grow.<br /><br />Admitting that you have made mistakes is one thing- but it is another thing entirely to mention something extremely detrimental<br />about your personality that could prevent you from getting the job entirely. For example- talking about a time when you missed<br />an important meeting with a client because you spent all of the previous night partying- slept in and forgot to set your alarm<br />might not be the best story to go with. There is generally no need to go into the reasons for why the mistake happened -<br />you just need to get into the story.<br /><br /><strong>Examples:</strong><br /><br /> - Last year- I was leading a team of coworkers to secure a deal with a new client that would have gotten us a lot of business.<br />We did not get it- and as leader of the team- I accepted full responsibility. I took it upon myself to reach out to the potential<br />client to see what we could have done better. It turned out our business just was not as experienced as the company they went<br />with- so I talked with my boss about how we could accentuate other positive aspects of the company to any future clients.<br />A few months later- another client surfaced- and by implementing different strategies- we landed the deal.<br /><br /> - I think the worst mistake I ever made at work was in my first ever job - five years ago now.<br />A more senior member of the team seemed to take an instant dislike to me from the start - and one day she was particularly<br />unpleasant to me in front of several colleagues. Later on, I was talking to one of those colleagues who was, I thought,<br />attempting to console me. Angry and hurt, I foolishly vented my feelings and told her what I thought of the lady in question.<br />I was naturally shocked to find out that she went on to tell everyone what I had said and this certainly didn\'t help my<br />relationship with the team member who was causing me problems. Rather than let the situation carry on, I chose to have a<br />quiet word with this lady so as to find out what her problem was with me and to see if we could put it behind us.<br />It turned out it was nothing personal; she just resented the fact that a friend of hers had also been interviewed<br />for my position and had been turned down. Once we had got matters out into the air, her behaviour changed and we actually<br />got on quite well after that. However, I certainly learned a lot from the experience. I learned that careful communication<br />is vital in managing interpersonal relationships and that if I have a problem with someone it\'s always best to talk it over<br />with them rather than with someone else.
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--Give me an example of a time when you failed to hit a deadline.-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            The most common mistake is to NOT answer the question. I can understand why a candidate might freeze up if asked about a failure.<br />If you haven\'t prepared to address this topic, it can be daunting to try to instantly think of a good example and then describe it<br />in a diplomatic way that shows you are both honest and a smart hire.<br />Many candidates will um and uh for a while and finally say something like: "Well, I can\'t think of any serious failures.<br />I guess I\'ve been fortunate to be pretty successful in most of my positions so far&hellip;"<br />That might seem like a safe way to answer. However, from the interviewer\'s perspective, you\'re not answering the question at all.<br /><br />Here are some guidelines for selecting the right example:<br /><br />1. Choose a real failure. You must answer the question. Don\'t go with something like: "We only improved sales by 35%,<br />but I wanted to do more, so I felt like a failure. I guess I\'m just a perfectionist." (insert a humblebrag shrug)<br /><br />2. Don\'t raise red flags. At the same time, you don\'t have to confess your deepest and darkest secrets. Don\'t choose a failure<br />that was the result of a serious personal mistake (totally forgot to attend the meeting) or character flaw<br />(probably shouldn\'t have called the client "Sweet cheeks"). A team failure can work well because you share responsibility with others<br />(just make sure you acknowledge your role and don\'t try to pass the buck completely).<br /><br />3. Focus on the learning. Pick a story that ends with a compelling example of a lesson learned.<br />Ideally, you should be able to point to applying your hard-won knowledge/skills successfully on a subsequent project.<br /><br /><strong>S/T (Situation/Task)</strong><br />This is the "backstory." Provide an overview of the project or situation. Keep it concise and give only enough background for context.</pre>
<ul>
<li>I would say that my biggest professional failure was in my current role as a project manager at ABC Consulting Corp.</li>
<li>Last year, our team failed to land a $2 million new project from one of our existing clients.</li>
<li>The project should have been ours, but we dropped the ball.</li>
</ul>
<pre><strong>A (Approach)</strong><br />After you have given a brief background of what the failure was, it\'s time to walk through a bit more detail about<br />what happened and why.</pre>
<ul>
<li>I think the biggest issue was that the whole team took it for granted that the project would be ours.</li>
<li>We had a good relationship with the client and we had just wrapped up a very successful project for them.</li>
<li>But in retrospect, we didn\'t go the extra mile to wow them. We didn\'t push as hard as we should have.That opened up the opportunity for a competitor to put on a big show and steal the business.</li>
<li>A team of us, led by the account manager, went to pitch. It was a solid pitch and we got great feedback.</li>
</ul>
<pre><strong>R (Results)</strong><br />A good STAR interview story always features a happy ending. With a failure story, your R section will be a<br />little different than usual. With a typical STAR answer, the R describes the positive outcome(s) of the actions that<br />you took (increased sales, reduced costs, winning presentation).</pre>
<ul>
<li>Losing the business was a real blow to the company - financially and from a morale perspective too.</li>
<li>Our #1 lesson as a team was to never take a client for granted - and to never, ever settle for a "good-enough" pitch.<br />We have to hit all of our presentations out of the park. And I can honestly say that we\'ve done so ever since -<br />and it has led to a record year for new business in our group.</li>
<li>Personally, I learned that I need to pay more attention to the dynamics within the client organization and read between the lines more.</li>
</ul>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--Tell me about a time you learned a new skill. How did you approach it and how to did you apply your new learning?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
           The interviewer wants to know that you can learn new skills, under pressure.<br />Hiring managers want to hear that you are willing to put in the effort required to learn new skills,<br />even when it may seem difficult.<br /><br />Think about times when your company implemented new software, or when you learned a new procedure.<br />Perhaps your employer has asked you to attend a workshop at the last minute, or you had to study for a policy exam.<br />These make great examples! Discuss how you diligently studied related materials, attended a training seminar,<br />or bought a book to help you learn the new content.<br /><br />Keep in mind; this is another excellent opportunity to express that you accept workplace changes with ease.<br /><br /><strong>Examples:</strong><br /><br /> - In my most recent role, I was unfamiliar with their hospital record keeping system. After a few days of on the job<br />training, I was able to maintain the hospital record keeping system, but I still wasn\'t happy with my fluency.<br />I found tutorials online and spent evenings training myself to a deeper level of knowledge. It was nice to dive in,<br />learn the system well, and have that sense of accomplishment early on in my role.<br /><br /> - When I first began my administration career, I started as a temp with an agency.<br />Placed in a variety of roles that changed weekly and sometimes even daily, I often jumped into roles where there was a lot<br />to learn in a short time. Deadlines were often due yesterday. I utilized and maximized my resources to the fullest.<br />I learned about plenty of industries and best of all, had fun doing it!<br /><br /> - When I started my first sales position, I took a pay cut for a highly commissioned opportunity.<br />I had to hit the ground running to get commissioned more quickly and move up the ranks. I had to learn the car industry<br />in no time so that I could start making appointments and sales. I spent the first week shadowing everyone I could,<br />reading the industry publications after hours, and even went to a dealership on the weekend to walk through as though<br />I were purchasing a used car. I wanted to understand them from the customer perspective. By Monday, I felt fully ramped<br />and was making appointments and running demos.

            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What are you most proud of? Why?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            The way you answer this question shows what you value, where you find satisfaction and can let them know if you will<br />be a good fit in their company. What you find important shows them the kind of environment you will do well in.<br />Their job is to figure out if you\'ll do well in their company\'s environment, so they ask a lot of questions that<br />will help them learn more about you. Many companies look for self-motivated individuals who will push themselves<br />towards success rather than need to be pushed.<br /><br /><strong>Points to Emphasize:</strong><br />You know that the interviewer is trying to figure out what motivates you, so there are a few key traits that you want<br />to make sure to touch on.<br /><br /> - Try to focus on experiences and traits that can tie into the position you are applying for.<br /> - Talk about what led you to the moment that made you so proud.<br /> - Discuss what you did after this moment of success.<br /> - Give details about how you plan to achieve this pride again.<br /> - Letting the interviewer know that you strive to have proud moments again will show that you have goals for yourself.<br /><br /><strong>Examples:</strong><br /><br /> - I am most proud of when one of the biggest clients of company ABC was about to switch suppliers and I had to stop<br />them from switching. I used the excellent personal relationship that I had built up with the client over the past year to<br />persuade them to stay with our company and negotiated new terms. The result was that they placed even more orders than the<br />previous quarter.<br /><br /> - I am most proud of when a Google algorithm update made the company I was working for organic traffic plummet and<br />their Adwords spend increase. My job was to fix the site to make sure that it was compliant with the new Google Update<br />and also wouldn\'t be affected by any updates for the foreseeable future. I spent hours fixing the blog and putting a new<br />content plan in place to keep everything controlled. The plan worked, the organic traffic picked up, and the company reduced<br />its Adwords budget.<br /><br />But, don\'t limit your response purely to work achievements; personal accomplishments can be just as important and telling.<br />If this is to be your first job, there may be things you achieved at college or university that you were particularly proud of.<br />If you\'ve had a break from employment to raise a family, you could be most proud of what your children have achieved because<br />of the values you instilled in them as they were growing up.
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--Give an example of how you set goals.-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <strong>Example:</strong><br /> <br /> - Within a few weeks of beginning my first job as a sales associate in a department store,<br />I knew that I wanted to be in the fashion industry.<br />I decided that I would work my way up to department manager, and at that point I would have enough money saved to be able to attend<br />design school full-time.<br />I did just that, and I even landed my first job through an internship I completed the summer before graduation.
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--Give an example of a goal you reached and how you achieved it.-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre>While you don\'t need to be incredibly specific with this answer,<br />demonstrate your understanding of the company and industry and clearly communicate the path you\'re on:</pre>
<ul>
<li>Details your accomplishments to date to show that you have already been able to effectively achieve goals.</li>
<li>Delineate the ways in which your goals align with the job at hand.</li>
<li>Describe any tangible achievements on the horizon.</li>
<li>Convince the interviewer that this position is key to your plan for success.
</li>
<li>Describe your personal qualities that will enable you to achieve your goals.</li>
</ul>
<pre>Avoid answering in a way that puts the focus on salary (raises, bonuses, commission) or job titles.<br />While you want to avoid a vague response, it\'s best to stay away from goals that may or may not be something you can achieve at the<br />company.<br />\n You wouldn\'t, for instance, want to lay out your strategy for being promoted to a management-level position while interviewing at<br />a company that doesn\'t have that role available.<br /><br /><strong>Examples:</strong><br /> <br /> - When I started working for XYZ Company, I wanted to achieve the Employee of the Month title. It was a motivational<br />challenge, and not all the employees took it that seriously, but I really wanted that parking spot, and my picture on the wall.<br />I went out of my way to be helpful to my colleagues, supervisors, and customers - which I would have done anyway, I liked the<br />job and the people I worked with. The third month I was there, I got the honor. It was good to achieve my goal, and I actually<br />ended up moving into a managerial position there pretty quickly, I think because of my positive attitude and perseverance.</pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--Tell me about a goal you failed to achieve.-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
           The goal is to evaluate how the candidate deals with adversity, disappointment, and failure.<br />(Plus, sometimes knowing when to give up is as important as knowing when to start.)<br />\n\n Typical Structure -<br />\n\n -  The interviewee set a huge goal, didn\'t achieve that goal, takes responsibility for not having achieved the goal...<br />and not only takes responsibility but also learned from the experience: About himself, about what to do next time,<br />about what motivates him, about what is truly important to him...<br />\n\n Example:<br />\n\n - In my last job we were given the opportunity to pitch for a major contract - at relatively short notice.<br />I was part of a team that spent a good couple of weeks working very hard on the tender and it was clear that our<br />company was undoubtedly the best choice for the contract. Unfortunately, the client had employed a rather inexperienced<br />individual to review the tenders and they fell for a competitor\'s sales pitch - which had a lot less substance but a lot more spin.<br />It was a major blow. I was naturally very disappointed at what seemed a very unfair decision, especially having put so much<br />effort into the tender - but I wrote it down to experience and got on with successfully bidding for other contracts.<br />The following year, the client having been very dissatisfied with our competitor\'s performance, we were asked to re-tender<br />for the contract. This time, we won it. We did of course learn some lessons from our previous failure but, most of all,<br />we were fortunate that the individual responsible for reviewing the tenders this time was a lot more experienced.
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>

    </string-array>

    <!--Java Technical Questions-->
    <string-array name="javaTechnicalQuestions">
        <item>
            Explain JVM, JRE and JDK?
        </item>
        <item>
            Explain public static void main(String args[]).
        </item>
        <item>
           Why Java is platform independent?
        </item>
        <item>
            Why java is not 100% Object-oriented?
        </item>
        <item>
            What are wrapper classes?
        </item>
        <item>
            What are constructors in Java?
        </item>
        <item>
            What is singleton class and how can we make a class singleton?
        </item>
        <item>
            What is the difference between Array list, Linked list and Vector?
        </item>
        <item>
            What is the difference between equals() and == ?
        </item>
        <item>
            What are the differences between Heap and Stack Memory?
        </item>
        <item>
           What is Polymorphism and runtime polymorphism or dynamic method dispatch?
        </item>
        <item>
           What is Inheritance?
        </item>
        <item>
           What is Abstraction?
        </item>
        <item>
           What is Encapsulation?
        </item>
        <item>
           What is the difference between abstract classes and interfaces?
        </item>
        <item>
           What is method overloading and method overriding?
        </item>
        <item>
            Can you override a private or static method in Java?
        </item>
        <item>
          What is multiple inheritance? Is it supported by Java?
        </item>
        <item>
           What is association?
        </item>
        <item>
           What do you mean by aggregation?
        </item>
        <item>
           What is composition in Java?
        </item>
        <item>
           What is the difference between Error &amp; Exception and how can you handle Java exceptions??
        </item>
        <item>
           What are the differences between Checked Exception and Unchecked Exception?
        </item>
        <item>
           What purpose does the keywords final, finally, and finalize fulfill?
        </item>
        <item>
           What are the differences between throw and throws?
        </item>
        <item>
            What is Exception Propagation?
        </item>
        <item>
           How to create a custom Exception?
        </item>
        <item>
          What are the important methods of Java Exception Class?
        </item>
        <item>
           What are the differences between processes and threads?
        </item>
        <item>
           What is synchronization?
        </item>
        <item>
            Can we write multiple catch blocks under single try block?
        </item>
        <item>
           What is the difference between double and float variables in Java?
        </item>
        <item>
            Why would it be more secure to store sensitive data (such as a password,
            social security number, etc.) in a character array rather than in a String?
        </item>
        <item>
           What is the ThreadLocal class? How and why would you use it?
        </item>
        <item>
           What is the volatile keyword? How and why would you use it?
        </item>
        <item>
           Compare the sleep() and wait() methods in Java, including when and why you would use one vs. the other.
        </item>
        <item>
           What is the Java Classloader? List and explain the purpose of the three types of class loaders.
        </item>
        <item>
           If one needs a Set, how do you choose between HashSet vs. TreeSet?
        </item>
        <item>
           How are Java enums more powerful than integer constants? How can this capability be used?
        </item>
        <item>
            What are static initializers and when would you use them?
        </item>
        <item>
            What is serialization? How do you implement it?
        </item>
    </string-array>

    <!--Java Technical Answers-->
    <string-array name="javaTechnicalAnswers">
        <!--Explain JVM, JRE and JDK?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <strong>JVM </strong>(<strong>Java Virtual Machine</strong>): It is an abstract machine.<br />It is a specification that provides run-time environment in which java bytecode can be executed. It follows three notations:<br />- <strong>Specification</strong>: It is a document that describes the implementation of the Java virtual machine. It is provided by Sun and other companies.<br />- <strong>Implementation</strong>: It is a program that meets the requirements of JVM specification.<br />- <strong>Runtime Instance</strong>: An instance of JVM is created whenever you write a java command on the command prompt and run the class.<br /><br /><strong>JRE</strong> (<strong>Java Runtime Environment</strong>): JRE refers to a runtime environment in which java bytecode can be executed.<br />It implements the JVM (Java Virtual Machine) and provides all the class libraries and other support files that<br />JVM uses at runtime. So JRE is a software package that contains what is required to run a Java program.<br />Basically, it\'s an implementation of the JVM which physically exists.<br /><br /><strong>JDK</strong> (<strong>Java Development Kit</strong>): It is the tool necessary to compile, document and package Java programs.<br />The JDK completely includes JRE which contains tools for Java programmers. The Java Development Kit is provided free of charge.<br />Along with JRE, it includes an interpreter/loader, a compiler (javac), an archiver (jar), a documentation generator (javadoc)<br />and other tools needed in Java development. In short, it contains JRE + development tools.
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--Explain public static void main(String args[]).-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <strong>public</strong>: Public is an access modifier, which is used to specify who can access this method. Public means that this Method will<br />be accessible by any Class.<br />static: It is a keyword in java which identifies it is class based i.e it can be accessed without creating the instance<br />of a Class.<br /><strong>void</strong>: It is the return type of the method. Void defines the method which will not return any value.<br /><strong>main</strong>: It is the name of the method which is searched by JVM as a starting point for an application with a particular<br />signature only. It is the method where the main execution occurs.<br /><strong>String args[]</strong>: It is the parameter passed to the main method.
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--Why Java is platform independent?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            Platform independent practically means "write once run anywhere". Java is called so because of its byte codes which can run<br />on any system irrespective of its underlying operating system.
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--Why java is not 100% Object-oriented?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            Java is not 100% Object-oriented because it makes use of eight primitive datatypes such as boolean, byte, char, int, float,<br />double, long, short which are not objects.
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What are wrapper classes?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            Wrapper classes converts the java primitives into the reference types (objects). Every primitive data type has a class dedicated<br />to it. These are known as wrapper classes because they "wrap" the primitive data type into an object of that class.<br />Refer to the below image which displays different primitive type, wrapper class and constructor argument.
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What are constructors in Java?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            In Java, constructor refers to a block of code which is used to initialize an object. It must have the same name as that<br />of the class. Also, it has no return type and it is automatically called when an object is created.<br /><br />There are two types of constructors:<br />1. Default constructor<br />2. Parameterized constructor
             </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What is singleton class and how can we make a class singleton?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            Singleton class is a class whose only one instance can be created at any given time,<br />in one JVM. A class can be made singleton by making its constructor private.
             </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What is the difference between Array list, Linked list and Vector?-->
        <item>
             <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            Their main difference is their implementation which causes different performance for different operations.<br />ArrayList is implemented as a resizable array. As more elements are added to ArrayList, its size is increased dynamically.<br />It\'s elements can be accessed directly by using the get and set methods, since ArrayList is essentially an array.<br /><br /><strong>LinkedList</strong> is implemented as a double linked list. Its performance on add and remove is better than Arraylist,<br />but worse on get and set methods. Vector is similar with ArrayList, but it is synchronized.<br /><strong>ArrayList</strong> is a better choice if your program is thread-safe. Vector and ArrayList require space as more elements are added.<br /><br /><strong>Vector</strong> each time doubles its array size, while ArrayList grow 50% of its size each time. LinkedList, however, also implements<br />Queue interface which adds more methods than ArrayList and Vector, such as offer(), peek(), poll(), etc.<br /><br /><strong>Note</strong>: The default initial capacity of an ArrayList is pretty small.<br />It is a good habit to construct the ArrayList with a higher initial capacity. This can avoid the resizing cost.<br />Also, Vector is deprecated.
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What is the difference between equals() and == ?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            Equals() method is defined in Object class in Java and used for checking equality of two objects defined by business logic.<br />"==" or equality operator in Java is a binary operator provided by Java programming language and used to compare primitives<br />and objects. public boolean equals(Object o) is the method provided by the Object class.<br />The default implementation uses == operator to compare two objects.<br /><br />Therefore the equals() method compares the "value" inside String instances (on the heap) irrespective<br />if the two object references refer to the same String instance or not.<br />On the other hand, the "==" operator compares the value<br />of two object references to see whether they refer to the same String instance.<br /><br /><strong>For example</strong>: method can be overridden like String class. equals() method is used to compare the values of two objects.
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What are the differences between Heap and Stack Memory?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
           Stack is used for static memory allocation and Heap for dynamic memory allocation, both stored in the computer\'s RAM .<br /><br />Variables allocated on the stack are stored directly to the memory and access to this memory is very fast, and<br />it\'s allocation is dealt with when the program is compiled. When a function or a method calls another function which<br />in turns calls another function etc., the execution of all those functions remains suspended until the very last function<br />returns its value. The stack is always reserved in a LIFO (Last in First out) order, the most recently reserved block is<br />always the next block to be freed. This makes it really simple to keep track of the stack, freeing a block from the stack<br />is nothing more than adjusting one pointer.<br /><br />Variables allocated on the heap have their memory allocated at run time and accessing this memory is a bit slower,<br />but the heap size is only limited by the size of virtual memory. Element of the heap have no dependencies with each other<br />and can always be accessed randomly at any time. You can allocate a block at any time and free it at any time.<br />This makes it much more complex to keep track of which parts of the heap are allocated or free at any given time.<br /><br />You can use the stack if you know exactly how much data you need to allocate before compile time and it is not too big.<br />You can use heap if you don\'t know exactly how much data you will need at runtime or if you need to allocate a lot of data.<br /><br />In a multi-threaded situation each thread will have its own completely independent stack but they will share the heap.<br />Stack is thread specific and Heap is application specific. The stack is important to consider in exception handling and thread<br />executions.
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What is Polymorphism and runtime polymorphism or dynamic method dispatch?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre>Polymorphism is briefly described as "one interface, many implementations".<br />Polymorphism is a characteristic of being able to assign a different meaning or usage to something in different contexts<br />specifically, to allow an entity such as a variable, a function, or an object to have more than one form.<br />There are two types of polymorphism:<br />- Compile time polymorphism<br />- Run time polymorphism<br /><br />Compile time polymorphism is method overloading whereas Runtime time polymorphism is done using inheritance and interface.<br /><br />In Java, runtime polymorphism or dynamic method dispatch is a process in which a call to an overridden method is resolved at<br />runtime rather than at compile-time. In this process, an overridden method is called through the reference variable of a superclass.<br /><br />Example:<br /><br /></pre>

            <pre style="margin: 0; line-height: 125%;"> <em style="color: #008800; font-weight: bold;">class</em> <em style="color: #bb0066; font-weight: bold;">Car</em> <br /><em style="color: #333333;"> {</em>
 <em style="color: #333399; font-weight: bold;">void</em> <em style="color: #0066bb; font-weight: bold;">run</em><em style="color: #333333;">()<br /></em> <em style="color: #333333;">{<br /></em><em style="background-color: #ffffff;"> System</em><em style="color: #333333;">.</em><em style="color: #0000cc;">out</em><em style="color: #333333;">.</em><em style="color: #0000cc;">println</em><em style="color: #333333;">("</em><em style="background-color: #ffffff;">car is running"</em><em style="color: #333333;">);<br /></em> <em style="color: #333333;">}<br /></em> <em style="color: #333333;">}<br /></em> <em style="color: #008800; font-weight: bold;">class</em> <em style="color: #bb0066; font-weight: bold;">Audi</em> <em style="color: #008800; font-weight: bold;">extends</em><em style="background-color: #ffffff;"> Car<br /> </em><em style="color: #333333;">{<br /></em> <em style="color: #333399; font-weight: bold;">void</em> <em style="color: #0066bb; font-weight: bold;">run</em><em style="color: #333333;">()<br /></em> <em style="color: #333333;">{<br /></em><em style="background-color: #ffffff;"> System</em><em style="color: #333333;">.</em><em style="color: #0000cc;">out</em><em style="color: #333333;">.</em><em style="color: #0000cc;">prinltn</em><em style="color: #333333;">("</em><em style="background-color: #ffffff;">Audi is running safely with </em><em style="color: #0000dd; font-weight: bold;">100</em><em style="background-color: #ffffff;">km"</em><em style="color: #333333;">);<br /></em> <em style="color: #333333;">}<br /></em> <em style="color: #008800; font-weight: bold;">public</em> <em style="color: #008800; font-weight: bold;">static</em> <em style="color: #333399; font-weight: bold;">void</em> <em style="color: #0066bb; font-weight: bold;">main</em><em style="color: #333333;">(</em><em style="background-color: #ffffff;">String args</em><em style="color: #333333;">[])<br /></em> <em style="color: #333333;">{<br /></em><em style="background-color: #ffffff;"> Car b</em><em style="color: #333333;">=</em> <em style="color: #008800; font-weight: bold;">new</em><em style="background-color: #ffffff;"> Audi</em><em style="color: #333333;">();</em>    <em style="color: #888888;">//upcasting<br /></em><em style="background-color: #ffffff;"> b</em><em style="color: #333333;">.</em><em style="color: #0000cc;">run</em><em style="color: #333333;">();<br /></em> <em style="color: #333333;">}<br /></em> <em style="color: #333333;">}</em>
</pre>

            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What is inheritance-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
           <pre>Inheritance is the process wherein characteristics are inherited from ancestors. Similarly, in Java,<br />a subclass inherits the characteristics (properties and methods) of its superclass (ancestor).<br />For example, a vehicle is a superclass and a car is a subclass. The car (subclass) inherits all of the vehicle&rsquo;s properties.<br />The inheritance mechanism is very useful in code reuse.<br />The following are some limitations of Java class inheritance: A subclass cannot inherit private members of its superclass.<br />Constructor and initializer blocks cannot be inherited by a subclass. A subclass can have only one superclass.<br /><br />The keyword "extends" is used to derive a subclass from the superclass, as illustrated by the following syntax:</pre>

            <pre><em>class Name_of_subclass extends Name_of superclass</em><br />{ //new fields and methods that would define the subclass go here }<br /><br />If you want to derive a subclass Rectangle from a superclass Shapes, you can do it as follows:<br /><em>class Rectangle extends Shapes { &hellip;. }</em></pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What is Abstraction?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">

            <pre>Data Abstraction is the property by virtue of which only the essential details are displayed to the user.<br />The trivial or the non-essentials units are not displayed to the user.<br />E.g. A car is viewed as a car rather than its individual components.<br /><br />Data Abstraction may also be defined as the process of identifying only the required characteristics of an object<br />ignoring the irrelevant details.The properties and behaviors of an object differentiate it from other objects of similar type<br />and also help in classifying/grouping the objects.<br /><br />Consider a real-life example of a man driving a car. The man only knows that pressing the accelerators will increase the<br />speed of car or applying brakes will stop the car but he does not know about how on pressing the accelerator the speed is<br />actually increasing, he does not know about the inner mechanism of the car or the implementation of accelerator,<br />brakes etc in the car. This is what abstraction is.<br /><br />In java, abstraction is achieved by interfaces and abstract classes. We can achieve 100% abstraction using interfaces.<br /><br />Abstract classes and Abstract methods :<br />1. An abstract class is a class that is declared with abstract keyword.<br />2. An abstract method is a method that is declared without an implementation.<br />3. An abstract class may or may not have all abstract methods. Some of them can be concrete methods<br />4. A method defined abstract must always be redefined in the subclass,thus making overriding compulsory OR either make subclass itself abstract.<br />5. Any class that contains one or more abstract methods must also be declared with abstract keyword.<br />6. There can be no object of an abstract class.That is, an abstract class can not be directly instantiated with the new operator.<br />7. An abstract class can have parametrized constructors and default constructor is always present in an abstract class.<br /><br />Consider a classic "shape" example, perhaps used in a computer-aided design system or game simulation.<br />The base type is "shape" and each shape has a color, size and so on. From this, specific types of shapes are<br />derived(inherited)-circle, square, triangle and so on &ndash; each of which may have additional characteristics and behaviors.<br /><br />For example, certain shapes can be flipped. Some behaviors may be different, such as when you want to calculate the area<br />of a shape. The type hierarchy embodies both the similarities and differences between the shapes.<br /><br />Example:</pre>

          <pre style="margin: 0; line-height: 125%;"><em style="color: #008800; font-weight: bold;">abstract</em> <em style="color: #008800; font-weight: bold;">class</em> <em style="color: #bb0066; font-weight: bold;">Shape<br /></em><em style="color: #333333;">{<br /></em>String color<em style="color: #333333;">;<br /></em><br /><em style="color: #888888;">// these are abstract methods<br /></em><em style="color: #008800; font-weight: bold;">abstract</em> <em style="color: #333399; font-weight: bold;">double</em> <em style="color: #0066bb; font-weight: bold;">area</em><em style="color: #333333;">();<br /></em><em style="color: #008800; font-weight: bold;">public</em> <em style="color: #008800; font-weight: bold;">abstract</em> String <em style="color: #0066bb; font-weight: bold;">toString</em><em style="color: #333333;">();<br /></em><br /><em style="color: #888888;">// abstract class can have constructor<br /></em><em style="color: #008800; font-weight: bold;">public</em> <em style="color: #0066bb; font-weight: bold;">Shape</em><em style="color: #333333;">(</em>String color<em style="color: #333333;">)</em> <em style="color: #333333;">{<br /></em> System<em style="color: #333333;">.</em><em style="color: #0000cc;">out</em><em style="color: #333333;">.</em><em style="color: #0000cc;">println</em><em style="color: #333333;">(</em><em style="background-color: #fff0f0;">"Shape constructor called"</em><em style="color: #333333;">);<br /></em> <em style="color: #008800; font-weight: bold;">this</em><em style="color: #333333;">.</em><em style="color: #0000cc;">color</em> <em style="color: #333333;">=</em> color<em style="color: #333333;">;<br /></em> <em style="color: #333333;">}<br /></em>
<br /><em style="color: #888888;">// this is a concrete method<br /></em><em style="color: #008800; font-weight: bold;">public</em> String <em style="color: #0066bb; font-weight: bold;">getColor</em><em style="color: #333333;">()</em> <em style="color: #333333;">{<br /></em><em style="color: #008800; font-weight: bold;">return</em> color<em style="color: #333333;">;<br /></em><em style="color: #333333;">}<br /></em><em style="color: #333333;">}<br /></em><em style="color: #008800; font-weight: bold;">class</em> <em style="color: #bb0066; font-weight: bold;">Circle</em> <em style="color: #008800; font-weight: bold;">extends</em> Shape<br /><em style="color: #333333;">{<br /></em><em style="color: #333399; font-weight: bold;">double</em> radius<em style="color: #333333;">;<br /></em><br /><em style="color: #008800; font-weight: bold;">public</em> <em style="color: #0066bb; font-weight: bold;">Circle</em><em style="color: #333333;">(</em>String color<em style="color: #333333;">,</em><em style="color: #333399; font-weight: bold;">double</em> radius<em style="color: #333333;">)</em> <em style="color: #333333;">{<br /></em><br /><em style="color: #888888;">// calling Shape constructor<br /></em> <em style="color: #008800; font-weight: bold;">super</em><em style="color: #333333;">(</em>color<em style="color: #333333;">);<br /></em> System<em style="color: #333333;">.</em><em style="color: #0000cc;">out</em><em style="color: #333333;">.</em><em style="color: #0000cc;">println</em><em style="color: #333333;">(</em><em style="background-color: #fff0f0;">"Circle constructor called"</em><em style="color: #333333;">);<br /></em><em style="color: #008800; font-weight: bold;">this</em><em style="color: #333333;">.</em><em style="color: #0000cc;">radius</em> <em style="color: #333333;">=</em> radius<em style="color: #333333;">;<br /></em><em style="color: #333333;">}<br /></em><br /> <em style="color: #555555; font-weight: bold;">@Override<br /></em> <em style="color: #333399; font-weight: bold;">double</em> <em style="color: #0066bb; font-weight: bold;">area</em><em style="color: #333333;">()</em> <em style="color: #333333;">{<br /></em> <em style="color: #008800; font-weight: bold;">return</em> Math<em style="color: #333333;">.</em><em style="color: #0000cc;">PI</em> <em style="color: #333333;">*</em> Math<em style="color: #333333;">.</em><em style="color: #0000cc;">pow</em><em style="color: #333333;">(</em>radius<em style="color: #333333;">,</em> <em style="color: #0000dd; font-weight: bold;">2</em><em style="color: #333333;">);<br /></em> <em style="color: #333333;">}<br /></em><br /><em style="color: #555555; font-weight: bold;">@Override<br /></em> <em style="color: #008800; font-weight: bold;">public</em> String <em style="color: #0066bb; font-weight: bold;">toString</em><em style="color: #333333;">()</em> <em style="color: #333333;">{<br /></em><em style="color: #008800; font-weight: bold;">return</em> <em style="background-color: #fff0f0;">"Circle color is "</em> <em style="color: #333333;">+</em> <em style="color: #008800; font-weight: bold;">super</em><em style="color: #333333;">.</em><em style="color: #0000cc;">color</em> <em style="color: #333333;">+<br /></em><em style="background-color: #fff0f0;">"and area is : "</em> <em style="color: #333333;">+</em> area<em style="color: #333333;">();<br /></em><em style="color: #333333;">}<br /></em><br /><em style="color: #333333;">}<br /></em> <em style="color: #008800; font-weight: bold;">class</em> <em style="color: #bb0066; font-weight: bold;">Rectangle</em> <em style="color: #008800; font-weight: bold;">extends</em> Shape<em style="color: #333333;">{<br /></em>
<em style="color: #333399; font-weight: bold;">double</em> length<em style="color: #333333;">;<br /></em> <em style="color: #333399; font-weight: bold;">double</em> width<em style="color: #333333;">;<br /></em><br /><em style="color: #008800; font-weight: bold;">public</em> <em style="color: #0066bb; font-weight: bold;">Rectangle</em><em style="color: #333333;">(</em>String color<em style="color: #333333;">,</em><em style="color: #333399; font-weight: bold;">double</em> length<em style="color: #333333;">,</em><em style="color: #333399; font-weight: bold;">double</em> width<em style="color: #333333;">)</em> <em style="color: #333333;">{<br /></em> <em style="color: #888888;">// calling Shape constructor<br /></em><em style="color: #008800; font-weight: bold;">super</em><em style="color: #333333;">(</em>color<em style="color: #333333;">);<br /></em>System<em style="color: #333333;">.</em><em style="color: #0000cc;">out</em><em style="color: #333333;">.</em><em style="color: #0000cc;">println</em><em style="color: #333333;">(</em><em style="background-color: #fff0f0;">"Rectangle constructor called"</em><em style="color: #333333;">);<br /></em><em style="color: #008800; font-weight: bold;">this</em><em style="color: #333333;">.</em><em style="color: #0000cc;">length</em> <em style="color: #333333;">=</em> length<em style="color: #333333;">;<br /></em><em style="color: #008800; font-weight: bold;">this</em><em style="color: #333333;">.</em><em style="color: #0000cc;">width</em> <em style="color: #333333;">=</em> width<em style="color: #333333;">;<br /></em><em style="color: #333333;">}<br /></em><br /><em style="color: #555555; font-weight: bold;">@Override<br /></em> <em style="color: #333399; font-weight: bold;">double</em> <em style="color: #0066bb; font-weight: bold;">area</em><em style="color: #333333;">()</em> <em style="color: #333333;">{<br /></em> <em style="color: #008800; font-weight: bold;">return</em> length<em style="color: #333333;">*</em>width<em style="color: #333333;">;<br /></em><em style="color: #333333;">}<br /></em><br /><em style="color: #555555; font-weight: bold;">@Override<br /></em><em style="color: #008800; font-weight: bold;">public</em> String <em style="color: #0066bb; font-weight: bold;">toString</em><em style="color: #333333;">()</em> <em style="color: #333333;">{<br /></em><em style="color: #008800; font-weight: bold;">return</em> <em style="background-color: #fff0f0;">"Rectangle color is "</em> <em style="color: #333333;">+</em> <em style="color: #008800; font-weight: bold;">super</em><em style="color: #333333;">.</em><em style="color: #0000cc;">color</em> <em style="color: #333333;">+<br /></em><em style="background-color: #fff0f0;">"and area is : "</em> <em style="color: #333333;">+</em> area<em style="color: #333333;">();<br /></em><em style="color: #333333;">}<br /></em><br /><em style="color: #333333;">}<br /></em><em style="color: #008800; font-weight: bold;">public</em> <em style="color: #008800; font-weight: bold;">class</em> <em style="color: #bb0066; font-weight: bold;">Test<br /></em><em style="color: #333333;">{<br /></em><em style="color: #008800; font-weight: bold;">public</em> <em style="color: #008800; font-weight: bold;">static</em> <em style="color: #333399; font-weight: bold;">void</em> <em style="color: #0066bb; font-weight: bold;">main</em><em style="color: #333333;">(</em>String<em style="color: #333333;">[]</em> args<em style="color: #333333;">)<br /></em><em style="color: #333333;">{<br /></em>Shape s1 <em style="color: #333333;">=</em> <em style="color: #008800; font-weight: bold;">new</em> Circle<em style="color: #333333;">(</em><em style="background-color: #fff0f0;">"Red"</em><em style="color: #333333;">,</em> <em style="color: #6600ee; font-weight: bold;">2.2</em><em style="color: #333333;">);<br /></em>Shape s2 <em style="color: #333333;">=</em> <em style="color: #008800; font-weight: bold;">new</em> Rectangle<em style="color: #333333;">(</em><em style="background-color: #fff0f0;">"Yellow"</em><em style="color: #333333;">,</em> <em style="color: #0000dd; font-weight: bold;">2</em><em style="color: #333333;">,</em> <em style="color: #0000dd; font-weight: bold;">4</em><em style="color: #333333;">);<br /></em><br />System<em style="color: #333333;">.</em><em style="color: #0000cc;">out</em><em style="color: #333333;">.</em><em style="color: #0000cc;">println</em><em style="color: #333333;">(</em>s1<em style="color: #333333;">.</em><em style="color: #0000cc;">toString</em><em style="color: #333333;">());<br /></em>System<em style="color: #333333;">.</em><em style="color: #0000cc;">out</em><em style="color: #333333;">.</em><em style="color: #0000cc;">println</em><em style="color: #333333;">(</em>s2<em style="color: #333333;">.</em><em style="color: #0000cc;">toString</em><em style="color: #333333;">());<br /></em><em style="color: #333333;">}<br /></em><em style="color: #333333;">}<br /></em>
</pre>

           <pre><strong>Output</strong>:<br /><em> Shape constructor called</em><br /><em> Circle constructor called</em><br /><em> Shape constructor called</em><br /><em> Rectangle constructor called</em><br /><em> Circle color is Redand area is : 15.205308443374602</em><br /><em> Rectangle color is Yellowand area is : 8.0</em></pre>

            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What is Encapsulation?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre>Encapsulation in Java is a mechanism of wrapping the data (variables) and code acting on the data (methods) together as a<br />single unit. In encapsulation, the variables of a class will be hidden from other classes, and can be accessed only through<br />the methods of their current class. Therefore, it is also known as data hiding.<br />To achieve encapsulation in Java; <br />- Declare the variables of a class as private.<br />- Provide public setter and getter methods to modify and view the variables values.<br /><br /><strong>Examples</strong>:</pre>
<pre><em>/* File name : EncapTest.java */</em><br /><em>public class EncapTest {</em><br /><em>private String name;</em><br /><em>private String idNum;</em><br /><em>private int age;</em><br /><br /><em>public int getAge() {</em><br /><em>return age;</em><br /><em>}</em><br /><br /><em>public String getName() {</em><br /><em>return name;</em><br /><em>}</em><br /><br /><em>public String getIdNum() {</em><br /><em>return idNum;</em><br /><em>}</em><br /><br /><em>public void setAge( int newAge) {</em><br /><em>age = newAge;</em><br /><em>}</em><br /><br /><em>public void setName(String newName) {</em><br /><em>name = newName;</em><br /><em>}</em><br /><br /><em>public void setIdNum( String newId) {</em><br /><em>idNum = newId;</em><br /><em>}</em><br /><em>}</em><br /><br />The public setXXX() and getXXX() methods are the access points of the instance variables of the EncapTest class.<br />Normally, these methods are referred as getters and setters. Therefore, any class that wants to access the variables should<br />access them through these getters and setters.<br />The variables of the EncapTest class can be accessed using the following program; <br /><br /><em>/* File name : RunEncap.java */</em><br /><em>public class RunEncap {</em><br /><br /><em>   public static void main(String args[]) </em><br /><em>   {</em><br /><em>      EncapTest encap = new EncapTest();</em><br /><em>      encap.setName("James");</em><br /><em>      encap.setAge(20);</em><br /><em>      encap.setIdNum("12343ms");</em><br /><br /><em>      System.out.print("Name : " + encap.getName() + " Age : " + encap.getAge());</em><br /><em>   }</em><br /><em>}</em></pre>
<pre>This will produce the following result &minus;<br /><br /><strong>Output;</strong><br />Name : James Age : 20</pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What is the difference between abstract classes and interfaces?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre>The key technical differences between an <strong>abstract class</strong> and an <strong>interface</strong> are:<br /><br />- Abstract classes can have constants, members, method stubs (methods without a body) and defined methods,<br />whereas interfaces can only have constants and methods stubs.<br /><br />- Methods and members of an abstract class can be defined with any visibility,<br />whereas all methods of an interface must be defined as public (they are defined public by default).<br /><br />- When inheriting an abstract class, a concrete child class must define the abstract methods,<br />whereas an abstract class can extend another abstract class and abstract methods from the parent class don\'t have to be defined.<br /><br />- Similarly, an interface extending another interface is not responsible for implementing methods from the parent<br />interface. This is because interfaces cannot define any implementation.<br /><br />- A child class can only extend a single class (abstract or concrete), whereas an interface can extend<br />or a class can implement multiple other interfaces.<br /><br />- A child class can define abstract methods with the same or less restrictive visibility,<br />whereas a class implementing an interface must define the methods with the exact same visibility (public).</pre>

            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What is method overloading and method overriding?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre><strong>Method Overloading</strong>:<br />- In Method Overloading, Methods of the same class shares the same name but each method must have different<br />number of parameters or parameters having different types and order.<br />- Method Overloading is to "add" or "extend" more to method\'s behavior.<br />- It is a compile time polymorphism.<br />- The methods must have different signature.<br />- It may or may not need inheritance in Method Overloading.</pre>
<pre> <br /><strong>Example</strong>:<br /><em>class Adder {</em><br /><em>Static int add(int a, int b)</em><br /><em>{</em><br /><em>return a+b;</em><br /><em>}</em><br /><em>Static double add( double a, double b)</em><br /><em>{</em><br /><em>return a+b;</em><br /><em>}</em><br /><em>public static void main(String args[])</em><br /><em>{</em><br /><em>System.out.println(Adder.add(11,11));</em><br /><em>System.out.println(Adder.add(12.3,12.6));</em><br /><em>}}</em><br /><br /><strong>Method Overriding:</strong><br /><br />- In Method Overriding, sub class have the same method with same name and exactly the same number and<br />type of parameters and same return type as a super class.<br />- Method Overriding is to "Change" existing behavior of method.<br />- It is a run time polymorphism.<br />- The methods must have same signature.<br />- It always requires inheritance in Method Overriding.<br /><br /><strong>Example</strong>:<br /><br /><em>class Car {</em><br /><em>void run(){</em><br /><em>System.out.println("car is running");</em><br /><em>}</em><br /><em>Class Audi extends Car{</em><br /><em>void run()</em><br /><em>{</em><br /><em>System.out.prinltn("Audi is running safely with 100km");</em><br /><em>}</em><br /><em>public static void main( String args[])</em><br /><em>{</em><br /><em>Car b=new Audi();</em><br /><em>b.run();</em><br /><em>}</em><br /><em>}</em></pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--Can you override a private or static method in Java?-->
        <item>
             <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
             <pre>You cannot override a private or static method in Java. If you create a similar method with same return type and same<br />method arguments in child class then it will hide the super class method; this is known as method hiding. Similarly,<br />you cannot override a private method in sub class because it\'s not accessible there. What you can do is create another<br />private method with the same name in the child class.<br /><br /><strong>Example</strong>:<br /><br /><em>class Base {</em><br /><em>private static void display() {</em><br /><em>System.out.println("Static or class method from Base");</em><br /><em>}</em><br /><em>public void print() {</em><br /><em>System.out.println("Non-static or instance method from Base");</em><br /><em>}</em><br /><em>class Derived extends Base {</em><br /><em>private static void display() {</em><br /><em>System.out.println("Static or class method from Derived");</em><br /><em>}</em><br /><em>public void print() {</em><br /><em>System.out.println("Non-static or instance method from Derived");</em><br /><em>}</em><br /><em>public class test {</em><br /><em>public static void main(String args[])</em><br /><em>{</em><br /><em>Base obj= new Derived();</em><br /><em>obj1.display();</em><br /><em>obj1.print();</em><br /><em>}</em><br /><em>}</em></pre>

            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What is multiple inheritance? Is it supported by Java?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
           <pre>If a child class inherits the property from multiple classes is known as multiple inheritance. Java does not allow to<br />extend multiple classes.<br />The problem with multiple inheritance is that if multiple parent classes have a same method name, then at runtime<br />it becomes difficult for the compiler to decide which method to execute from the child class.<br />Therefore, Java doesn\'t support multiple inheritance. The problem is commonly referred as Diamond Problem.</pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What is Association? -->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre><strong>Association</strong> is a relationship where all object have their own lifecycle and there is no owner.<br />Let\'s take an example of Teacher and Student. Multiple students can associate with a single teacher and<br />a single student can associate with multiple teachers but there is no ownership between the objects and<br />both have their own lifecycle. These relationship can be one to one, One to many, many to one and many to many.</pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What do you mean by aggregation?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre><strong>Aggregation</strong> is a specialized form of Association where all object have their own lifecycle but there is ownership and<br />child object can not belongs to another parent object. Let\'s take an example of Department and teacher.<br />A single teacher can not belong to multiple departments, but if we delete the department teacher object will not destroy.</pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What is composition in Java?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre><strong>Composition</strong> is again specialized form of Aggregation and we can call this as a "death" relationship.<br />It is a strong type of Aggregation. Child object dose not have their lifecycle and if parent object deletes<br />all child object will also be deleted. Let\'s take again an example of relationship between House and rooms.<br />House can contain multiple rooms there is no independent life of room and any room can not belong to two different house<br />if we delete the house room will automatically delete.</pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What is the difference between Error & Exception and how can you handle Java exceptions??-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre>An error is an irrecoverable condition occurring at runtime. Such as OutOfMemory error.<br />These JVM errors you can not repair them at runtime.Though error can be caught in catch block but the execution<br />of application will come to a halt and is not recoverable.<br />While exceptions are conditions that occur because of bad input or human error etc.<br />e.g. FileNotFoundException will be thrown if the specified file does not exist.<br />Or a NullPointerException will take place if you try using a null reference.<br />In most of the cases it is possible to recover from an exception<br />(probably by giving user a feedback for entering proper values etc).<br /><br />There are five keywords used to handle exceptions in Java:<br /><br />1. try<br />2. catch<br />3. finally<br />4. throw<br />5. throws</pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What are the differences between Checked Exception and Unchecked Exception?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre><strong>Checked Exception</strong><br />- The classes that extend Throwable class except RuntimeException and Error are known as checked exceptions.<br />- Checked exceptions are checked at compile-time.<br />- Example: IOException, SQLException etc.<br /><br /><strong>Unchecked Exception</strong><br />- The classes that extend RuntimeException are known as unchecked exceptions.<br />- Unchecked exceptions are not checked at compile-time.<br />- Example: ArithmeticException, NullPointerException etc.</pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What purpose does the keywords final, finally, and finalize fulfill?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre><strong>Final</strong>:<br />Final is used to apply restrictions on class, method and variable. Final class can\'t be inherited,<br />final method can\'t be overridden and final variable value can\'t be changed.<br /><br /><strong>Example</strong>:<br /><em>class FinalVarExample {</em><br /><br /><em>public static void main( String args[])</em><br /><em>{</em><br /><em>final int a=10;   // Final variable</em><br /><em>a=50;             //Error as value can\'t be changed</em><br /><em>}</em><br /><br /><strong>Finally:</strong><br />Finally is used to place important code, it will be executed whether exception is handled or not.<br /><br /><strong>Example</strong>:<br /><em>class FinallyExample {</em><br /><br /><em>public static void main(String args[]){</em><br /><em>try {</em><br /><em>int x=100;</em><br /><em>}</em><br /><em>catch(Exception e) {</em><br /><em>System.out.println(e);</em><br /><em>}</em><br /><em>finally {</em><br /><em>System.out.println("finally block is executing");}</em><br /><em>}}</em><br /><em>}</em><br /><br /><strong>Finalize</strong><br />Finalize is used to perform clean up processing just before object is garbage collected.<br /><br /><strong>Example</strong>:<br /><em>class FinalizeExample {</em><br /><br /><em>public void finalize() {</em><br /><em>System.out.println("Finalize is called");</em><br /><em>}</em><br /><br /><em>public static void main(String args[])</em><br /><em>{</em><br /><em>FinalizeExample f1=new FinalizeExample();</em><br /><em>FinalizeExample f2=new FinalizeExample();</em><br /><em>f1= NULL;</em><br /><em>f2=NULL;</em><br /><em>System.gc();</em><br /><em>}</em><br /><em>}</em></pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What are the differences between throw and throws?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre>1. throws clause is used to declare an exception and throw keyword is used to throw an exception explicitly.<br />2. If we see syntax wise then throw is followed by an instance variable and throws is followed by exception class names.<br />3. The keyword throw is used inside method body to invoke an exception and throws clause is used in method declaration<br />(signature).<br />4. You cannot declare multiple exceptions with throw. You can declare multiple exception e.g. public void method()throws<br />IOException,SQLException.<br />5. Checked Exceptions can not be propagated with throw only because it is explicitly used to throw an particular exception. checked exception can be propagated with throws.</pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What is exception propagation?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre>After a method throws an exception, the runtime system searches the call stack for a method that<br />contains a block of code(exception handler) that can handle the exception. The search begins with<br />the method in which the error occurred and proceeds through the call stack in the reverse order in<br />which the methods were called. When an appropriate handler is found, the runtime system passes the<br />exception to the handler.<br />Also, there\'s a note-worthy point: Only unchecked exceptions are propagated. Checked exceptions throw compilation error<br /><br />Lets say, we have a chain of methods where method3() calls method2() and method2() calls method1(). So when<br />1) An exception occurs in the method3() and in method3() we don\'t have any exception handler.<br />2) Uncaught exception will be propagated downward in stack i.e it will check appropriate exception handler in the method2().<br />3) Again in method2 if we don\'t have any exception handler then again exception is propagated downward to method1()<br />where it finds exception handler.<br /><br /><strong>Example</strong>:<br /><br /><em>class ExceptionPropagation{</em><br /><br /><em>void method3(){</em><br /><em>      int result = 100 / 0;  //Exception Generated</em><br /><em>}</em><br /><br /><em>void method2(){</em><br /><em>      method3();</em><br /><em>}</em><br /><br /><em>void method1(){</em><br /><em>try{</em><br /><em>   method2();</em><br /><em>} catch(Exception e){</em><br /><em>System.out.println("Exception is handled here");</em><br /><em>}</em><br /><em>}</em><br /><br /><em>public static void main(String args[]){</em><br /><em>ExceptionPropagation obj=new ExceptionPropagation();</em><br /><em>obj.method1();</em><br /><em>System.out.println("Continue with Normal Flow...");</em><br /><em>}</em><br /><em>}</em><br /><br /><strong>Output</strong>:<br /><br />Exception is handled here<br /><br />Continue with Normal Flow...</pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--How to create a custom Exception?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre>- class New1Exception extends Exception { }               // this will create Checked Exception<br />- class NewException extends IOException { }             // this will create Checked exception<br />- class NewException extends NullPointerException { }  // this will create UnChecked exception</pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What are the important methods of Java Exception Class?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre>Exception and all of it\'s subclasses doesn\'t provide any specific methods and all of the methods are defined in the base<br />class Throwable.<br /><br />1. String getMessage() &ndash; This method returns the message String of Throwable and the message can be provided while creating the exception through it\'s constructor.<br />2. String getLocalizedMessage() &ndash; This method is provided so that subclasses can override it to provide locale specific message to the calling program. Throwable class implementation of this method simply use getMessage() method to return the exception message.<br />3. Synchronized Throwable getCause() &ndash; This method returns the cause of the exception or null id the cause is unknown.<br />4. String toString() &ndash; This method returns the information about Throwable in String format, the returned String contains the name of Throwable class and localized message.<br />5. void printStackTrace() &ndash; This method prints the stack trace information to the standard error stream, this method is overloaded and we can pass PrintStream or PrintWriter as argument to write the stack trace information to the file or stream.<br /><br /></pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What are the differences between processes and threads?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre>Key difference: Thread and Process are two closely related terms in multi-threading.<br />The main difference between the two terms is that the threads are a part of a process,<br />i.e. a process may contain one or more threads, but a thread cannot contain a process.<br /><br />In programming, there are two basic units of execution: processes and threads.<br />They both execute a series of instructions. Both are initiated by a program or the operating system.<br />This article helps to differentiate between the two units.<br /><br />Process A process is an instance of a program that is being executed. It contains the program code and its current activity.<br />Depending on the operating system, a process may be made up of multiple threads of execution that execute instructions<br />concurrently. A program is a collection of instructions; a process is the actual execution of those instructions.<br /><br />A process has a self-contained execution environment. It has a complete set of private basic run-time resources;<br />in particular, each process has its own memory space. Processes are often considered similar to other programs or applications.<br />However, the running of a single application may in fact be a set of cooperating processes.<br />To facilitate communication between the processes, most operating systems use Inter Process Communication (IPC) resources,<br />such as pipes and sockets. The IPC resources can also be used for communication between processes on different systems.<br />Most applications in a virtual machine run as a single process. However, it can create additional processes using a process<br />builder object.<br /><br />In computers, a thread can execute even the smallest sequence of programmed instructions that can be managed independently<br />by an operating system. The applications of threads and processes differ from one operating system to another.<br />However, the threads are made of and exist within a process; every process has at least one. Multiple threads can also<br />exist in a process and share resources, which helps in efficient communication between threads.<br /><br />On a single processor, multitasking takes place as the processor switches between different threads; it is known<br />as multithreading. The switching happens so frequently that the threads or tasks are perceived to be running at the same time.<br />Threads can truly be concurrent on a multiprocessor or multi-core system, with every processor or core executing the<br />separate threads simultaneously.<br /><br />In summary, threads may be considered lightweight processes, as they contain simple sets of instructions and can<br />run within a larger process. Computers can run multiple threads and processes at the same time.<br /><br />Comparison between <strong>Process</strong> and <strong>Thread</strong>:<br /><br /><strong>Process</strong>:<br />- An executing instance of a program is called a process.<br />- It has its own copy of the data segment of the parent process.<br />- Processes must use inter-process communication to communicate with sibling processes.<br />- Processes have considerable overhead.<br />- New processes require duplication of the parent process.<br />- Processes can only exercise control over child processes.<br />- Any change in the parent process does not affect child processes.<br />- Run in separate memory spaces.<br />- Most file descriptors are not shared.<br />- There is no sharing of file system context.<br />- It does not share signal handling.<br />- Process is controlled by the operating system.<br />- Processes are independent.<br /><br /><strong>Thread</strong>:<br />- A thread is a subset of the process.<br />- It has direct access to the data segment of its process.<br />- Threads can directly communicate with other threads of its process.<br />- Threads have almost no overhead.<br />- New threads are easily created.<br />- Threads can exercise considerable control over threads of the same process.<br />- Any change in the main thread may affect the behavior of the other threads of the process.<br />- Run in shared memory spaces.<br />- It shares file descriptors.<br />- It shares file system context.<br />- It shares signal handling.<br />- Threads are controlled by programmer in a program.<br />- Threads are dependent.</pre>
             </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What is synchronizations?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre><strong>Synchronization</strong> refers to multi-threading. A synchronized block of code can be executed by only one thread at a time.<br />As Java supports execution of multiple threads, two or more threads may access the same fields or objects.<br />Synchronization is a process which keeps all concurrent threads in execution to be in sync. Synchronization avoids<br />memory consistency errors caused due to inconsistent view of shared memory. When a method is declared as synchronized<br />the thread holds the monitor for that method\'s object. If another thread is executing the synchronized method the thread<br />is blocked until that thread releases the monitor.</pre>
             </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--Can we write multiple catch blocks under single try blocks?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre>It is possible to have multiple catch blocks under single try block but the approach should be from specific to general.<br /><br /><strong>Example</strong>:<br /><em>public class Example {</em><br /><em>public static void main(String args[]) {</em><br /><em>try {</em><br /><em>int a[]= new int[10];</em><br /><em>a[10]= 10/0;</em><br /><em>}</em><br /><em>catch(ArithmeticException e)</em><br /><em>{</em><br /><em>System.out.println("Arithmetic exception in first catch block");</em><br /><em>}</em><br /><em>catch(ArrayIndexOutOfBoundsException e)</em><br /><em>{</em><br /><em>System.out.println("Array index out of bounds in second catch block");</em><br /><em>}</em><br /><em>catch(Exception e)</em><br /><em>{</em><br /><em>System.out.println("Any exception in third catch block");</em><br /><em>}</em><br /><em>}</em></pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What is the difference between double and float variables in Java?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre>Though both float and double datatype are used to represent floating point numbers in Java, a double data type is more precise<br />than float. A double variable can provide precision up to 15 to 16 decimal points as compared to float precision of 6 to 7<br />decimal digits. Another significant difference between float and double is their storage requirement,<br />double is more expensive than float. It takes 8 bytes to store a variable while float just takes 4 bytes.<br />Which means, if memory is constraint than its better to use float than double. BTW, the double type also has larger<br />range than float and if your numbers don\'t fit well in float then you have to use double in Java. It\'s also worth noting<br />that floating point numbers or real numbers are by default double in Java. If you want to store them into float variable,<br />you need to either cast them or use a prefix \'f\' or \'F\'.<br /><br />Also to note that: float uses 1 bits for sign, 8 bits for exponent and 23 bits for mantissa,<br />while double uses 1 bits for sign, 11 bits for exponent and 52 bits for mantissa.</pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--Why would it be more secure to store sensitive data (such as a password,
        social security number, etc.) in a character array rather than in a String?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre>In Java, Strings are immutable and are stored in the String pool.<br />What this means is that, once a String is created, it stays in the pool in memory until being garbage collected.<br />Therefore, even after you\'re done processing the string value (e.g., the password), it remains available in memory<br />for an indeterminate period of time thereafter (again, until being garbage collected) which you have no real control over.<br />Therefore, anyone having access to a memory dump can potentially extract the sensitive data and exploit it.<br /><br />In contrast, if you use a mutable object like a character array, for example, to store the value, you can set it to<br />blank once you are done with it with confidence that it will no longer be retained in memory.</pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What is the ThreadLocal class? How and why would you use it?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre>A single ThreadLocal instance can store different values for each thread independently.<br />Each thread that accesses the get() or set() method of a ThreadLocal instance is accessing its own,<br />independently initialized copy of the variable. ThreadLocal instances are typically private static fields in<br />classes that wish to associate state with a thread (e.g., a user ID or transaction ID).<br />The example below, from the ThreadLocal Javadoc, generates unique identifiers local to each thread.<br />A thread\'s id is assigned the first time it invokes ThreadId.get() and remains unchanged on subsequent calls.<br /><br /><strong>Example</strong>:<br /><em>public class ThreadId {</em><br /><em> // Next thread ID to be assigned</em><br /><em>private static final AtomicInteger nextId = new AtomicInteger(0);</em><br /><br /><em>// Thread local variable containing each thread\'s ID</em><br /><em> private static final ThreadLocal&amp;lt;Integer&amp;gt; threadId =</em><br /><em> new ThreadLocal&amp;lt;Integer&amp;gt;() {</em><br /><em> @Override protected Integer initialValue() {</em><br /><em> return nextId.getAndIncrement();</em><br /><em> }</em><br /><em> };</em><br /><br /><em>// Returns the current thread\'s unique ID, assigning it if necessary</em><br /><em>public static int get() {</em><br /><em>return threadId.get();</em><br /><em>}</em><br /><em> }</em><br /><br />Each thread holds an implicit reference to its copy of a thread-local variable as long as the thread is alive and<br />the ThreadLocal instance is accessible; after a thread goes away, all of its copies of thread-local instances are subject<br />to garbage collection (unless other references to these copies exist).</pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What is the volatile keyword? How and why would you use it?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre>In Java, each thread has its own stack, including its own copy of variables it can access.<br />When the thread is created, it copies the value of all accessible variables into its own stack.<br />The volatile keyword basically says to the JVM "Warning, this variable may be modified in another Thread".<br /><br />In all versions of Java, the volatile keyword guarantees global ordering on reads and writes to a variable.<br />This implies that every thread accessing a volatile field will read the variable\'s current value instead of (potentially)<br />using a cached value.<br /><br />In Java 5 or later, volatile reads and writes establish a happens-before relationship, much like acquiring and<br />releasing a mutex.<br /><br />Using volatile may be faster than a lock, but it will not work in some situations. The range of situations in which<br />volatile is effective was expanded in Java 5; in particular, double-checked locking now works correctly.<br /><br />The volatile keyword is also useful for 64-bit types like long and double since they are written in two operations.<br />Without the volatile keyword you risk stale or invalid values.<br /><br />One common example for using volatile is for a flag to terminate a thread. If you\'ve started a thread, and<br />you want to be able to safely interrupt it from a different thread, you can have the thread periodically<br />check a flag (i.e., to stop it, set the flag to true). By making the flag volatile, you can ensure that the thread that<br />is checking its value will see that it has been set to true without even having to use a synchronized block.<br /><br /><strong>Example</strong>:<br /><em>public class Foo extends Thread {</em><br /><em>private volatile boolean close = false;</em><br /><em>public void run() {</em><br /><em>while(!close) {</em><br /><em>// do work</em><br /><em>}</em><br /><em>}</em><br /><em>public void close() {</em><br /><em>close = true;</em><br /><em>// interrupt here if needed</em><br /><em>}</em><br /><em>}</em></pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--Compare the sleep() and wait() methods in Java, including when and why you would use one vs. the other.-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre>- sleep() is a blocking operation that keeps a hold on the monitor / lock of the shared object for the specified number of<br />milliseconds.<br /><br />- wait(), on the other hand, simply pauses the thread until either (a) the specified number of milliseconds<br />have elapsed or(b) it receives a desired notification from another thread (whichever is first),<br />without keeping a hold on the monitor/lock of the shared object.<br /><br />- sleep() is most commonly used for polling, or to check for certain results, at a regular interval.<br />wait() is generally used in multithreaded applications, in conjunction with notify() / notifyAll(),<br />to achieve synchronization and avoid race conditions.</pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What is the Java Classloader? List and explain the purpose of the three types of the class loaders.        -->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre>The Java Classloader is the part of the Java runtime environment that loads classes on demand (lazy loading)<br />into the JVM (Java Virtual Machine). Classes may be loaded from the local file system, a remote file system, or even the web.<br /><br />When the JVM is started, three class loaders are used:<br />1. Bootstrap Classloader: Loads core java API file rt.jar from folder.<br />2. Extension Classloader: Loads jar files from folder.<br />3. System/Application Classloader: Loads jar files from path specified in the CLASSPATH environment variable.</pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--if one needs a Set, how do you choose between HashSet vs TreeSet?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre>At first glance, HashSet is superior in almost every way: O(1) add, remove and contains, vs. O(log(N)) for TreeSet.<br /><br />However, TreeSet is indispensable when you wish to maintain order over the inserted elements or query for a range of<br />elements within the set.<br /><br />Consider a Set of timestamped Event objects. They could be stored in a HashSet, with equals and hashCode based on that<br />timestamp. This is efficient storage and permits looking up events by a specific timestamp, but how would you get all events<br />that happened on any given day? That would require a O(n) traversal of the HashSet, but it&rsquo;s only a O(log(n)) operation with<br />TreeSet using the tailSet method;<br /><br /><em>public class Event implements Comparable&lt;Event&gt; {</em><br /><em>private final long timestamp;</em><br /><em><br />public Event(long timestamp) {</em><br /><em>      this.timestamp = timestamp;</em><br /><em>}</em><br /><br /><em>@Override <br />public int compareTo(Event that) {</em><br /><em>      return Long.compare(this.timestamp, that.timestamp);</em><br /><em>   }</em><br /><em>}</em><br /><em>         ...<br /></em><br /><em>SortedSet&lt;Event&gt; events = new TreeSet&lt;&gt;();</em><br /><em>events.addAll(...); // events come in</em><br /><br /><em>// all events that happened today</em><br /><em>long midnightToday = ...;</em><br /><em>events.tailSet(new Event(midnightToday));</em><br /><em>}</em><br /><br />If Event happens to be a class that we cannot extend or that doesn&rsquo;t implement Comparable,<br />TreeSet allows us to pass in our own Comparator:<br /><br /><em>SortedSet&lt;Event&gt;; events = new TreeSet&lt;&gt;(</em><br /><em>    (left, right) -&gt; Long.compare(left.timestamp, right.timestamp));</em><br /><br />Generally speaking, TreeSet is a good choice when order matters and when reads are balanced against the increased cost of writes.</pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--How are Java enums more powerful than integer constants? How can this capability be used?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre>Enums are essentially final classes with a fixed number of instances. They can implement interfaces but cannot extend<br />another class.<br />This flexibility is useful in implementing the strategy pattern, for example, when the number of strategies is fixed.<br />Consider an address book that records multiple methods of contact. We can represent these methods as an enum and attach fields,<br />like the filename of the icon to display in the UI, and any corresponding behaviour, like how to initiate contact via that method:<br /><br /><em>public enum ContactMethod {</em><br /><em>PHONE("telephone.png") {</em><br /><em>@Override public void initiate(User user) {</em><br /><em>    Telephone.dial(user.getPhoneNumber());</em><br /><em>    }</em><br /><em>},</em><br /><em>EMAIL("envelope.png") {</em><br /><em>@Override public void initiate(User user) {</em><br /><em>       EmailClient.sendTo(user.getEmailAddress());</em><br /><em>    }</em><br /><em>},</em><br /><em> SKYPE("skype.png") {</em><br /><em>     ...</em><br /><em>};</em><br /><br /><em>ContactMethod(String icon) {</em><br /><em>    this.icon = icon;</em><br /><em>}</em><br /><br /><em>private final String icon;</em><br /><br /><em>public abstract void initiate(User user);</em><br /><br /><em>public String getIcon() {</em><br /><em>     return icon;</em><br /><em>}</em><br /><em>}</em><br /><br />We can dispense with switch statements entirely by simply using instances of ContactMethod:<br /><br /><em>ContactMethod method = user.getPrimaryContactMethod();</em><br /><em>displayIcon(method.getIcon());</em><br /><em>method.initiate(user);</em><br /><br />This is just the beginning of what can be done with enums.<br />Generally, the safety and flexibility of enums means they should be used in place of integer constants,<br />and switch statements can be eliminated with liberal use of abstract methods.</pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What are static initializers and when would you use them?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre>A static initializer gives you the opportunity to run code during the initial loading of a class and it guarantees<br />that this code will only run once and will finish running before your class can be accessed in any way.<br />They are useful for performing initialization of complex static objects or to register a type with a static registry,<br />as JDBC drivers do.<br />Suppose you want to create a static, immutable Map containing some feature flags.<br />Java doesn\'t have a good one-liner for initializing maps, so you can use static initializers instead:<br /><br /><em>public static final Map&lt;String, Boolean&gt; FEATURE_FLAGS;</em><br /><em>static {</em><br /><em>Map&lt;String, Boolean&gt; flags = new HashMap&lt;&gt;();</em><br /><em>flags.put("frustrate-users", false);</em><br /><em>flags.put("reticulate-splines", true);</em><br /><em>flags.put(...);</em><br /><em>FEATURE_FLAGS = Collections.unmodifiableMap(flags);</em><br /><em>}<br /></em><br />Within the same class, you can repeat this pattern of declaring a static field and immediately initializing it,<br />since multiple static initializers are allowed.</pre>            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--what is serialization? how do you implement it?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre>Serialization is the process of converting an object into a stream of bytes in order to store an object into memory,<br />so that it can be recreated at a later time, while still keeping the object\'s original state and data.<br /><br />After a serialized object has been written into a file, it can be read from the file and deserialized that is,<br />the type information and bytes that represent the object and its data can be used to recreate the object in memory.<br /><br />Most impressive is that the entire process is JVM independent, meaning an object can be serialized on one platform and<br />deserialized on an entirely different platform.<br /><br />Classes ObjectInputStream and ObjectOutputStream are high-level streams that contain the methods for serializing<br />and deserializing an object.<br /><br /><strong>Example</strong>:<br /><br />Suppose that we have the following Employee class, which implements the Serializable interface;<br /><br /><em>public class Employee implements java.io.Serializable {</em><br /><em>public String name;</em><br /><em>public String address;</em><br /><em>public transient int SSN;</em><br /><em>public int number;</em><br /><br /><em>public void mailCheck() {</em><br /><em>      System.out.println("Mailing a check to " + name + " " + address);</em><br /><em>   }</em><br /><em>}</em><br /><br /><strong>Serializing an Object</strong>;<br /><br /><em>import java.io.*;</em><br /><em>public class SerializeDemo {</em><br /><br /><em>public static void main(String [] args) {</em><br /><em>Employee e = new Employee();</em><br /><em> e.name = "Reyan Ali";</em><br /><em> e.address = "Phokka Kuan, Ambehta Peer";</em><br /><em> e.SSN = 11122333;</em><br /><em> e.number = 101;</em><br /><br /><em> try {</em><br /><em> FileOutputStream fileOut =</em><br /><em> new FileOutputStream("/tmp/employee.ser");</em><br /><em> ObjectOutputStream out = new ObjectOutputStream(fileOut);</em><br /><em> out.writeObject(e);</em><br /><em> out.close();</em><br /><em> fileOut.close();</em><br /><em> System.out.printf("Serialized data is saved in /tmp/employee.ser");</em><br /> <br /><em>} catch (IOException i) {</em><br /><em> i.printStackTrace();</em><br /><em> }</em><br /><em> }</em><br /><em> }</em><br /><br /><strong>Note</strong> &minus; When serializing an object to a file, the standard convention in Java is to give the file a .ser extension.<br /><br /><strong>Deserializing an Object</strong>;<br /><br /><em>import java.io.*;</em><br /><em>public class DeserializeDemo {</em><br /><br /><em>public static void main(String [] args) {</em><br /><em>Employee e = null;</em><br /><br /><em>try {</em><br /><em> FileInputStream fileIn = new FileInputStream("/tmp/employee.ser");</em><br /><em> ObjectInputStream in = new ObjectInputStream(fileIn);</em><br /><em> e = (Employee) in.readObject();</em><br /><em> in.close();</em><br /><em> fileIn.close();</em><br /> <br /><em>}</em><br /><em> catch (IOException i) {</em><br /><em> i.printStackTrace();</em><br /><em> return;</em><br /> <br /><em>}</em><br /><em> catch (ClassNotFoundException c) {</em><br /><em> System.out.println("Employee class not found");</em><br /><em> c.printStackTrace();</em><br /><em> return;</em><br /><em> }</em><br /><br /><em> System.out.println("Deserialized Employee...");</em><br /><em> System.out.println("Name: " + e.name);</em><br /><em> System.out.println("Address: " + e.address);</em><br /><em> System.out.println("SSN: " + e.SSN);</em><br /><em> System.out.println("Number: " + e.number);</em><br /><em>  }</em><br /><em> }</em><br /><br /><strong>Output</strong>:<br /><br />Deserialized Employee...<br />Name: Reyan Ali<br />Address:Phokka Kuan, Ambehta Peer<br />SSN: 0<br />Number:101</pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
    </string-array>

    <!--Android Technical Questions-->
    <string-array name="androidTechnicalQuestions">
        <item>
            Why did you become an Android developer? What are some of the advantages of the Android platform?
        </item>
        <item>
            What are the latest Android versions? The most important Oreo new features?
        </item>
        <item>
            What Is the Google Android SDK?
        </item>
        <item>
            What is the Android Architecture?
        </item>
        <item>
            Describe the Android Framework.
        </item>
        <item>
             What is AAPT?
        </item>
        <item>
            Mention Native Android Actions?
        </item>
        <item>
            Describe Activities.
        </item>
        <item>
             What do you know about Material design?
        </item>
        <item>
            What’s the difference between Dialog and AlertDialog in Android?
        </item>
        <item>
            What’s the difference between FrameLayout, GridLayout, ConstraintLayout, LinearLayout and RelativeLayout and which has better performance?
        </item>
        <item>
            What are Intents and Describe three common use cases for using an Intent.
        </item>
        <item>
            Where should you use implicit and explicit intent?
        </item>
        <item>
            What is the function of an intent filter?
        </item>
        <item>
            What are containers?
        </item>
        <item>
             What do you think are some disadvantages of Android?
        </item>
        <item>
            What are the four essential states of an activity?
        </item>
        <item>
            What are the seven lifecycle methods of Android activity and what is their purpose?
        </item>
        <item>
            The last callback in the lifecycle of an activity is onDestroy().
            The system calls this method on your activity as the final signal that your activity instance is being completely
            removed from the system memory. Usually, the system will call onPause() and onStop() before calling onDestroy().
            Describe a scenario, though, where onPause() and onStop() would not be invoked.
        </item>
        <item>
            What is the importance of settings permissions in app development?
        </item>
        <item>
            Enumerate the three key loops when monitoring an activity.
        </item>
        <item>
            What is the difference between a fragment and an activity? Explain the relationship between the two.
        </item>
        <item>
            Which method is called only once in a fragment life cycle?
        </item>
        <item>
            When is the onStop() method invoked?
        </item>
        <item>
            What are the different states wherein a process is based?
        </item>
        <item>
            How to communicate between fragments?
        </item>
        <item>
            What is ANR, When does it occur and How can it be prevented?
        </item>
        <item>
            What role does Dalvik play in Android development?
        </item>
        <item>
            What is the AndroidManifest.xml?
        </item>
        <item>
            What is AIDL and What data types are supported?
        </item>
        <item>
            What is the difference between foreground and visible lifetime?
        </item>
        <item>
            What is the difference between a regular bitmap and a nine-patch image?
        </item>
        <item>
            How many types we can store data in Android Phone, which is better approaches
            in SharedPreferences and SQLite to save small data or large data ?
        </item>
        <item>
            What is SQLite? How does it differ from client-server database management systems?
        </item>
        <item>
            What is DDMS and what can it do?
        </item>
        <item>
            What is a ContentProvider and what is it typically used for?
        </item>
        <item>
            Under what condition could the code sample crash your application? How would you modify the code to avoid this potential problem?
            Explain your answer.
        </item>
        <item>
            Suppose that you are starting a service in an Activity as follows:
            \nIntent service = new Intent(context, MyService.class);
            \nstartService(service);
            \nwhere MyService accesses a remote server via an Internet connection.
            \nIf the Activity is showing an animation that indicates some kind of progress, what issue might you encounter and
            how could you address it?
        </item>
        <item>
            What is the difference between Service, IntentService, Thread and AsyncTask? How is each used?
        </item>
        <item>
            How to run the service even after killing the application in android ?
        </item>
        <item>
            Normally, in the process of carrying out a screen reorientation, the Android platform tears down the foreground activity
            and recreates it, restoring each of the view values in the activity’s layout.
            \nIn an app you’re working on, you notice that a view’s value is not being restored after screen reorientation.
            What could be a likely cause of the problem that you should verify, at a minimum, about that particular view?
        </item>
        <item>
            What is the relationship between the life cycle of an AsyncTask and an Activity?
            What problems can this result in? How can these problems be avoided?
        </item>
        <item>
            What is the difference between Serializable and Parcelable ? Which is best approach in Android ?
        </item>
        <item>
            What are "launch modes"? What are the two mechanisms by which they can be defined? What specific types of
            launch modes are supported?
        </item>
        <item>
            What is a broadcast receiver?
        </item>
        <item>
            When dealing with multiple resources, which one takes precedence?
        </item>

    </string-array>

    <!--Android Technical Answers -->
    <string-array name="androidTechnicalAnswers">
        <!--Why did you become an android developer? what are some of the advantages of the Android platform?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre>You want a developer who really knows how to play to the strengths of your chosen platform.<br />Some key advantages of Android are listed below for your convenience.<br /><br />- <strong>Open Source</strong>: No licenses, no distribution or development fees.<br />- <strong>DVM</strong> (Dalvik Virtual Machine): DVM is a highly optimized virtual machine for mobile devices.<br />- <strong>Platform Diversity</strong>: Since Android is open-source, it has been adopted by a wide range of manufacturers of mobile devices.<br />- <strong>Experience with Java</strong>: Java is the language of choice for Android app development.<br /><br />Those who already have years of experience in Java will feel right at home developing for Android.</pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What are the latest Android versions? The most important Oreo new features?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
<pre>Android Versions with Code names From 2015 which are supported by Google.<br />- October 2015: Marshmallow 6.0 - 6.0.1, API level 23<br />- August 2016: Nougat 7.0 - 7.1.2, API level 24 - 25<br />- August 2017: Oreo 8.0 - 8.1, API level 26 - 27<br />- May 2018: Android P (Beta) - 9, API level 28<br /><br />Noticeable Features:<br /><br />- <strong>Power Saving</strong>:<br />For one, Google has put automatic limits on background app activities in the latest version of Android.<br />This means that the operating system will specifically limit background usage including broadcasts, background services,<br />and location updates. This translates to less energy consumption by apps when you are not actively using them and longer<br />battery life as a result.<br /><br />- <strong>Better and more Secure Apps</strong>:<br />Google is now very active in nudging developers towards optimizing their apps. Google Play Protect is a background service<br />that will quietly analyze the behavior of apps in an effort to detect malware and, if found, automatically remove it from<br />your device and from the Play Store itself (exactly how that part works is still a bit fuzzy right now).<br />Google is also being a bit stricter on developers when it comes to stability and performance.<br />If the app falls in the bottom 25 percent, the dev will get a warning and if there are no improvements,<br />it might result in the app being pulled off the Google Play Store.<br /><br />- <strong>Preventing Boot Loops</strong>:<br />This is a great feature to be introduced in the new Android 8.0 Oreo. Rescue Party is a feature that helps prevent boot loops.<br />Boot loop, if you are unfamiliar with the term, is what happens when the device starts up and restarts immediately over and over.<br />When core systems are not running well, Android will take notice of that and try to return them to their default states.<br />If that doesn\'t work, it will reboot automatically in the Recovery Mode and provide the option of a factory reset as a last<br />ditch effort.<br /><br />- <strong>Wi-Fi Aware</strong>:<br />Compatible smartphones will be able to use Neighbor Awareness Networking and communicate with nearby devices without an<br />internet connection.<br />"Wi-Fi Aware continuously discovers other devices within a user\'s Wi-Fi range prior to association, making it easy to find<br />nearby information and services available that match preferences set by the user. Wi-Fi Aware devices bring users a more<br />interesting, relevant, and productive mobility experience. An individual in a subway station can connect to a person within<br />proximity to play a game, while simultaneously receiving train schedule updates without the need for an internet connection.<br />Co-workers on a lunch break can establish peer-to-peer connections to share photos, while also maintaining a connection to<br />the company network.<br />Wi-Fi Aware is a key enabler of a truly personalized social, local, and mobile experience and works well in crowded environments.<br />Wi-Fi Aware is poised for mass adoption, with native support available in the Android Oreo operating system."<br /><br />- <strong>Google Autofill</strong>:<br />Google resolves this annoyance by bringing Autofill password management to Android. This feature allows you to manage all<br />of your passwords in a single place, and will result in an easier and more secure way to log into your accounts.<br />And the best part is that it syncs across devices, so if you\'ve used Google Autofill while browsing the internet with Chrome,<br />you\'ll have access to all that log in information via your mobile device, too, as long as you\'re using the same Google Account.<br /><br />For developer features, check <a href="https://developer.android.com/about/versions/oreo/android-8.0">Android Developers</a>.</pre>            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What is the Google Android SDK?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
           <pre>The Google Android SDK is a toolset that developers need in order to write apps on Android enabled devices.<br />It contains a graphical interface that emulates an Android driven handheld environment, allowing them to test<br />and debug their codes.</pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What is the Android Architecture?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre>The Android software stack is typically divided into the five main components detailed below.<br />- <strong>Linux Kernel</strong>: The base layer of an application that directly interfaces with the device hardware - this is the level<br />that deals with hardware drivers like the camera, keypad, and display.<br />- <strong>Native Libraries</strong>: Resting on top of the Linux Kernel are a set of open-source libraries,<br />including the SQLite database, libc, and the WebKit browser engine.<br />- <strong>Android Runtime</strong>: The Dalvik Virtual Machine is in the same level as the Native Libraries and allows<br />every Android app to run its own processes.<br />- <strong>Application Framework</strong>: The next layer up provides higher-level services in the form of Java classes to<br />applications on the device. The key services to know are the Activity Manager, Content Providers, Resource Manager,<br />Notifications Manager, and the View System.<br />- <strong>Applications</strong>: The top layer is the Android App itself. This is the level where applications are actually<br />installed, and the one developers are most familiar with.</pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--Describe the Android Framework?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre>The Android Framework is an important aspect of the Android Architecture. Here you can find all the classes and methods<br />that developers would need in order to write applications on the Android environment.</pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What is AAPT?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
           <pre>AAPT is short for Android Asset Packaging Tool. This tool provides developers with the ability to deal with<br />zip-compatible archives, which includes creating, extracting as well as viewing its contents.<br />So It is the default tool of the Android SDK to pack all classes and resources in an APK file.</pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--Mention Native Android actions?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre>The following non-comprehensive list shows some of the native actions available as static string constants in the Intent class.<br />When creating implicit Intents you can use these actions, called Activity Intents, to start Activities and sub-Activities<br />within your own applications.<br /><br />- <strong>action_answer</strong>: Opens an Activity that handles incoming calls. Currently this is handled by the native in-call screen.<br /><br />- <strong>action_call</strong>: Brings up a phone dialer and immediately initiates a call using the number supplied in the Intent URI.<br />Generally it\'s considered better form to use action_dial if possible.<br /><br />- <strong>action_delete</strong>: Starts an Activity that lets you delete the data specified at the Intent\'s data URI.<br /><br />- <strong>action_dial</strong>: Brings up a dialer application with the number to dial pre-populated from the Intent URI.<br />By default this is handled by the native Android phone dialer. The dialer can normalize most number schemas:<br />for example, <em>tel:555-1234</em> and <em>tel:(212) 555 1212</em> are both valid numbers.<br /><br />- <strong>action_edit</strong>: Requests an Activity that can edit the data at the specified Intent URI.<br /><br />- <strong>action_insert</strong>: Opens an Activity capable of inserting new items into the Cursor specified in the Intent URI.<br />When called as a sub-Activity it should return a URI to the newly inserted item.<br /><br />- <strong>action_pick</strong>: Launches a sub-Activity that lets you pick an item from the Content Provider specified by the Intent URI.<br />When closed it should return a URI to the item that was picked. The Activity launched depends on the data being picked:<br />for example, passing <em>content://contacts/people</em> will invoke the native contacts list.<br /><br />- <strong>action_search</strong>: Launches the Activity used for performing a search. Supply the search term as a string in the Intent\'s<br />extras using thffiearchManager.QUERY key.<br /><br />- <strong>action_sendto</strong>: Launches an Activity to send a message to the contact specified by the Intent URI.<br /><br />- <strong>action_send</strong>: Launches an Activity that sends the data specified in the Intent. The recipient contact needs to be<br />selected by the resolved Activity. Use setType to set the MIME type of the transmitted data.</pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--Describe Activities.-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
           <pre>An activity is a single, focused thing that the user can do. Almost all activities interact with the user, so the Activity class<br />takes care of creating a window for you in which you can place your UI with setContentView(View).<br />While activities are often presented to the user as full-screen windows, they can also be used in other ways:<br />as floating windows (via a theme with windowIsFloating set) or embedded inside of another activity (using ActivityGroup).<br />There are two methods almost all subclasses of Activity will implement:<br /><br />- onCreate(Bundle) is where you initialize your activity.<br />Most importantly, here you will usually call setContentView(int) with a layout resource defining your UI, and using<br /><br />- onPause() is where you deal with the user leaving your activity. Most importantly,<br />any changes made by the user should at this point be committed (usually to the ContentProvider holding the data).<br /><br />To be of use with Context.startActivity(), all activity classes must have a corresponding &lt;activity&gt;;<br />declaration in their package\'s AndroidManifest.xml.</pre>
             </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What do you know about Material Design-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre>Material design is a comprehensive guide for visual, motion, and interaction design across platforms and devices.<br />To use material design in Android apps, follow the guidelines and<br />use the new components and styles available in the material design support library.<br /><br />Android provides the following features to help you build material design apps:<br /><br />- A material design app theme to style all your UI widgets<br />- Widgets for complex views such as lists and cards<br />- New APIs for custom shadows and animations</pre>
             </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What's the difference between Dialog and AlertDialog Android?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre>Dialogs in Android are used to shows alerts for making decisions or to edit a single value.<br />But there are some differences between an AlertDialog and a BasicDialog.<br />In an AlertDialog you always want to show a message and at least one Button for user interaction.<br />In a BasicDialog you have a custom view to a TextView or something more complex.<br /><br />Furthermore AlertDialog is derived from Dialog and provides additional functionality in terms of<br />Dialog Title, Icon, 3 lines of message you can display to the user.<br />It also provides for lists, checkboxes etc. So you can decide which one to choose yourself.</pre>
             </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What’s the difference between FrameLayout, GridLayout, ConstraintLayout, LinearLayout and RelativeLayout
        and which has better performance?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre>- <strong>ConstraintLayout</strong>: ConstraintLayout allows you to create large and complex layouts with a flat view hierarchy<br />(no nested view groups). It\'s similar to RelativeLayout in that all views are laid out according to relationships<br />between sibling views and the parent layout, but it\'s more flexible than RelativeLayout and easier to use with Android<br />Studio\'s Layout Editor.<br />All the power of ConstraintLayout is available directly from the Layout Editor\'s visual tools, because the layout API<br />and the Layout Editor were specially built for each other. So you can build your layout with ConstraintLayout entirely by<br />drag-and-dropping instead of editing the XML.<br /><br />- <strong>FrameLayout</strong>: FrameLayout is designed to block out an area on the screen to display a single item. Generally,<br />FrameLayout should be used to hold a single child view, because it can be difficult to organize child views in a way that\'s<br />scalable to different screen sizes without the children overlapping each other. You can, however, add multiple children to a<br />FrameLayout and control their position within the FrameLayout by assigning gravity to each child, using the android:layout_gravity<br />attribute.<br />Child views are drawn in a stack, with the most recently added child on top. The size of the FrameLayout is the size of<br />its largest child (plus padding), visible or not (if the FrameLayout\'s parent permits). Views that are GONE are used for<br />sizing only if setConsiderGoneChildrenWhenMeasuring() is set to true.<br /><br />- <strong>GridLayout</strong>: A layout that places its children in a rectangular grid.<br />The grid is composed of a set of infinitely thin lines that separate the viewing area into cells.<br />Throughout the API, grid lines are referenced by grid indices. A grid with N columns has N + 1 grid indices that run<br />from 0 through N inclusive. Regardless of how GridLayout is configured, grid index 0 is fixed to the leading edge of the<br />container and grid index N is fixed to its trailing edge (after padding is taken into account).<br /><br />- <strong>LinearLayout</strong>: LinearLayout is a view group that aligns all children in a single direction,<br />vertically or horizontally. You can specify the layout direction with the android:orientation attribute.<br />All children of a LinearLayout are stacked one after the other, so a vertical list will only have one child per row,<br />no matter how wide they are, and a horizontal list will only be one row high (the height of the tallest child, plus padding).<br />A LinearLayout respects margins between children and the gravity (right, center, or left alignment) of each child.<br /><br />- <strong>RelativeLayout</strong>: RelativeLayout is a view group that displays child views in relative positions.<br />The position of each view can be specified as relative to sibling elements (such as to the left-of or below another view)<br />or in positions relative to the parent RelativeLayout area (such as aligned to the bottom, left or center).<br />A RelativeLayout is a very powerful utility for designing a user interface because it can eliminate nested view groups<br />and keep your layout hierarchy flat, which improves performance. If you find yourself using several nested LinearLayout<br />groups, you may be able to replace them with a single RelativeLayout.<br /><br /><strong>Conclusion</strong>: A detailed performance testing is made in <a href="https://android-developers.googleblog.com/2017/08/understanding-performance-benefits-of.html">Android Developers</a>.</pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What are intents and Describe three common use cases for using an Intent.-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre>An Intent is a messaging object you can use to request an action from another app component.<br />Although intents facilitate communication between components in several ways, there are three fundamental use cases:<br /><br />- <strong>Starting an Activity</strong>:<br />An Activity represents a single screen in an app. You can start a new instance of an<br />Activity by passing an Intent to startActivity(). The Intent describes the activity to start and carries any necessary data.<br />\nIf you want to receive a result from the activity when it finishes, call startActivityForResult(). Your activity receives the result as a separate Intent object in your activity\'s onActivityResult() callback. For more information, see the Activities guide.<br /><br />- <strong>Starting a Service</strong>:<br />A Service is a component that performs operations in the background without a user interface.<br />With Android 5.0 (API level 21) and later, you can start a service with JobScheduler.<br />For more information about JobScheduler, see its API-reference documentation.<br />For versions earlier than Android 5.0 (API level 21), you can start a service by using methods of the Service class.<br />You can start a service to perform a one-time operation (such as downloading a file) by passing an Intent to startService().<br />The Intent describes the service to start and carries any necessary data.<br />If the service is designed with a client-server interface, you can bind to the service from another component<br />by passing an Intent to bindService(). For more information, see the Services guide.<br /><br />- <strong>Delivering a Broadcast</strong>:<br />A broadcast is a message that any app can receive. The system delivers various broadcasts for system events,<br />such as when the system boots up or the device starts charging. You can deliver a broadcast to other apps by passing<br />an Intent to sendBroadcast() or sendOrderedBroadcast().<br /><br />There are two types of <strong>intents</strong>:<br /><br />-<strong> Explicit intents</strong> specify which application will satisfy the intent, by supplying either the target app\'s package name<br />or a fully-qualified component class name. You\'ll typically use an explicit intent to start a component in your own app,<br />because you know the class name of the activity or service you want to start. For example, you might start a new activity<br />within your app in response to a user action, or start a service to download a file in the background.<br /><br />- <strong>Implicit intents</strong> do not name a specific component, but instead declare a general action to perform, which allows a<br />component from another app to handle it. For example, if you want to show the user a location on a map, you can use an<br />implicit intent to request that another capable app show a specified location on a map.</pre>
             </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--Where should you use implicit and explicit intent? -->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre>- You\'ll typically use an explicit intent to start a component in your own app,<br />because you know the class name of the activity or service you want to start. For example, you might start a new activity<br />within your app in response to a user action, or start a service to download a file in the background.<br /><br />- Implicit intents do not name a specific component, but instead declare a general action to perform, which allows a<br />component from another app to handle it. For example, if you want to show the user a location on a map, you can use an<br />implicit intent to request that another capable app show a specified location on a map.</pre>
             </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What is the function of an intentfilter?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre>Specifies the types of intents that an activity, service, or broadcast receiver can respond to.<br />An intent filter declares the capabilities of its parent component &mdash; what an activity or service<br />can do and what types of broadcasts a receiver can handle. It opens the component to receiving intents<br />of the advertised type, while filtering out those that are not meaningful for the component.<br /><br />Most of the contents of the filter are described by its &lt;action&gt;, &lt;category&gt;, and &lt;data&gt; subelements.</pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What are containers?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre>Containers, as the name itself implies, holds objects and widgets together, depending on which specific items are needed and<br />in what particular arrangement that is wanted. Containers may hold labels, fields, buttons, or even child containers, as examples.</pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What do you think are some disadvantages of Android?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre>Given that Android is an open-source platform, and the fact that different Android operating systems have been released<br />on different mobile devices, there\'s no clear cut policy to how applications can adapt with various OS versions and upgrades.<br />One app that runs on this particular version of Android OS may or may not run on another version. Another disadvantage is<br />that since mobile devices such as phones and tabs come in different sizes and forms, it poses a challenge for developers to<br />create apps that can adjust correctly to the right screen size and other varying features and specs.</pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What are the four essential states of an activity?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre><strong>Active</strong> &ndash; if the activity is at the foreground<br /><strong>Paused</strong> &ndash; if the activity is at the background and still visible<br /><strong>Stopped</strong> &ndash; if the activity is not visible and therefore is hidden or obscured by another activity<br /><strong>Destroyed</strong> &ndash; when the activity process is killed or completed terminated</pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What are the seven lifecycle methods of Android activity and what is their purpose?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre>The seven lifecycle methods of Android activity are onCreate(), onStart(), onRestart(), onResume(), onPause(), onStop(),<br />and onDestroy(). Their purpose is to help structure your code around how you want an activity to perform throughout its<br />lifecycle on the device.<br /><br />For example, onCreate() is where you would perform your static setup, from creating views to binding data to lists.<br />It is always immediately followed by onStart(), where the app will be made visible to the user.<br /><br />What you\'re looking for in their response is a solid grasp of the lifecycle of an Android app.<br />The functions of these methods are pretty self-explanatory based on their names.</pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--The last callback in the lifecycle of an activity is onDestroy().
        The system calls this method on your activity as the final signal that your activity instance is being completely
        removed from the system memory. Usually, the system will call onPause() and onStop() before calling onDestroy().
        Describe a scenario, though, where onPause() and onStop() would not be invoked.-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre>onPause() and onStop() will not be invoked if finish() is called from within the onCreate() method.<br />This might occur, for example, if you detect an error during onCreate() and call finish() as a result.<br />In such a case, though, any cleanup you expected to be done in onPause() and onStop() will not be executed.<br /><br />Although onDestroy() is the last callback in the lifecycle of an activity, it is worth mentioning that this callback<br />may not always be called and should not be relied upon to destroy resources. It is better have the resources created in<br />onStart() and onResume(), and have them destroyed in onStop() and onPause(), respectively.</pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What is the importance of settings permissions in app development?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre>The purpose of a permission is to protect the privacy of an Android user. Android apps must request permission to access<br />sensitive user data (such as contacts and SMS), as well as certain system features (such as camera and internet).<br />Depending on the feature, the system might grant the permission automatically or might prompt the user to approve the request.</pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--Enumerate the three key loops when monitoring an activity-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre><strong>Entire lifetime</strong> &ndash; activity happens between onCreate and onDestroy.<br /><strong>Visible lifetime</strong> &ndash; activity happens between onStart and onStop.<br /><strong>Foreground lifetime</strong> &ndash; activity happens between onResume and onPause.</pre>             </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What is the difference between a fragment and an activity? Explain the relationship between the two.-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre>An activity is typically a single, focused operation that a user can perform (such as dial a number, take a picture,<br />send an email, view a map, etc.). Yet at the same time, there is nothing that precludes a developer from creating an<br />activity that is arbitrarily complex.<br /><br />Activity implementations can optionally make use of the Fragment class for purposes such as producing more modular code,<br />building more sophisticated user interfaces for larger screens, helping scale applications between small and large screens,<br />and so on. Multiple fragments can be combined within a single activity and, conversely, the same fragment can often be reused<br />across multiple activities. This structure is largely intended to foster code reuse and facilitate economies of scale.<br /><br />A fragment is essentially a modular section of an activity, with its own lifecycle and input events, and which can be<br />added or removed at will. It is important to remember, though, that a fragment\'s lifecycle is directly affected by its host<br />activity\'s lifecycle; i.e., when the activity is paused, so are all fragments in it, and when the activity is destroyed,<br />so are all of its fragments.</pre>
             </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--Which method is called only once in a fragment life cycle?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
        <pre>- <strong>onAttached()</strong>;</pre>
        </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--When is the onStop() method invoked?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
           <pre>A call to onStop method happens when an activity is no longer visible to the user, either because another activity has<br />taken over or if in front of that activity.</pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What are the different states wherein a process is based?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre>There are 4 possible states:<br />&ndash; <strong>foreground activity</strong><br />&ndash; <strong>visible activity</strong><br />&ndash; <strong>background activity</strong><br />&ndash; <strong>empty process</strong></pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--How to communicate between fragments?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre>In order to reuse the Fragment UI components, you should build each as a completely self-contained, modular component that<br />defines its own layout and behavior. Once you have defined these reusable Fragments, you can associate them with an Activity<br />and connect them with the application logic to realize the overall composite UI.<br /><br />Often you will want one Fragment to communicate with another, for example to change the content based on a user event.<br />All Fragment-to-Fragment communication is done either through a shared ViewModel or through the associated Activity.<br />Two Fragments should never communicate directly.<br /><br />To allow a Fragment to communicate up to its Activity, you can define an interface in the Fragment class and implement it<br />within the Activity. The Fragment captures the interface implementation during its onAttach() lifecycle method and can<br />then call the Interface methods in order to communicate with the Activity.<br /><br /><strong>Example</strong>:<strong> Define an Interface;</strong><br /><br /><em>public class HeadlinesFragment extends ListFragment {</em><br /><em>OnHeadlineSelectedListener mCallback;</em><br /><br /><em>// Container Activity must implement this interface</em><br /><br /><em>public interface OnHeadlineSelectedListener {</em><br /><em>public void onArticleSelected(int position);</em><br /><em>    }</em><br /><br /><em>@Override</em><br /><em>public void onAttach(Activity activity) {</em><br /><em>      super.onAttach(activity);</em><br /><br /><em>// This makes sure that the container activity has implemented</em><br /><em>// the callback interface. If not, it throws an exception</em><br /><em>try {</em><br /><em>    mCallback = (OnHeadlineSelectedListener) activity;</em><br /><em>  } catch (ClassCastException e) {</em><br /><em>throw new ClassCastException(activity.toString()</em><br /><em>+ " must implement OnHeadlineSelectedListener");</em><br /><em>}</em><br /><em>}</em><br /><br /><em>          ...</em><br /><em>}</em><br /><br />Now the fragment can deliver messages to the activity by calling the onArticleSelected() method<br />(or other methods in the interface) using the mCallback instance of the OnHeadlineSelectedListener interface.<br /><br />For example, the following method in the fragment is called when the user clicks on a list item. The fragment uses the<br />callback interface to deliver the event to the parent activity.<br /><br /><strong>Implement The Interface;</strong><br />In order to receive event callbacks from the fragment, the activity that hosts it must implement<br />the interface defined in the fragment class.<br /><br /><em>public static class MainActivity extends Activity</em><br /><em>implements HeadlinesFragment.OnHeadlineSelectedListener{</em><br /><em> ...</em><br /><br /><em>public void onArticleSelected(int position) {</em><br /><em> // The user selected the headline of an article from the HeadlinesFragment</em><br /><em> // Do something here to display that article</em><br /><em>}</em><br /><em>}</em><br /><br /><strong>Deliver a Message to a Fragment;</strong><br /><br />The host activity can deliver messages to a fragment by capturing the Fragment instance with findFragmentById(),<br />then directly call the fragment\'s public methods.<br />For instance, imagine that the activity shown above may contain another fragment that\'s used to display the item specified<br />by the data returned in the above callback method. In this case, the activity can pass the information received in the<br />callback method to the other fragment that will display the item:<br /><br /><em>public static class MainActivity extends Activity</em><br /><em>implements HeadlinesFragment.OnHeadlineSelectedListener{</em><br /><em> ...</em><br /><br /><em>public void onArticleSelected(int position) {</em><br /><em>    // The user selected the headline of an article from the HeadlinesFragment</em><br /><em>    // Do something here to display that article</em><br /><br /><em>       ArticleFragment articleFrag = (ArticleFragment)</em><br /><em>       getSupportFragmentManager().findFragmentById(R.id.article_fragment);</em><br /><br /><em>          if (articleFrag != null) {</em><br /><em>       // If article frag is available, we\'re in two-pane layout...</em><br /><br /><em>          // Call a method in the ArticleFragment to update its content</em><br /><em>       articleFrag.updateArticleView(position);</em><br /><em>    } else {</em><br /><em> // Otherwise, we\'re in the one-pane layout and must swap frags...</em><br /><br /><em>          // Create fragment and give it an argument for the selected article</em><br /><em> ArticleFragment newFragment = new ArticleFragment();</em><br /><em> Bundle args = new Bundle();</em><br /><em> args.putInt(ArticleFragment.ARG_POSITION, position);</em><br /><em> newFragment.setArguments(args);</em><br /><br /><em> FragmentTransaction transaction = getSupportFragmentManager().beginTransaction();</em><br /><br /><em>       // Replace whatever is in the fragment_container view with this fragment,</em><br /><em>       // and add the transaction to the back stack so the user can navigate back</em><br /><em>    transaction.replace(R.id.fragment_container, newFragment);</em><br /><em> transaction.addToBackStack(null);</em><br /><br /><em>          // Commit the transaction</em><br /><em>       transaction.commit();</em><br /><em>    }</em><br /><em> }</em><br /><em> }</em></pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What is ANR, when does it occur and how can it be prevented?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre>\'ANR\' in Android is \'Application Not Responding.\' It means when the user is interacting with the activity,<br />and the activity is in the onResume() method, a dialog appears displaying "application not responding."<br /><br />It happens because we start a heavy and long running task like downloading data in the main UI thread.<br />To avoid ANR, an app should perform lengthy database or networking operations in separate threads.<br />For background task-intensive apps, you can alleviate pressure from the UI thread by using the IntentService.<br />Other solution can be to perform your heavy tasks in the background using Async Task class.<br /><br />In general, it helps to always define time-outs for all your web service calls and to remain ever vigilant<br />for infinite loops in complex calculations.</pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What role does Dalvik play in Android development?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            Dalvik serves as a virtual machine, and it is where every Android application runs.
            Through Dalvik, a device is able to execute multiple virtual machines efficiently through better memory management.
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What is the AndroidManifest.xml?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre>Every app project must have an AndroidManifest.xml file (with precisely that name) at the root of the project source set.<br />The manifest file describes essential information about your app to the Android build tools, the Android operating system,<br />and Google Play.<br /><br />Among many other things, the manifest file is required to declare the following:<br /><br />- The app\'s package name, which usually matches your code\'s namespace. The Android build tools use this to determine<br />the location of code entities when building your project. When packaging the app, the build tools replace this value with the<br />application ID from the Gradle build files, which is used as the unique app identifier on the system and on Google Play.<br /><br />- The components of the app, which include all activities, services, broadcast receivers, and content providers.<br />Each component must define basic properties such as the name of its Kotlin or Java class. It can also declare capabilities<br />such as which device configurations it can handle, and intent filters that describe how the component can be started.<br /><br />- The permissions that the app needs in order to access protected parts of the system or other apps.<br />It also declares any permissions that other apps must have if they want to access content from this app.<br /><br />- The hardware and software features the app requires, which affects which devices can install the app from<br />Google Play.</pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What is AIDL and What data types are supported by AIDL?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre>AIDL, or Android Interface Definition Language, handles the interface requirements between a client and a service<br />so both can communicate at the same level through interprocess communication or IPC. This process involves breaking<br />down objects into primitives that Android can understand. This part is required simply because a process cannot<br />access the memory of the other process.<br /><br />AIDL has support for the following data types:<br />- string<br />- charSequence<br />- List<br />- Map<br />- all native Java data types like int,long, char and Boolean</pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What is the difference between foreground and visible lifetime?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
           <pre><strong>The Visible Lifetime</strong>: Although this is termed the "visible lifetime", the app may not be directly visible and interacting<br />with the user at any one time if it is not in the foreground. The feature that distinguishes this lifetime is that,<br />even if not in the foreground, the app maintains resources such that it can instantaneously return to the foreground.<br /><br /><strong>The Foreground Lifetime</strong>: During foreground lifetime the activity is in front of all other activities and interacting<br />with the user.<br /><br />So If you display an Activity on the screen and the user is interacting with it, it is both in the foreground and visible.<br />Between onResume() and onPause() called foreground lifetime.<br /><br />If you start another Activity, which is transparent and shows a dialog box over the previous Activity, then the new Activity<br />(the dialog box) is in the foreground and the old Activity is not in the foreground but still visible.<br />Between onStart() and onStop() called visible lifetime.</pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What is the difference between a regular bitmap and a nine-patch image?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre>In general, a Nine-patch image allows resizing that can be used as background or other image size requirements for<br />the target device. The Nine-patch refers to the way you can resize the image: 4 corners that are unscaled,<br />4 edges that are scaled in 1 axis, and the middle one that can be scaled into both axes.</pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--How many types we can store data in Android Phone, which is better approaches
        in SharedPreferences and SQLite to save small data or large data ?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre>Android provides several options for you to save your app data. The solution you choose depends on your specific needs,<br />such as how much space your data requires, what kind of data you need to store, and whether the data should be private<br />to your app or accessible to other apps and the user.<br /><br />The different data storage options available on Android:<br /><br />- <strong>Internal file storage</strong>: Store app-private files on the device file system.<br />- <strong>External file storage</strong>: Store files on the shared external file system. This is usually for shared user files, such as photos.<br />- <strong>Shared preferences</strong>: Store private primitive data in key-value pairs.<br />- <strong>Databases</strong>: Store structured data in a private database.<br /><br /><strong>Internal File Storage</strong>:<br /><em>Internal Storage</em><br />By default, files saved to the internal storage are private to your app, and other apps cannot access them<br />(nor can the user, unless they have root access). This makes internal storage a good place for internal app data that the<br />user doesn\'t need to directly access. The system provides a private directory on the file system for each app where you can<br />organize any files your app needs.<br /><br />When the user uninstalls your app, the files saved on the internal storage are removed. Because of this behavior,<br />you should not use internal storage to save anything the user expects to persist independently of your app. For example,<br />if your app allows users to capture photos, the user would expect that they can access those photos even after they<br />uninstall your app. So you should instead save those types of files to the public external storage.<br /><br /><em>Internal cache files</em><br />If you\'d like to keep some data temporarily, rather than store it persistently,<br />you should use the special cache directory to save the data. Each app has a private cache directory specifically for<br />these kinds of files. When the device is low on internal storage space, Android may delete these cache files to recover space.<br />However, you should not rely on the system to clean up these files for you. You should always maintain the cache files yourself<br />and stay within a reasonable limit of space consumed, such as 1MB. When the user uninstalls your app, these files are removed.<br /><br /><strong>External File Storage</strong>:<br />Every Android device supports a shared "external storage" space that you can use to save files. This space is called<br />external because it\'s not a guaranteed to be accessible&mdash;it is a storage space that users can mount to a computer as an<br />external storage device, and it might even be physically removable (such as an SD card). Files saved to the external storage<br />are world-readable and can be modified by the user when they enable USB mass storage to transfer files on a computer.<br /><br />So before you attempt to access a file in external storage in your app, you should check for the availability of the external<br />storage directories as well as the files you are trying to access.<br /><br />Most often, you should use external storage for user data that should be accessible to other apps and saved even if the user<br />uninstalls your app, such as captured photos or downloaded files. The system provides standard public directories for these<br />kinds of files, so the user has one location for all their photos, ringtones, music, and such.<br /><br /><strong>Shared Preferences</strong>:<br />If you don\'t need to store a lot of data and it doesn\'t require structure, you should use SharedPreferences.<br />The SharedPreferences APIs allow you to read and write persistent key-value pairs of primitive data types:<br />booleans, floats, ints, longs, and strings.<br /><br />The key-value pairs are written to XML files that persist across user sessions, even if your app is killed. You can<br />manually specify a name for the file or use per-activity files to save your data.<br /><br />The API name "shared preferences" is a bit misleading because the API is not strictly for saving "user preferences,"<br />such as what ringtone a user has chosen. You can use SharedPreferences to save any kind of simple data, such as the user\'s<br />high score.<br /><br /><strong>Databases</strong>:<br />Android provides full support for SQLite databases. Any database you create is accessible only by your app.<br /><br />The SQLite APIs are fairly low-level and require a great deal of time and effort to use. For example:<br /><br />There is no compile-time verification of raw SQL queries.<br />As your schema changes, you need to update the affected SQL queries manually. This process can be time consuming and error prone.<br />You need to write lots of boilerplate code to convert between SQL queries and Java data objects.<br /><br />The Room persistence library takes care of these concerns for you while providing an abstraction layer over SQLite.<br />Therefore the Room library provides an object-mapping abstraction layer that allows fluent database access while harnessing<br />the full power of SQLite.</pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What is SQLite? How does it differ from client-server database management systems?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre>SQLite is the open-source relational database of choice for Android applications. The SQLite engine is serverless,<br />transactional, and self-contained. Instead of the typical client-server relationship of most database management systems,<br />the SQLite engine is integrally linked with the application. The library can also be called dynamically, and makes use<br />of simple function calls that reduce latency in database access.</pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What is DDMS and what can it do?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre>DDMS is short for Dalvik Debug Monitor Server. It ships natively with Android and contains a number of useful debugging<br />features including:<br />- location data spoofing<br />- port-forwarding<br />- network traffic tracking<br />- incoming call/SMS spoofing<br />- thread and heap information<br />- screen capture<br />- and the ability to simulate network state, speed and latency.</pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What is a ContentProvider and what is it typically used for?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre>A ContentProvider manages access to a structured set of data. It encapsulates the data and provide mechanisms for defining<br />data security. ContentProvider is the standard interface that connects data in one process with code running in another process.</pre>
             </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--Under what condition could the code sample below crash your application? How would you modify the code to avoid this -->
        <!--potential problem? Explain your answer.-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre><strong>Sample Code</strong>:<br /><em>Intent sendIntent = new Intent();</em><br /><em>sendIntent.setAction(Intent.ACTION_SEND);</em><br /><em>sendIntent.putExtra(Intent.EXTRA_TEXT, textMessage);</em><br /><em>sendIntent.setType(HTTP.PLAIN_TEXT_TYPE); // "text/plain" MIME type</em><br /><em>startActivity(sendIntent);</em><br /><br />An implicit intent specifies an action that can invoke any app on the device able to perform the action.<br />Using an implicit intent is useful when your app cannot perform the action, but other apps probably can.<br />If there is more than one application registered that can handle this request, the user will be prompted<br />to select which one to use.<br /><br />However, it is possible that there are no applications that can handle your intent. In this case, your application will<br />crash when you invoke startActivity(). To avoid this, before calling startActivity() you should first verify that there<br />is at least one application registered in the system that can handle the intent. To do this use resolveActivity() on your<br />intent object.<br /><br /><strong>Answer</strong>:<br /><em>// Verify that there are applications registered to handle this intent</em><br /><em>// (resolveActivity returns null if none are registered)</em><br /><em>if (sendIntent.resolveActivity(getPackageManager()) != null) {</em><br /><em>startActivity(sendIntent);</em><br /><em> }</em></pre>
             </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--Suppose that you are starting a service in an Activity as follows:-->
        <!--\nIntent service = new Intent(context, MyService.class);-->
        <!--\nstartService(service);-->
        <!--\nwhere MyService accesses a remote server via an Internet connection.-->
        <!--\nIf the Activity is showing an animation that indicates some kind of progress, what issue might you encounter and-->
        <!--how could you address it?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre>Responses from a remote service via the Internet can often take some time, either due to networking latencies,<br />or load on the remote server, or the amount of time it takes for the remote service to process and respond to the request.<br /><br />As a result, if such a delay occurs, the animation in the activity (and even worse, the entire UI thread) could be<br />blocked and could appear to the user to be "frozen" while the client waits for a response from the service.<br />This is because the service is started on the main application thread (or UI thread) in the Activity.<br /><br />The problem can (and should) be avoided by relegating any such remote requests to a background thread or, when feasible,<br />using an an asynchronous response mechanism.<br /><br /><strong>Note</strong>: Accessing the network from the UI thread throws a runtime exception in newer<br />Android versions which causes the app to crash.</pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What is the difference between Service and IntentService? How is each used?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
           <pre>Service is the base class for Android services that can be extended to create any service. A class that directly extends<br />Service runs on the main thread so it will block the UI (if there is one) and should therefore either be used only for<br />short tasks or should make use of other threads for longer tasks.<br /><br />IntentService is a subclass of Service that handles asynchronous requests (expressed as "Intents") on demand.<br />Clients send requests through startService(Intent) calls. The service is started as needed, handles each Intent<br />in turn using a worker thread, and stops itself when it runs out of work. Writing an IntentService can be quite simple;<br />just extend the IntentService class and override the onHandleIntent(Intent intent) method where you can manage all incoming<br />requests.</pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--How to run the service even after killing the application in Android?      -->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre>The service will still have a chance of being killed by the kernel in a state of low memory if it is low priority. So you have two<br />options:<br /><br />1) Keep it running in the foreground by calling the startForeground() method.<br /><br />2) Restart the service if it gets killed. Here is a part of the example from the docs where they talk about restarting the<br />service after it is killed:<br /><br /><em>public int onStartCommand(Intent intent, int flags, int startId) {</em><br /><em>Toast.makeText(this, "service starting", Toast.LENGTH_SHORT).show();</em><br /><br /><em>// For each start request, send a message to start a job and deliver the</em><br /><em>// start ID so we know which request we\'re stopping when we finish the job</em><br /><em>Message msg = mServiceHandler.obtainMessage();</em><br /><em>msg.arg1 = startId;</em><br /><em>mServiceHandler.sendMessage(msg);</em><br /><br /><em>// If we get killed, after returning from here, restart</em><br /><em>return START_STICKY;</em><br /><em>}</em></pre>
             </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--Normally, in the process of carrying out a screen reorientation, the Android platform tears down the foreground activity-->
        <!--and recreates it, restoring each of the view values in the activity’s layout.-->
        <!--\nIn an app you’re working on, you notice that a view’s value is not being restored after screen reorientation.-->
        <!--What could be a likely cause of the problem that you should verify, at a minimum, about that particular view?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre>You should verify that it has a valid id. In order for the Android system to restore the state of the views in your activity,<br />each view must have a unique ID, supplied by the android:id attribute.<br /><br />\Complete guide about the concept is on <a href="https://developer.android.com/guide/components/activities/activity-lifecycle#java">Android Developers</a>.</pre>
             </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What is the relationship between the life cycle of an AsyncTask and an Activity? What problems can this result in? How can -->
        <!--these problems be avoided?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
           <pre>An AsyncTask is not tied to the life cycle of the Activity that contains it. So, for example, if you start an AsyncTask inside<br />an Activity and the user rotates the device, the Activity will be destroyed (and a new Activity instance will be created) but the<br />AsyncTask will not die but instead goes on living until it completes.<br /><br />Then, when the AsyncTask does complete, rather than updating the UI of the new Activity, it updates the former instance<br />of the Activity (i.e., the one in which it was created but that is not displayed anymore!).<br />This can lead to an Exception (of the type java.lang.IllegalArgumentException: View not attached to window manager if you use,<br />for instance, findViewById to retrieve a view inside the Activity).<br /><br />There\'s also the potential for this to result in a memory leak since the AsyncTask maintains a reference to the Activity,<br />which prevents the Activity from being garbage collected as long as the AsyncTask remains alive.<br /><br />For these reasons, using AsyncTasks for long-running background tasks is generally a bad idea.<br />Rather, for long-running background tasks, a different mechanism (such as a service) should be employed.</pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What is difference between Serializable and Parcelable ? Which is best approach in Android ?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
          <pre>Serializable is a standard Java interface. You simply mark a class Serializable by implementing the interface, and<br />Java will automatically serialize it in certain situations.<br /><br />Parcelable is an Android specific interface where you implement the serialization yourself.<br />It was created to be far more efficient than Serializable, and to get around some problems with the default<br />Java serialization scheme.</pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What are launch modes? What are the two mechanisms by which they can be defined? What specific types of launch modes are supported?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
            <pre>A "launch mode" is the way in which a new instance of an activity is to be associated with the current task.<br /><br />Launch modes may be defined using one of two mechanisms:<br /><br />1- <strong>Manifest file</strong>. When declaring an activity in a manifest file, you can specify how the activity should associate with tasks<br />when it starts. Supported values include:<br /><br />- <strong>standard</strong> (default). Multiple instances of the activity class can be instantiated and multiple instances can be added<br />to the same task or different tasks. This is the common mode for most of the activities.<br />- <strong>singleTop</strong>. The difference from standard is, if an instance of the activity already exists at the top of the<br />current task and the system routes the intent to this activity, no new instance will be created because it will fire off an<br />onNewIntent() method instead of creating a new object.<br />- <strong>singleTask</strong>. A new task will always be created and a new instance will be pushed to the task as the root.<br />However, if any activity instance exists in any tasks, the system routes the intent to that activity instance through<br />the onNewIntent() method call. In this mode, activity instances can be pushed to the same task. This mode is useful<br />for activities that act as the entry points.<br />- <strong>singleInstance</strong>. Same as singleTask, except that the no activities instance can be pushed into the same<br />task of the singleInstance\'s. Accordingly, the activity with launch mode is always in a single activity instance task.<br />This is a very specialized mode and should only be used in applications that are implemented entirely as one activity.<br /><br />2- <strong>Intent flags</strong>. Calls to startActivity() can include a flag in the Intent that declares if and how the new activity should be associated with the current task. Supported values include:<br /><br />- <strong>FLAG_ACTIVITY_NEW_TASK</strong>. Same as singleTask value in Manifest file (see above).<br />- <strong>FLAG_ACTIVITY_SINGLE_TOP</strong>. Same as singleTop value in Manifest file (see above).<br />- <strong>FLAG_ACTIVITY_CLEAR_TOP</strong>. If the activity being started is already running in the current task,<br />then instead of launching a new instance of that activity, all of the other activities on top of it are destroyed<br />and this intent is delivered to the resumed instance of the activity (now on top), through onNewIntent().<br />There is no corresponding value in the Manifest file that produces this behavior.</pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--What is a broadcast receiver?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
           <pre>Broadcast Receivers simply respond to broadcast messages from other applications or from the system itself.<br />These messages are sometimes called events or intents. For example, applications can also initiate broadcasts to<br />let other applications know that some data has been downloaded to the device and is available for them to use,<br />so this is broadcast receiver who will intercept this communication and will initiate appropriate action.</pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
        <!--When dealing with multiple resources, which one takes precedence?-->
        <item>
            <![CDATA[<html><pre style="text-align:center">
           <pre>Assuming that all of these multiple resources are able to match the configuration of a device, the \'locale\' qualifier<br />almost always takes the highest precedence over the others.</pre>
            </pre></html>
            ]]>
        </item>
    </string-array>

    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>


</resources>
