<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="cvTopics">
        <item>
            CV(Curriculum Vitae) or Resume?
        </item>
        <item>
            Tailor and Format CV
        </item>
        <item>
            Action Verbs/Power Words
        </item>
        <item>
            Key Points to Include
        </item>
        <item>
            The Header
        </item>
        <item>
            Summary
        </item>
        <item>
            Educational History
        </item>
        <item>
            Work Experience
        </item>
        <item>
            Any Hard/Soft and Transferable skills
        </item>
        <item>
            Awards and honours
        </item>
        <item>
            Any published work
        </item>
        <item>
            Interests/Hobbies
        </item>
        <item>
            References
        </item>
        <item>
            The Do\'s and Don\'t\'s
        </item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="cvTopicsTips">
        <!--Cv or Resume-->
        <item>
            There are three major differences between CVs and resumes are the length, the purpose and the layout.
            A resume is a brief summary of your skills and experience over one or two pages, a CV is more detailed
            and can stretch well beyond two pages. The resume will be tailored to each position whereas the CV
            will stay put and any changes will be in the cover letter.

            \n\nA CV has a clear chronological order listing the whole career of the individual whereas a resume\'s
            information can be shuffled around to best suit the applicant. I would say the main difference between a resume and
            a CV is that a CV is intended to be a full record of your career history and a resume is a brief, targeted list
            of skills and achievements.

            \n\nA resume is the preferred application document in the US and Canada. Americans and Canadians would only use a
            CV when applying for a job abroad or if searching for an academic or research oriented position.

            \n\nIn the UK, Ireland and New Zealand, a CV is used in all contexts and resumes aren\'t used at all.
            The CV prevails in mainland Europe and there is even a European Union CV format available for download.

            \n\nIn Germany, the CV is more commonly known as a Lebenslauf (true to the latin origins) and is only one of many application
            document the poor German job seekers must produce to get an interview.

            \n\nIn Australia, India and South Africa, the terms resume and CV are used interchangeably.
            The term resume is used more for jobs in the private sector and CV is more commonplace when applying for public service positions.
        </item>
        <!--Tailor and format CV-->
        <item>
            It takes a recruiter less than one minute to scan a programmer resume and to start a short list of eligible candidates
            for an interview. A resume format with dark colors for the heading with a column of content to the right of the article
            is more appealing to the eye than a general resume.

            \n\nThe art of writing a resume is to format the resume using a chronological, functional, or combination format.
            I recommend you think about what to write before you begin because it will need a combination of technical skills
            with qualitative data, interpersonal skills, achievements, volunteer work, or freelance experience to stand out
            from the pile of resumes recruiters often receive. As a recruiter scans your resume,
            it has to tell a story of your past, present, and where you plan to be in the future.

            \n\nAlso, it\'s important to tailor your CV:

            \n\n - Tailoring your Skills
            \n\nSkills are the most important thing to change when you tailor your CV.
            A straightforward way to do this is by looking at the skills desired by the employer in question and listing
            any of the skills you have, how you acquired them and where you’ve put them into practice.

            \n\n - Tailoring your Experience
            \n\nYou can\'t change your employment history, but you can select what employment and experience is included on your CV.
            Although everyone says that you should list your most recent employment on your CV, a better tip would be to list all
            recent and relevant work experience. What is relevant, of course, relies upon the job you’re applying for.
            As mentioned before, relevant experience will be completely different for a bar job compared with an engineering vacancy.

            \n\n - Tailoring your Hobbies
            \n\nIt\'s really not a good idea to stick with "Going to the gym, seeing friends and popular culture"
            as your hobbies on every CV you send. In fact, it’s not a good idea to have those boring, "generic" hobbies on any CV.

            \n\nMake sure your hobbies reflect you as a person and your ability to do the role you are applying for,
            as well as your passion for that industry.

            \n\nFor example, if you’re applying for a creative position, emphasise your love of drawing,
            visiting art galleries or your passion for a particular artist. Going for a role that requires
            a lot of writing? Try focusing on a particular genre of literature that you enjoy, or if you\'re
            going for a role that holds a lot of responsibility, focus on your love for hobbies that include team work (e.g. sports).
        </item>
        <!--Action Verbs/Power words-->
        <item>
            Using action verbs in resume writing is as easy as any other form of writing, so long as you know what to include and
            what to look for. Here are two tests to determine if you are using passive voice in your resume writing:

            \n\n 1 - Verb Test: Look for helping verbs, especially forms of the verb “to be.”

            \n\n 2 - "By You" Test: Can you insert the phrase "by you" after the verb? Does the sentence still make grammatical sense?
            If yes, this signifies passive voice.

            \n\nScan the resume for these warning signs and replace passive resume writing with more active verbs and sentences.
            Here are a few examples of passive resume sentences:

            \n\n 1 - A 20 percent revenue growth was realized in our department over two years.

            \n\n 2 - A promotion to supervisor was awarded to me after only one year of service.

            \n\n 3 - Responsibility was recognized as one of my strengths.

            \n\nHere are the same examples rewritten using active voice:

            \n\n 1 - My team realized 20 percent revenue growth over two years.

            \n\n 2 - After only one year, I earned a promotion to supervisor.

            \n\n 3 - Recognized for responsibility and proactive decisions.

            \n\nThe only time when passive voice is appropriate is when you want to draw more attention to results instead of yourself.
            This is very rare, and you should focus on your achievements rather than your company\'s results.

            \n\nMake your resume shine with achievements
            \nAnother action-word strategy is to use "achieving" language rather than "doing" language.
            How do you determine if the sentence is doing or achieving? Ask yourself three simple questions:

            \n\n 1 - Can anyone perform this function?

            \n\n 2 - Is this the standard, run-of-the-mill description?

            \n\n 3 - Did any results come from this action?

            \n\nIf your answers are yes, yes, and no, you are listing descriptions that only show what you can do.
            What you want instead is to show what you have achieved.

            \n\nHere are a few examples of "doing" sentences and how to convert them into "achieving" sentences:

            \n\n&#8226; Doing: Responsible for inventory control and ordering products.

            \n\n&#8226; Achieving: Optimize inventory by monitoring for product shortages and ensuring efficient service usage.

            \n\n&#8226; Doing: Help company sell more products and gain revenue.

            \n\n&#8226; Achieving: Increase profit margins by creating effective sales plans and implementing strategies to solidify
            client retention.

            \n\nUsing action verbs and active voice makes all the difference in your resume, so it\'s worth the extra effort.
            Show the employer what you can bring to the table by listing past achievements and notable contributions and you\'ll
            increase your chance of getting an interview.
        </item>
        <!--key points to include-->
        <item>
            Whether a potential employer asks to see your curriculum vitae, CV or resume, they\'re looking for one thing –
            a document that proves why you\'re the ideal candidate to invest their time and money in. Essentially it\'s
            a sales brochure, pinpointing the interesting USPs (unique selling points) that make you stand out from the crowd.

            \nThere\'s no universally accepted format, but your CV should cover these elements:

            \n\n&#8226; Your Details in the Header Section.
            \n\n&#8226; A Brief Bio
            \n\n&#8226; Work Experience
            \n\n&#8226; Educational History
            \n\n&#8226; Skills
            \n\n&#8226; Interests
            \n\n&#8226; References
        </item>
        <!--the header-->
        <item>

        </item>
        <!--summary-->
        <item>

        </item>
        <!--educational history-->
        <item>

        </item>
        <!--Work experience-->
        <item>

        </item>
        <!--Any hard/Soft and Transferable Skills-->
        <item>

        </item>
        <!--Awards and Honours-->
        <item>

        </item>
        <!--Any published work-->
        <item>

        </item>
        <!--Interests/Hobbies-->
        <item>

        </item>
        <!--References-->
        <item>

        </item>
        <!--The do's and don't's-->
        <item>
<!--https://www.myworldofwork.co.uk/getting-job/building-cv-->
        </item>

    </string-array>

</resources>