<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string-array name="interviewTopic">
        <item>
            Before the interview.
        </item>
        <item>
            What to bring to an interview?
        </item>
        <item>
            What to wear to an interview?
        </item>
        <item>
            The general structure of the interview.
        </item>
        <item>
            During the interview.
        </item>
        <item>
            What Interviewers Are Really Looking For?
        </item>
        <item>
            What questions to ask?
        </item>
        <item>
            After the interview.
        </item>
        <item>
            How to negotiate Salary?
        </item>
        <item>
            The Do\'s and Don\'ts
        </item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="interviewTopicTips">
        <!--Before the interview-->
        <item>
            The key to effective interviewing is to project confidence, stay positive, and be able to share examples of your
            workplace skills and your qualifications for the job. Take the time to work on your interview skills so that you
            can develop effective interview strategies to use in all of your interviews. It is a good idea to focus on your
            communication skills in particular, so you can speak clearly and concisely about the assets you can offer the employer.

            \n\n - Practice and Prepare:
            \nReview the typical job interview questions employers ask, and practice your answers. Strong answers are those that are
            specific but concise, drawing on concrete examples that highlight your skills and back up your resume.
            Your answers should also emphasize the skills that are most important to the employer and relevant to the position.
            Be sure to review the job listing, make a list of the requirements, and match them to your experience.
            \nNote that even the most well-prepared response will fall short if it does not answer the exact question
            you are being asked. While it’s important to familiarize yourself with best answers, it’s equally important
            to listen carefully during your interview in order to ensure your responses give the interviewer the
            information they are looking for.

            \n\n - Develop a Connection with the Interviewer
            \nIn addition to indicating what you know about the company, you should also try to develop a connection with your
            interviewer. Know the interviewer\'s name, and use it during the job interview. (If you're not sure of the name,
            call and ask prior to the interview. And, listen very carefully during introductions. If you\'re prone to forgetting names,
            jot it down somewhere discreet, like in small letters at the bottom of your notepad.)
            \nUltimately, building rapport and making a personal connection with your interviewer can up your chances of getting hired.
            People tend to hire candidates they like and who seem to be a good fit for the company\'s culture.

            \n\n - Research the Company, and Show What You Know
            \nDo your homework and research the employer and the industry, so you are ready for the interview question,
            "What do you know about this company?" If this question is not asked, you should try to demonstrate what
            you know about the company on your own.
            \nYou can do this by tying what you\'ve learned about the company into your responses.
            For example, you might say, "I noticed that when you implemented a new software system last year, your customer satisfaction
            ratings improved dramatically. I am well-versed in the latest technologies from my experience with developing software at ABC,
            and appreciate a company who strives to be a leader in its industry."
            \nYou should be able to find out a lot of information about the company\'s history, mission and values, staff,
            culture, and recent successes on its website. If the company has a blog and a social media presence,
            they can be useful places to look, too.


        </item>
        <!--what to bring to an interview-->
        <item>
            You should start preparing for your interview as soon as a company gets in touch with you about your candidacy.
            Use this comprehensive checklist to make sure you have everything you need to make a good first impression in the job interview.
            This way you\'ll show up prepared 100% of the time.

            \n\n - Folder
            \nWe’re about to outline a significant amount of paperwork you need to bring to a job interview, so first things first, you\'ll
            want to have a folder where you can neatly store these documents.
            \nThis simple act also shows you\'re organized, says Denver-based millennial career coach Jenn DeWall,
            which is a soft skill many employers look for in candidates.

            \n\n - Several copies of your resume
            \nYou most likely already submitted your resume when you applied for the job, but don\'t assume the interviewer will have a
            copy of it on hand. "Hiring managers get busy and sometimes forget to print out your resume," DeWall says.
            \nWhy bring multiple copies? "You never know how many employees you\'re going to be meeting with," says Rachel Loock,
            a career coach at the University of Maryland. "It’s rare you only meet with [the hiring manager]."

            \n\ - Business cards
            \nAlthough your resume should include your contact information, and business cards may seem old school, it can\'t
            hurt to bring them with you, says millennial career coach Anastasia Button. They\'re easy to carry, and
            "you never know if someone is going to ask for one," Button says. It’s always better to have a few handy, just in case.

            \n\n - Portfolio/work samples
            \nIf you\'re in a creative industry—like advertising, journalism, graphic design, architecture, or fashion—you should bring
            samples of your work that you can give to the interviewer. "Offer to send your full portfolio electronically later on," Button says.
            \nDepending on what you do, you may also want to have a sheet that showcases positive feedback you\'ve
            received from past clients on your work.

            \n\n - References
            If the interview goes well—better yet, when the interview goes well, the hiring manager might ask you for references on the
            spot, so you should have a list prepared with their contact information.
            \nTheoretically, you could just email the interviewer this information when you get home, but DeWall says that\'s a bad approach.
            "You want to make sure you give the company everything they need to move forward with the hiring process as quickly as possible,"
            she explains.

            \n\n - Pen and notepad
            Taking a few notes during your interview can be beneficial for a few reasons. For one, it shows you’re actively listening
            to the interviewer and engaged in the conversation, while also ensuring you won\'t forget important details about the job.
            Moreover, "you can refer to your notes, later on, to send the interviewer a personalized thank-you email," Loock says.
            \nJust make sure you ask the interviewer for permission before taking notes, and "don’t take so many notes that you’re not making
            eye contact," Loock says.
        </item>
        <!--What to wear to an interview?-->
        <item>
            The first impression you make on a potential employer is the most important one.
            The first judgment an interviewer makes is going to be based on how you look and what you are wearing.
            That\'s why it\'s always important to dress appropriately for a job interview.

            \n\nGenerally, you want to wear professional, or business, attire.
            For men, this might mean a suit jacket and slacks with a shirt and tie, or a sweater and button down.

            \nFor women, this might mean a blouse and dress pants or a statement dress. You can also incorporate some modern
            style trends into your outfit.

            \n\nWhether you are a man or woman, you also want to think about the colors you wear for an interview.
            Avoid anything too bright or flashy that will distract the hiring manager.

            \n\nNote: No matter how the dress code for the company is, always dress up "professionally", because you can never "over-dress".
            If you dress up the same as everyone else in the company and the other candidates, then you are not making any extra impression.
            Do not forget this.

            \n\nYou should also:

            \n\n&#8226; avoid wearing too much jewellery or make-up
            \n\n&#8226; cut and clean your fingernails
            \n\n&#8226; ensure that any briefcase or handbag you take is smart
            \n\n&#8226; polish your shoes
            \n\n&#8226; tidily arrange your hair
            \n\n&#8226; use aftershave or perfume sparingly
            \n\n&#8226; wash and iron your outfit.

        </item>
        <!--the general structure of the interview-->
        <item>
            Think about the basic structure of a good story. It always includes these elements:

            \n\n&#8226; A beginning – in the case of an interview, this can be small talk, setting the tone, establishing rapport,
            and providing a personal connection between you and the interviewer. The key here is to be your best self – don\'t force anything.

            \n\n&#8226; A body or middle – this is the substance of the one-on-one information exchange. All your preparation,
            accomplishment stories, personal strengths, abilities, and value statements can be used here to make a compelling case for yourself.

            \n\n&#8226; A strong ending or finish – the close makes sure the interviewer has a firm grasp on where you fit into the company\'s
            landscape, exactly how you can add value to the position in question, and how you’re superior to the other candidates.
            This part of the story ensures that the interviewer is left with a good impression of you, your track record, and
            your ability to help the company meet its objectives.
        </item>
        <!--During the interview-->
        <item>
            First and foremost be on time for the interview.
            \nOn time means five to ten minutes early. If need be, drive to the interview location ahead of time so you know exactly
            where you are going and how long it will take to get there. Take into account the time of your interview so you can adjust
            for local traffic patterns at that time. Give yourself a few extra minutes to visit the restroom, check your outfit, and
            calm your nerves.

            \n\nCalm the nerves -
            \nThe majority of candidates get pretty nervous prior to an interview, there\'s a lot riding on it after all. It\'s a good thing!
            It shows that something important is about to happen.

            \n\nTry and channel nervousness by remembering that your interviewer may be more nervous than you!
            This is especially true of a panel interview, where inexperienced staff may be pulled in and may be afraid of fluffing
            their lines or losing face in front of colleagues.

            \n\nNo one will mark you down for being nervous in an interview. It even shows a certain amount of respect.
            You\'re more likely to make a poor impression by appearing complacent or superior.

            \n\nTry to Avoid Negative Thinking -
            \nStress around interviews is often influenced by our assumptions or the statements we make to ourselves about the process.
            Identifying and countering anxiety-provoking thoughts can help to lower levels of anxiety. Some of the negative thoughts
            that can up your anxiety level include:

            \n\n"I have to land this job, or I will be hopelessly unemployed."
            Counter this thinking with statements emphasizing that no one interview will determine your work future.
            There will be other options and other chances to land a good job.
            \n"I just messed up that answer, I'm toast, and I'll never be hired here."
            One poor answer normally does not knock a candidate out of consideration.
            An interview is like a test, getting an 85 or 90 might be good enough to land the job.
            \n"I'm afraid that they will ask me a question which stumps me and I'll look foolish."
            If you are well prepared, you will normally be able to share some answer which reflects positively on your strengths.
            If you are truly stumped, then say something like "That's a great question, can I give that some additional consideration
            and get back to you?" You might even supply the answer in question as part of your follow up communication.
            \n"There's no way I'm qualified for this job."
            Mentally review your qualifications repeatedly prior to the interview to convince yourself that you have the right stuff.

            \n\nBody Language -
            \nWhile first impressions do count for a lot, it's during your conversation that interviewers will have an extended time
            to take you in. Your answers to questions are important, as is your stance while listening and responding.
            Keep these body language tips in mind:

            \n\n&#8226; Posture and Sitting Style
            First and foremost: No slumping! Keep your back straight. Lean forward slightly to indicate interest.
            Do not recline back into the chair fully; this can make you seem bored or disengaged.

            \n\nAvoid crossing your arms or placing items in your lap; these habits indicate defensiveness, nerves,
            and a need for self-protection when what you'd ideally convey during an interview is confidence.

            \n\nTip: If you're offered a choice of seating, opt for the straight-backed chair —plush, cushioned chairs and couches may be comfy,
            but it's hard to sit gracefully within them.

            \n\n&#8226; Avoid Crossing Your Legs
            \nMost experts recommend against crossed legs. With a long interview, you might need to re-cross them because your leg is falling
            asleep. This could come across as fidgeting.

            \n\n&#8226; Suppress Restless Habits
            \nSpeaking of fidgeting…if you're a nail-biter, knuckle cracker, hair twirler, or leg tapper,
            don't allow these habits to make an appearance during the interview. All will appear unprofessional and convey nerves.
            Plus: Most of these actions are generally considered impolite.

            \n\n&#8226; Use Your Hands
            \nDo you naturally talk with your hands? Go ahead and let them move during the interview.
            Stopping the natural gestures may lead to an awkward appearance.
            Just make sure your motions don't become so enthusiastic that they distract from your words.

            \n\n&#8226; Eye Contact
            \nIt's important to make eye contact during your interview,
            but don’t mistake that for a directive to make constant eye contact.
            That is disconcerting and aggressive. At the same time, avoiding eye contact entirely comes across as untrustworthy and distant
            — it could make it seem like your answers are dishonest. Balance it out: Aim to make eye contact as you listen and respond to
            questions, but allow it to break occasionally, and let your eyes wander.

            \nThink: How would I make eye contact if I were chatting with a friend?

            \n\nActive Listening -
            \nIt’s often easier to learn by reading examples. Here are some examples of statements and questions employed with active listening:

            \n&#8226; Building Trust and Establishing Rapport: "Tell me what I can do to help."
            "I was really impressed to read on your website how you donate 5 percent of each sale to charity."
            \n&#8226; Demonstrating Concern: "I am eager to help you; I know you are going through some tough challenges."
            "I know how hard a corporate restructuring can be – how is staff morale at this point?"
            \n&#8226; Paraphrasing: "So, you are saying that the uncertainty about who will be your new supervisor is creating stress for you."
            "So, you think that we need to build up our social media marketing efforts."
            \n&#8226; Brief Verbal Affirmation: "I understand that you would like more frequent feedback about your performance."
            "Thank you. I appreciate your time in speaking to me."
            \n&#8226; Asking Open-Ended Questions: "I can see that John's criticism was very upsetting to you.
            Which aspect of his critique was most disturbing?" "It’s clear that the current situation is intolerable for you.
            What changes would you like to see?"
            \n&#8226; Asking Specific Questions: "How long do you expect your hiring process to last?"
            "What is your average rate of staff turnover?"
            \n&#8226; Waiting to Disclose Your Opinion: "Tell me more about your proposal to reorganize the department."
            "Can you please provide some history for me regarding your relationship with your former business partner?"
            \n&#8226; Disclosing Similar Situations: "I was also very conflicted about returning to work after the birth of my son."
            "I had the responsibility of terminating four of my personnel, due to downsizing, over the last two years.
            Even if it’s necessary, it never gets easier."

            \n\nBy employing these active listening techniques, you will impress your interviewer as a thoughtful, analytical,
            highly desirable candidate for the position. Think about possible situations that may occur during an interview and
            come up with strategies to allow you to listen actively.

            \n\nUsing the STAR method to answer interview questions -
            Once you’ve got to know your CV and the role you’re interviewing for, you must prepare for common interview questions.

            \nIt’s all very well claiming that you\'re \'a good leader\' or \'a team player\', but that\'s not the right way to answer an
            interview question in 2018.

            \nEach time you reference one of your skills you should support it with an example to prove to the interviewer that your skills are genuine. A popular technique for illustrating your skills is the STAR method:

            \n\n&#8226; Situation: Give some context to the story you’re about to tell, outline where you were and why you were there.

            \n\n&#8226; Task: Describe what you were doing and if you faced any challenges whilst doing it.

            \n\n&#8226; Action: Then explain the actions you took to complete the task and how you tackled any challenges you faced.

            \n\n&#8226; Results: Finally, reveal the outcome, this should demonstrate your skills,
            what you achieved and also anything you learnt from the situation.

            \n\nKeep this method in mind and come up with a few go-to examples you can use in the interview.
            If you\'ve done your research, you should be able to tailor these examples more specifically to the role you\'re applying for.

            \n\nFocus on Success -
            Many athletic and job coaches believe that visualizing images of success can improve performance and alleviate anxiety.
            Try frequently imagining positive interactions with your interviewer, particularly in the hours immediately before your interview.

            \n\nCounselors recommend relaxation techniques, such as progressive muscle relaxation or breathing exercises as a way
            to manage anxiety. If your anxiety around interviewing is excessive, then you might consider engaging a psychologist in
            identifying the underlying issues and helping you to develop effective coping strategies.

            \n\nOne other point to remember is that if you don\'t get this job, there will be another one.
            It just wasn\'t meant to me. Consider it a learning experience and move forward to the next opportunity.

        </item>
        <!--What Interviewers Are Really Looking For?-->
        <item>
            &#8226; Brutal honesty

            \nSomehow, we have all been conditioned to approach an interview in a very formal and conceited manner.
            We are so fearful of saying something negative that we refuse to do so even when asked.
            To wit, if you\'ve ever been asked "what is your worst quality?" during an interview,
            I am sure you have managed to weave this into something overwhelmingly positive – and wildly fictitious.
            But why? Some of the strongest candidates I have interviewed are those who are unflinchingly honest during an interview.
            I once had a candidate tell me that one of my company\'s recent social media campaigns was, in his words, "a total disaster".
            When pushed for an answer, he was able to clearly explain why and what he would have done differently. Some people may consider
            it risky to brashly criticize the work of a potential employer; personally, I consider it common sense
            (if you are able to back it up, of course).

            \n\n&#8226; Get personal

            \nDuring a recent interview, I asked a fairly routine question about why the candidate had applied for the job.
            After a fairly uninspiring answer, she turned the question around and asked me why I had chosen to sell my business
            and accept my current job. Wait, what? It turns out that this candidate had done a great deal of research on my
            professional background to better understand my perspective and to find some common ground.
            She was also able to draw parallels between her career and my own professional path.
            It was clear to me that this candidate had gone beyond the simple corporate research and had chosen to make this interview
            much more personal. And, given how the great majority of interviews can be quite laborious, this was truly a breath of fresh air.

            \n\n&#8226; Get involved immediately

            \nSome of the most engaging interviews are those that function more like a brainstorming meeting than a Q&amp;A session.
            As a candidate, you are encouraged to ask appropriate questions about the position and company during the interview.
            However, don\'t limit your questions simply to procedural or functional elements. I’d suggest you get stuck in and make
            it seem like you are already a member of the team. Feel free to create a dialogue about how decisions are made or how projects
            are run. The hiring manager should be happy to discuss these real-life scenarios with you and should provide you an opportunity
            to offer your own insights. For example, my team had just concluded a long web development project and was interviewing a
            new web developer. Rather than ask questions about parking or lunch hours, he asked me questions about our chosen project
            management methodology and why we hadn\'t considered different approaches. We spent the next thirty minutes brainstorming
            ideas about how to manage the next big project. And, for these thirty minutes, the candidate felt more like a member of
            my team than a complete stranger interviewing for a job.

            \n\n&#8226; Initiative

            \nYou\'d be amazed how few candidates take the initiative to supply an interviewer with additional assets for consideration.
            For example, the great majority of writers show up to interviews without a portfolio or links to published articles.
            If I don\'t explicitly request writing samples, I don’t receive any. And this does not reflect well on the candidates.
            If you want to avoid being an afterthought, take some initiative. Some of the most impressive candidates I have interviewed
            are those who have come armed with portfolios, presentations or other documents to support their candidacy.
            One candidate went so far as to produce a high-level communications plan during an interview for a social media position.

            \n\nSo aside from the required eye-contact, body language, punctuality and company knowledge, these types of initiatives get you
            noticed and leave an interviewer feeling that the candidate had put their best foot forward.
        </item>
        <!--What questions to ask-->
        <item>
            Your opportunity to ask questions usually comes at the end of the interview.
            You must prepare at least two questions that demonstrate your interest in the position,
            your drive to excel in the role, and the fact that you’ve done some homework (researched company, industry, department).

            \n\nSo how do you come up with these smart questions that show you\'re the perfect hire? As you conduct your pre-interview
            research, make note of topics that you’d like to ask about.

            \n\nKeep in the mind that the best questions to ask are focused, open-ended question.

            \n\nAvoid yes or no questions and avoid questions that are so broad that they are difficult to answer.
            You don\'t want to stump the interviewer when you\'re trying to make a good impression and develop rapport.

            \n\nExamples:

            \n\n - Can you tell me more about the day-to-day responsibilities of this job?

            \n\n - What do you think are the most important qualities for someone to excel in this role?

            \n\n - Based on your top-performing employees, what are their common traits that they possess?

            \n\n - What are your expectations for this role during the first 30 days, 60 days, year?

            \n\n - Describe the culture of the company.

            \n\n - Where do you think the company is headed in the next 5 years?

            \n\n - Who do you consider your top competitor, and why?

            \n\n - What are the biggest opportunities facing the company/department right now?

            \n\n - What are the biggest challenges facing the company/department right now?

            \n\n - What do you like best about working for this company?

            \n\n - What is the typical career path for someone in this role?

            \n\n - What are the next steps in the interview process?
        </item>
        <!--After the interview-->
        <item>
            Find out what the next steps are and when you can expect to hear back on the outcome of the interview.
            Once everything has been wrapped up, be sure to thank them for taking the time to meet with you and
            tell them that you look forward to hearing from them soon. Exit on a handshake and follow the interview
            up with a phone call or an email and make sure you ask for feedback.

            \n\nUltimately, if you practise interview questions, do your research, deliver your answers concisely and get some
            interesting conversations going, there’s no reason why a job interview can\'t be a pleasant experience.

            \n\nYou can learn from every interview you go to – even the failed attempts. Keep practising these techniques, and you
            can become a master of the 2018 job interview.
        </item>
        <!--How to negotiate salary?-->
        <item>
            - Wait for the appropriate time. Once you know what you should be earning, how do you go about getting it? Start by being very patient. When interviewing for a new position, do your best not to bring up compensation until the employer makes you an offer.

            \n\n&#8226; - Resist throwing out the first number. If you\'re asked what your salary requirements are, say that they
            are open based upon the position and the overall compensation package. Or tell the employer you'd like to know more
            about the responsibilities and the challenges of the job prior to discussing salary.
            \n\n&#8226; - Base your salary request on data. If you\'re forced to give a number, provide a salary range based upon
            the research you've done up front. Use this research to inform your negotiating technique. Talk about what\'s appropriate
            for the role, based on your experience and what you have to offer. Resist the temptation to talk about your personal
            financial needs.
            \n\n&#8226; - Take your time. Once you've received the offer, you don't need to accept (or reject) it right away.
            A simple "I need to think it over" can get you an increase in the original offer.
            \n\n&#8226; - Consider saying no. If you're ambivalent about the position, a "no" can bring you a better offer too.
            I turned down a position I knew I didn't want, regardless of salary, and received three follow-up phone calls upping
            the compensation package.
            \n\n&#8226; - But don\'t decline a job that you want or need. Be careful though, if you do definitely need that new job
            there's a risk that the employer may accept your declining the position and move on to the next candidate.
            \n\n&#8226; - Negotiate benefits. Consider whether there are employee benefits and perks that might be negotiable,
            even if the salary isn\'t.


        </item>
        <!--the do's and don'ts-->
        <item>
            &#8226; Do come prepared.
            \n\n&#8226; Do arrive early.
            \n\n&#8226; Do quiz yourself in advance with practice questions.
            \n\n&#8226; Do dress stylishly and meticulously.
            \n\n&#8226; Do sit up straight and speak with confidence.
            \n\n&#8226; Do make eye contact. But don’t overdo it to the point where you make the interviewer uncomfortable.
            \n\n&#8226; Do take some time to consider your answers and respond thoughtfully. You shouldn’t feel pressured to answer each question in rapid fire.
            \n\n&#8226; Do take time for pleasantries and a bit of casual social banter.
            \n\n&#8226; Do your research about the company and the employer beforehand.
            \n\n&#8226; Do set up Google alerts to keep you abreast of the latest developments at the company.
            \n\n&#8226; Do spend time researching the market and the forces that are influencing the industry.
            \n\n&#8226; Do follow up with a thank-you email, letting the interviewer know it was nice to meet them and that you look forward to hearing back soon.
            \n\n&#8226; Do subtly put your name on their radar the day after the interview by liking a post on their social media account.
            \n\n&#8226; Do ensure that your most recent posts on your social media accounts show something positive and professional.
            \n\n&#8226; Do strike a power pose before you head to the interview. It will boost your endorphins and improve your confidence.
            \n\n&#8226; Do use language that is appropriate for the job environment and demonstrate your experience by using a bit of well-placed jargon.
            \n\n&#8226; Do be yourself. You want to project an authentic and genuine demeanour.
            \n\n&#8226; Do understand that interviews are as much an opportunity to show the employer that you would be a pleasant person to work with as they are to demonstrate skills and experience, this is a social opportunity.
            \n\n&#8226; Do consider your career goals and clearly define your reasons for wanting the job.
            \n\n&#8226; Do practice your interview skills with a friend or colleague.
            \n\n&#8226; Do prepare answers to common interview questions.
            \n\n&#8226; Do eat a healthy and energising breakfast before going in.
            \n\n&#8226; Do breath deeply, relax the muscles of your face, and take the time to pause before the interview.
            \n\n&#8226; Do exercise regularly in the week leading up to the interview.
            \n\n&#8226; Do your homework about the industry and the company.
            \n\n&#8226; Don’t fidget.
            \n\n&#8226; Don’t stress yourself out by dwelling on negative possibilities.
            \n\n&#8226; Don’t slip into the non-professional language.
            \n\n&#8226; Don’t simply recap your resume. An interview is a chance to demonstrate all the qualities your resume cannot.
            \n\n&#8226; Don’t be brusque with the administrative staff. You need to impress every person you encounter at the company.
            \n\n&#8226; Don’t forget to smile and introduce some appropriate levity into the interview.
            \n\n&#8226; Don’t fail to use the interview process as a networking opportunity.
            \n\n&#8226; Don’t get flustered if you slip up on a question.
            \n\n&#8226; Don’t be late because you get lost along the way or encounter some unexpected circumstance. Plan for delays.
            \n\n&#8226; Don’t forget that this is a fundamentally social situation. Be amiable.
            \n\n&#8226; Don’t allow your answers to go off on tangents. Keep the focus on your best qualities.
            \n\n&#8226; Don’t schedule for late in the week, if you can avoid it. The ideal time for an interview is 10:30 on a Tuesday when employers are most likely to remember you.
            \n\n&#8226; Don’t over-caffeinate.
            \n\n&#8226; Don’t be afraid to admit you don’t know the answer to a question. It’s better than faking it.
            \n\n&#8226; Don’t speak ill of former coworkers, employers or colleagues.
            \n\n&#8226; Don’t reveal unnecessary personal information or make unprofessional remarks.
            \n\n&#8226; Don’t forget to give a firm handshake.
            \n\n&#8226; Don’t let your tact lapse. You need to demonstrate the diplomatic behaviour.
            \n\n&#8226; Don’t apologise unnecessarily.
            \n\n&#8226; Don’t fail to follow up after the interview with all of your contacts at the company.
            \n\n&#8226; Don’t brag or oversell yourself. Humility is a powerful, persuasive tool.
            \n\n&#8226; Don’t mention your shortcomings or make excuses.
            \n\n&#8226; Don’t let nerves paralyse you. Relax and act naturally.
            \n\n&#8226; Don’t forget to highlight your biggest strengths.
            \n\n&#8226; Don’t panic! You’ll do great.
        </item>
    </string-array>

</resources>