<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Interview Revision</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="nav_header_title">by Ahmet Ince</string>
    <string name="nav_header_desc">Navigation header</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>

    <!--Interview Prep Grid Texts-->
    <string name="topText">Go through each of the projects or components of your resume and ensure that you can talk about them in
detail. Filling out a grid like this may help:</string>
    <string name="belowTable">Along the top, as columns, you should list all the major aspects of your resume, including each project, job,
or activity. Along the side, as rows, you should list the common behavioural questions.
Study this grid before your interview. Reducing each story to just a couple of keywords may make the grid
easier to study and recall. You can also more easily have this grid in front of you during an interview without
it being a distraction.
</string>

    <!--Behavioural Questions-->
    <string-array name="behaviouralQuestions">
        <item>So, tell me about yourself.</item>
        <item>How would a friend or colleague describe you?</item>
        <item>What are your strengths?</item>
        <item>What are your weaknesses?</item>
        <item>How do you handle a challenge?</item>
        <item>Tell me about a challenging client-facing situation and how you handled it.</item>
        <item>Describe a time when you anticipated a problem was coming and you came up with options to solve it.</item>
        <item>Tell me about a time when you had to manage multiple responsibilities. How did you handle that?</item>
        <item>Tell me about the toughest decision you have had to make in the past x months.</item>
        <item>Have you ever made a mistake? How did you handle it? </item>
        <item>Tell me about how you worked effectively under pressure.</item>
        <item>Describe a time when you led by example.</item>
        <item>Give an example of how you worked on a team.</item>
        <item>What do you do if you disagree with someone at work?</item>
        <item>Tell me about a time you had to work closely with someone whose personality or work style clashed with yours.</item>
        <item>Sometimes we have an all-hands-on-deck situation that may require everyone to work extra hours. How would you handle that?</item>
        <item>What is your biggest professional mistake? How did you handle it?</item>
        <item>Give me an example of a time when you failed to hit a deadline.</item>
        <item>Tell me about a time you learned a new skill. How did you approach it and how to did you apply your new learning?</item>
        <item>What are you most proud of? Why?</item>
        <item>Give an example of how you set goals.</item>
        <item>Give an example of a goal you reached and how you achieved it.</item>
        <item>Tell me about a goal you failed to achieve.</item>
    </string-array>

    <!--Behavioural Answers -->
    <string-array name="behaviouralAnswers">
        <item>1</item>
        <item>2</item>
        <item>3</item>
        <item>4</item>
        <item>5</item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>

    </string-array>
    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>


</resources>
