<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="group_discussion_topic">
        <item>
            What is a Group Discussion?
        </item>
        <item>
            Preparing
        </item>
        <item>
            During the Group Discussion
        </item>
        <item>
            The Do\'s and Don\'t\'s
        </item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="group_discussion_topic_tips">
        <!--what is a group discussion?-->
        <item>
            Normally group discussions are used in the selection process for management trainees and executive positions.
            The objective of a group discussion is to mainly check your team playing skills because as a manager,
            you will be working in organisations with people. Employers are looking for candidates who have potential
            to be executives and to lead teams of people.

            \n\nThe group discussion is a test of your interactive skills and how good you are at communicating with other people.
            You\'ll have to be able to understand the other person\'s point of view while making your point and ensure that your
            team as a whole reaches a win-win situation; in other words a solution/agreement which is both
            feasible and accepted by all members of the team. A group discussion, to that extent, is a simulated managerial setting.

            \n\n&#8226; Groups of 8-10 candidates are formed into a leaderless group, and are given a specific situation to analyse
            and discuss within a given time limit, which may vary between twenty minutes and forty-five minutes.
            \n\n&#8226; They may be given a case study and asked to come out with a solution for a problem.
            \n\n&#8226; They may be given a topic and are asked to discuss the same.

            \n\nSkills assessed during a Group Discussion:

            \n\n&#8226; Leadership Skills – Ability to take leadership roles and be able to lead, inspire and carry the team along to help them achieve
            the group\'s objectives.

            \n\n&#8226; Communication Skills – Candidates will be assessed in terms of clarity of thought, expression and aptness of language.
            One key aspect is listening. It indicates a willingness to accommodate others views.

            \n\n&#8226; Interpersonal Skills – People skills are an important aspect of any job. They are reflected in the ability to interact
            with other members of the group in a brief situation. Emotional maturity and balance promotes good interpersonal relationships.
            The person has to be more people centric and less self-centred.

            \n\n&#8226; Persuasive Skills – The ability to analyse and persuade others to see the problem from multiple perspectives.

            Essentially, the group discussion is a test of your ability to think on your feet, your analytical prowess and your
            ability to make your point in a team-based environment.

        </item>
        <!--Preparing-->
        <item>
            - Practice
            \nThere is a saying "Practice Makes a Man Perfect" and it is absolutely right. To get sixes in group discussion match you
            need practice and the best way is to practice it in front of the mirror. A mirror is your twin, it will reflect your gesture,
            posture, your way of speaking way and you can get an image of yours.

            \n\n - Research the Company, and Show What You Know
            \nDo your homework and research the employer, the interviewers and the industry, so you feel comfortable with your knowledge of the company.
            \nYou should be able to find out a lot of information about the company\'s history, mission and values, staff,
            culture, and recent successes on its website. If the company has a blog and a social media presence,
            they can be useful places to look, too.
            \nSo during the group discussion and for Q&amp;A, you are ready to take initiative and show that you know well about the company and willing to work here more than other candidates.

        </item>
        <!--During the Group discussion-->
        <item>
            - Ensure you contribute to the group

            \nEnsure you contribute to the conversation. Often candidates take up behaviours or actions that aren\'t actively
            contributing to the group\'s outcome. For example, taking lead of the group, standing up to make notes on a board.
            Be careful not to fall into the trap of regarding these behaviours as earning you some positive points.
            In some cases these behaviours can even lead to you being alienated by other group members.

            \n\n - Manage your body language

            \nEnsure good body language and maintain relaxed eye contact. Make sure when you are listening to others you
            are attentive and demonstrate this through nods and gestures of agreement. If you feel uncomfortable in
            terms of how you are sitting, simply \'mirroring\' other people will help. Smiling always helps too.

            \n\n - Manage conflicts effectively

            \nAvoid confrontation and ensure you allow everyone a chance to speak. If someone is consistently rude and aggressive,
            do not resort to this behaviour yourself. Assessors will pick this up. Avoid being forceful or speaking over anybody.

            \n\n - Manage your time

            \nKeeping a check on the time will earn you points. Suggesting that you will keep a check on the time and providing
            regular updates throughout the discussion will also work well. However,
            if you commit to this responsibility then make sure you maintain that check.
            There is nothing worse than the session running out of time when you have appointed yourself as time-keeper.

            \n\n - Include others

            \nKeep an eye out for those who do not say anything and take the opportunity to ask them for their opinions.
            This will gain you both assessors\' appreciation and other group member\'s gratitude.

            \n\n - Ensure you are a team player

            \nMore often than not, the group discussion exercises require coming to an agreement on a particular issue. For example,
            you may be given individual proposals and asked to agree on two of these as a group. In these situations,
            remember you do not always have to get your ideas accepted. Try to do what is better for the company or
            organisation as presented in the exercise, rather than what you think might benefit you.
        </item>
        <!--the dos and donts-->
        <item>
            Do\'s
            \n\n - Arrive early
            When you\'re competing against a number of other candidates, it\'s essential you make the most of every opportunity to
            stand out –and not be remembered for the wrong reasons.
            \nAside from being punctual and courteous, arriving ahead of schedule has another unique advantage in this situation.
            At a group interview, you can expect to be monitored from the moment you enter the building, so the earlier you arrive,
            the longer you have to impress. It also allows you to interact with other candidates in a less formal setting, showing
            off your social skills.

            \nHowever, always bear in mind that there is such a thing as arriving too early. Getting there before the security guard won\'t
            win you any bonus points.

            \n\n - Remember the icebreaker
            \nBefore any of the actual tasks begin, you\'ll almost always be asked to provide some sort of introduction for yourself
            (or worse, some sort of introduction for someone else in the group). To avoid embarrassing situations, always prepare your
            answer beforehand. Your intro needn\'t be long, provided it\'s pertinent and engaging.
            \nRemember: if you can\'t think of anything particularly exciting, embellishments are allowed.
            Although it may be true, \'um, I’m not sure, I’m not really that interesting…\' isn\'t going to give you the start you need.


            \n\n - Sit up straight
            \nBody language can make all the difference. Do it right, and you\'ll appear attentive and alert,
            showing your interviewers that you’re genuinely interested in what they have to say. Do it wrong, however,
            and you\'ll only look listless and lethargic (not the qualities of choice for many employers).
            \nThere\'s nothing wrong with relaxing as the interview progresses and showing that you\'re comfortable.
            But you needn\'t let your attitude compromise your posture.
            So try and sit up straight wherever possible. Just remember to breathe occasionally…

            \n\n - Prepare questions
            \nIf you\'ve prepared for your interview correctly, you should have carried out plenty of research about what the
            company does and their position within the market. Always use this to your advantage during the obligatory
            \'any other questions\' portion of the interview.
            \nHowever, if you genuinely can’t think of anything to bring up for discussion, don\'t force it.
            Asking an irrelevant question just for the sake of asking one is more transparent than you may think.

            \n\n - Include everyone/Be inclusive
            \nAlthough your leadership skills are being assessed, don\'t be tempted to go overboard.
            One of the most important facets of leadership is the ability to ensure everyone\'s opinions are heard, not just voicing your own.
            If there\'s an introvert in the group, getting them involved in the task and encouraging them to participate
            will win you major points, both with your fellow candidates and with your interviewers.

            \n\n Don\'t\'s

            \n\n - Be fake
            \nIt may be a cliché, but sometimes the best advice is just to be yourself. Chances are your interviewers
            will be experienced in group situations, and therefore adept in detecting when someone’s overdoing it.
            \nTrying too hard to stand out is not going to make you many friends, especially amongst your assessors,
            so always try to be as genuine as possible.
            \nAlso, laughter. Unless you’re going for a job as a pantomime villain, leave your over-exuberant
            chuckles and guffaws at the door.

            \n\n - Talk over people
            \nThis is one of the most common mistakes of the group interview try-hard.
            When the competitive nature of the interview kicks in, it can be tempting to increase the volume to get your point across.
            However, whatever role you\'re applying for, you should never underestimate the importance of teamwork.
            \nRemember: the wisest people don’t always speak the loudest, but they always make their voices heard.
            So always try to think before you speak…

            \n\n - Get lost in the group – There\'s a fine balance between this point and the last. It\'s highly likely that,
            whether genuine or not, one or two people in the group will try and take control.
            \nIf and when this happens, don\'t let yourself be intimidated or overwhelmed. Instead, use them to your advantage.
            \nIf you don\'t agree with their points, feel free to be controversial and offer your own opinion,
            then open up the discussion to the group. A wise man once said: the tallest tree catches the most wind. Think about it…

            \n\n - Become too informal
            \nAs in any other interview situation, there\'s a certain etiquette for group interviews which should always be adhered to.
            It\'s fine to appear comfortable and relaxed in some instances. For example, taking your coat/scarf/hand-knitted woolly
            mittens off is perfectly acceptable (and indeed can be a particular bugbear for some recruiters if left on).
            Do not, however, use this as an excuse to leave your manners at the door.

            \n\n&#8226; Number one: don\'t refer to your interviewers or co-interviewees as \'mate\'. Your interviewers are not your friends.

            \n\n&#8226; Number two: never swear. Being controversial is ok, as long as you have a well-articulated,
            polite and appropriate argument. Being rude, vulgar or offensive, however, is definitely not.

            \n\n&#8226; Number three: avoid discussing any excesses you might enjoy in your own time (obvious topics include gambling and
            drinking etc, but we’re sure you get the picture). Perhaps save that particular tale for another day/week/lifetime –
            it\'s unlikely to impress

            \n\n - Lose concentration
            \nFinally, it’s essential to maintain maximum concentration at all times. Take notes,
            keep eye contact at an acceptable (and socially acceptable) level, smile, nod,
            and generally try and look enthusiastic and engaged throughout.
            \nAvoid spending your time staring off into space, or worse, checking your phone during proceedings.
            The same also applies to doodling. If you can\'t listen to the introductory presentation without practicing your
            inner Picasso, you probably won\'t be invited back any time soon.
        </item>

    </string-array>
</resources>