<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="group_discussion_topic">
        <item>
            What is a Group Discussion?
        </item>
        <item>
            Preparing
        </item>
        <item>
            During the Group Discussion
        </item>
        <item>
            The Do\'s and Don\'t\'s
        </item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="group_discussion_topic_tips">
        <!--//what is a group discussion?-->
        <item>
            Normally group discussions are used in the selection process for management trainees and executive positions.
            The objective of a group discussion is to mainly check your team playing skills because as a manager,
            you will be working in organisations with people. Employers are looking for candidates who have potential
            to be executives and to lead teams of people.

            \n\nThe group discussion is a test of your interactive skills and how good you are at communicating with other people.
            You\'ll have to be able to understand the other person\'s point of view while making your point and ensure that your
            team as a whole reaches a win-win situation; in other words a solution/agreement which is both
            feasible and accepted by all members of the team. A group discussion, to that extent, is a simulated managerial setting.

            \n\n&#8226; Groups of 8-10 candidates are formed into a leaderless group, and are given a specific situation to analyse
            and discuss within a given time limit, which may vary between twenty minutes and forty-five minutes.
            \n\n&#8226; They may be given a case study and asked to come out with a solution for a problem.
            \n\n&#8226; They may be given a topic and are asked to discuss the same.

            \n\nSkills assessed during a Group Discussion:

            \n\n&#8226; Leadership Skills – Ability to take leadership roles and be able to lead, inspire and carry the team along to help them achieve
            the group\'s objectives.

            \n\n&#8226; Communication Skills – Candidates will be assessed in terms of clarity of thought, expression and aptness of language.
            One key aspect is listening. It indicates a willingness to accommodate others views.

            \n\n&#8226; Interpersonal Skills – People skills are an important aspect of any job. They are reflected in the ability to interact
            with other members of the group in a brief situation. Emotional maturity and balance promotes good interpersonal relationships.
            The person has to be more people centric and less self-centred.

            \n\n&#8226; Persuasive Skills – The ability to analyse and persuade others to see the problem from multiple perspectives.

            Essentially, the group discussion is a test of your ability to think on your feet, your analytical prowess and your
            ability to make your point in a team-based environment.

        </item>
        <!--Preparing-->
        <item>

        </item>
        <!--During the Group discussion-->
        <item>

        </item>
        <!--the dos and donts-->
        <item>

        </item>
        <item>

        </item>
        <item>

        </item>

    </string-array>
</resources>